<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Godboxv2 on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet </title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/godboxv2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Godboxv2 on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/godboxv2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Server 2012 R2 returning to The GodBoxV2</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/windwsserver2012r2-returing-to-the-godboxv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/windwsserver2012r2-returing-to-the-godboxv2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few months of running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sabayon.org&#34;&gt;Sabayon&lt;/a&gt; Linux on the GodboxV2, i am going back to Windows Server. Back around October of last year, i installed Windows 10 Preview on the GodBoxV2, and, well, there where issues with graphics drivers, etc. Then, some time after, i cant remember off hand when, i moved to Sabayon Linux. Its based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gentoo.org&#34;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt; but has a lot of the components pre-built. Gentoo is a &amp;ldquo;Build from scratch&amp;rdquo; sort of OS. You get a basic kernel and a basic set of components, but you build everything else from scratch&amp;hellip; including rebuilding the kernel if you want. Sabayon, on the other hand has all that mostly prebuilt, though you can still use Gentoo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/Portage&#34;&gt;Portage&lt;/a&gt; to build stuff yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for the last few months, all was going mostly well&amp;hellip; but I miss Windows. And, given i have pretty much always ran a server OS on my main workstations, I am heading back to Server 2012R2. I was tempted by 2016, but its still very early days&amp;hellip; Maybe i will run it as a VM for a while, but we will see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
