<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>S3 on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/s3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in S3 on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/s3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed S3 data storage using Minio (and Zerotier)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/distributed-s3-storage-minio-zerotier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/distributed-s3-storage-minio-zerotier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, something i have been looking into in recient times has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_data_store&#34;&gt;Distributed Storage&lt;/a&gt;, and, more specifically, how to use the storage in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/&#34;&gt;many, many machines&lt;/a&gt; to protect data, and also increese my usable space&amp;hellip; There are a few projects on the market that do this (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceph.com/&#34;&gt;Ceph&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noobaa.com/&#34;&gt;NooBaa&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gluster.org/&#34;&gt;Gluster&lt;/a&gt; all spring to mind) but some are more painful to setup than others&amp;hellip; which brings me nicely to &lt;a href=&#34;https://minio.io/&#34;&gt;Minio&lt;/a&gt;. Minio is a 20ish MB executable you download from their site, mark it as executable (on Linux or Mac Boxes) and run&amp;hellip; and you have yourself a S3 compatable storage server&amp;hellip; Simples!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Wait!&amp;rdquo; i here you screem! &amp;ldquo;thats not distributed!&amp;rdquo;. Well, yes&amp;hellip; but, it can be! Their &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.minio.io/docs/distributed-minio-quickstart-guide&#34;&gt;Distributed Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt;, which is where i started with this, allows you to run a distributed copy of your data. I will let their documentation explain more, but this is what i did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;download the minio server (single executable file) on a minimum of 4 machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on each machine, run a command like the following:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/a6617921976eef0c1c79b3175bd76bf7.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;replacing accesskey and secretkey with keys (check minio documentation to get these) and foldertoexport with, well, the folder you want to export!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, i have 4 servers currently clustered. 2 are in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.online.net&#34;&gt;online.net&lt;/a&gt; (one in Paris, one in Amsterdam), 1 in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.net&#34;&gt;OVH.NET&lt;/a&gt; (France, somewhere) and one in Dublin (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/GodBoxV2.html&#34;&gt;GodBoxV2&lt;/a&gt; currently). They are all interconnected using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zerotier.com/&#34;&gt;ZeroTier&lt;/a&gt; (I will explain that later) and so far, so good&amp;hellip; only ran some basic tests, but with it, i could loose 2 machines and still have data&amp;hellip; Not bad for free! I will run some speed tests soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
