<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 13:10:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Carry</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/daily-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 13:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/daily-carry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of years back, I did a post about my &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2013/01/27/college_bag_contents.html&#34;&gt;Daily Carry for college&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; Well, I have finished (ish) college, but i still cary a lot of weird and wonderful stuff&amp;hellip; So, this is the update&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the contents are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530624866/16317125424_a03f9ec346_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/surface/en-gb/devices/surface-book&#34;&gt;SurfaceBook&lt;/a&gt; with an i7 processor, 16GB RAM and 512GB Storage, along with the dGPU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.samsung.com/uk/discover/mobile/samsung-galaxy-note-3-and-galaxy-gear-the-perfect-match/&#34;&gt;Samsung Galaxy Note 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B008EQ1YWA/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B008EQ1YWA&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&amp;amp;linkId=7ZYQH6ZH25FE3CBQ&#34;&gt;Beats by Dr. Dre Wireless on ear headphones&lt;/a&gt;. Bluetooth and wired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00UMJ3HDQ/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00UMJ3HDQ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&amp;amp;linkId=7BMHED4CKFRG5MRB&#34;&gt;TP-Link TL-WR703N&lt;/a&gt; modified with extra RAM and ROM. I will explain this later&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B0088PPFP4/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0088PPFP4&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&amp;amp;linkId=GYC4WLBAWOUFXLDX&#34;&gt;TP-Link MR3040&lt;/a&gt; currently used with the modem (see below) but to be replaced with the WR703N eventually&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00HT2HP6E/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00HT2HP6E&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&amp;amp;linkId=KFGQNRYDGTIMJPHO&#34;&gt;Huawei E3272 LTE Modem&lt;/a&gt; for broadband. Connected into either of the routers (above) or directly to the laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00KGVP71U/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00KGVP71U&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&amp;amp;linkId=GD4EI7NYMYZA2ZBK&#34;&gt;Anker 3 Port USB 3.0 HUB with 10/100/1000mb Ethernet&lt;/a&gt; Probably the coolest thing i have ever found! a 3 port USB 3 hub with a Gigabit Ethernet port included! There is one that came with the M3800, but its USB2 only (so, not fully gigabit) and takes up a USB port and gives nothing back&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00BQ5KHJW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00BQ5KHJW&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&amp;amp;linkId=QR7UYYKG6SIQS6GC&#34;&gt;Anker 3nd Gen Astro E4 13000mAh 2 Port External Battery&lt;/a&gt;. Handy little charger, since most of my devices run off USB. And it gives out a fair whack of power too!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00O636WGI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00O636WGI&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&amp;amp;linkId=SFIGWBHIXISO6B53&#34;&gt;Linx 8 Inch Windows 8.1 Tablet&lt;/a&gt; with Intel Quad core Atom (Z3735G) 1Gb RAM, 32Gb storage, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth and a 32Gb MicroSD card. Great little device, and handy when the M3800 is too big to use&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B008TM581M/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B008TM581M&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&amp;amp;linkId=PGRKADHBDM62ADWR&#34;&gt;Microsoft Wedge Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B000TSIAQO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000TSIAQO&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&amp;amp;linkId=R22PEM7OOE5DY3XI&#34;&gt;Microsoft Bluetooth Notebook Mouse 5000&lt;/a&gt; both connected to the Linx Tablet to have a full setup when required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://store.apple.com/us/buy-iphone/iphone6&#34;&gt;Apple iPhone 6 Plus&lt;/a&gt; (Not pictured). This was used to take this photo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more photos below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530624919/16752079580_ddd568fd5e_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530624931/16938202692_3eeeab8e05_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>testing</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 11:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;blablablablabla&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with AMD&#39;s Epyc</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/playing-with-amd-epyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/playing-with-amd-epyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, a few days back I got an email from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packet.net&#34;&gt;Packet.net&lt;/a&gt; about a promotion they and AMD where running. Essentially, they gave me some credit for their service (i am an existing customer) to play with one of their c2.medium machines. A c2.medium comes with an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amd.com/en/products/cpu/amd-epyc-7401p&#34;&gt;AMD EPYC 7401P&lt;/a&gt; which consists of 24 physical cores clocked at 2Gz with an all core boost at 2.8Gb and a max clock of 3Gz, 48 threads, 64GB ECC Memory, 2x120GB SSDs for boot and 2x480GB SSDs for main stoage. It also has a 20Gb network link (2x10gb bonded) and can run pretty much any OS you can think of (Windows is not on the list officially, but you can boot off your own ISO, so you could probably get it on there&amp;hellip; might not be supported, but it might be possible). all this for $1 per hour! And did i mention they are bare metal machines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the perfect opertunity to play with the new AMD processors. My current and previoius generation workstations (GodBoxv1 and Godboxv2) are both running Intel Xeon processors. the machine previous to this, the mac pro, is also running a Xeon processor. But previous to both of them, my first 2 major workstations ran AMD&amp;hellip; the first ran 2 AMD Athlon MP processors. These were old school processors that were single core, and i cant even remember their speeds, but i do know there were 32bit only and the machine maxed out at about 1.25GB RAM (well, i had it maxed out at that). the second AMD workstation ran 2 AMD Opterons&amp;hellip; again, single core machines, but this time, they ran 64 bit and IIRC maxed out at 8GB ram. This was a limitation of the board, not the processor&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about GodboxV.next, and the AMD processors, specicially the &lt;a href=&#34;https://products.amd.com/en-us/search/cpu/amd-ryzen%E2%84%A2/amd-ryzen%E2%84%A2-threadripper&#34;&gt;Threadrippers&lt;/a&gt; and Epycs, are contenders for the next machine&amp;hellip; so, this test allows me to check them out before i buy!Why would i say no?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, i spun a box up in New Jersey running Ubuntu 17.10 to play with it, and here are my findings&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, i ran lscpu on the box to see what i was playing with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/4877abe19c89f1e45e617da1b4d46447.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then ran fdisk -l to see what disks i had to play with. on my machine sda and sdb where the 480gb SSDs, sdc was a 120gb that was empty and sdd was the boot drive&amp;hellip; i installed the btrfs-progs and then formatted sda and sdb as a RAID0 array, which i then mounted to /mnt. this gave me just under 900gb to play with&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my first test is the usual test: building the Linux Kernel. I know that this is something that the lads at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servethehome.com&#34;&gt;ServeTheHome&lt;/a&gt; do a lot but its something i wanted to try my self&amp;hellip; So, first i installed git and build essential, then bison, flex and ncurses-dev, then i cloned Linus&amp;rsquo; git repo at git://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git. First things first: this machine has a twin 10gb link, a shead load of cores and some very fast storage. How long did it take to clone? it download 1.02 GiB at 35.32MiB/s (about 30 seconds and aboiut 280Mbit/s) and all in, took 2 min 55 seconds to clone. I then ran &amp;lsquo;time make -j 49&amp;rsquo; to see how long it would take&amp;hellip; hmmm&amp;hellip; no config file&amp;hellip; make menuconfig and just hit save&amp;hellip; defaults are grand&amp;hellip; time make -j 49 again&amp;hellip; and more errors&amp;hellip; after a bit of googling, i find the page from Ubutnu &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/KernelTeam/GitKernelBuild&#34;&gt;showing what i need to do to build the kernel&lt;/a&gt;. i follow that&amp;hellip; download a LOT more stuff using their instrustions, and finally, we get to build&amp;hellip; Time: 6 min 12 seconds&amp;hellip; this is a FULL default build of the kernel&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530618253/top_kernel_build_epy_hdb0R.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same build on a VM on GodboxV2 (which was given 32GB RAM and 16 thread, so a full Xeon E5-4620) took 8min 27s to clone (8.18MiB/s. or about 64Mbit/s) and 36 min&amp;hellip; yea, that is 3x less cores, 2x less memory, slower storage (This is on Spinny Disk, not SSD), slower network and it is also a VM VS bare metal, still, to be essentially 6 times slower? interesting&amp;hellip; I might, at some stage, boot the machine off a live Linux USB and run some more tests, but not tonight&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530618253/top-kernel-build-godboxv2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, all this is becasue i was holding out for the main event&amp;hellip; Photo processing&amp;hellip; I wanted to do somethign &amp;ldquo;real life&amp;rdquo;, which for me would be development and photo processing&amp;hellip; the kernel build gives an idea of a large project build built, the image processsing gives an idea of multimedia work&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so, i devised a test: Export a bunch of photos (mix of photos taken on my 5Ds, 5D MKII, iPhone 6 Plus and iPhone 7Plus) that are stored in light room as full  and run them though a basic .NET Core app i wrote. the code for the app is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/imageresizer-testapp&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;. The app fully utilizes the machine by using multiple threads, and because its 64 bit, it will use as much memory as it can get its hands on. It just does some basic processing: open the file, resize to 1024X1024 and then save it&amp;hellip; the 1024X1024 part is just a test&amp;hellip; i was a bit under the gun on time, so couldnt spend as much time working on it as i wanted to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, there was 1546 photos exported, and the total file size was 15Gb. First obstical was to get them uploaded to the Packet machine, which took a while (my upload speed is currently 40Mbit/s)&amp;hellip; Once up, i downloaded a copy of dotnet core 2.0 SDK, cloned the repo with the project, built and ran&amp;hellip; and man, its fast! 4 min 43 seconds. And it used all the cores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530618252/image-resizer-epyc.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running the same code on GodBoxV2 on the bare metal (no VM this time), i got XX min of a run&amp;hellip; Now, GodBoxV2 has other things running in the back ground, but not that much&amp;hellip; I also noticed that, on average, photos were being processed in 3-5 seconds on Epyc, but nearly 13-15, and sometimes 20 and 25 seconds on GodBoxV2. I also noticed that on Epyc, the dotnet process took nearly 45GB of RAM&amp;hellip; to run&amp;hellip; On GodBoxV2, it took over 70!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530618252/image_resizer_godbox_f5de0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. Some starting tests with these processors. I am well impressed with these processors, and would have no issue getting one for the next GodBox&amp;hellip; And with names like Epyc and Threadripper, why not?!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AS204994, Own IP Space and Anycast</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/as204994-own-ip-space-and-anycast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 22:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/as204994-own-ip-space-and-anycast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, if you are reading this page, it is being delivered with the magic of Anycast&amp;hellip; Well, technically, it was before, since i used &lt;a href=&#34;http://cloudflare.com&#34;&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;, and it still is because of Cloudflare, but also because of my own ASN (&lt;a href=&#34;http://as204994.net&#34;&gt;As204994&lt;/a&gt;), some servers in different locations, and some magic, which i will explain a bit of in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all started late last year when i got my hands on an ASN and a /48 block of IPv6 addresses. I had been reading stuff about BGP, routing, etc, and decided to go all in. it was quite cheap with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.hostus.us/aff.php?aff=2152&#34;&gt;HostUS&lt;/a&gt;. All in, it was about $50 for the year. As part of the process, i needed 2 upstream providers to say they would accept my announcement. They were &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.he.net&#34;&gt;Hurricane Electric&lt;/a&gt; though their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tunnelbroker.com&#34;&gt;Tunnel Broker&lt;/a&gt; service, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vultr.com/?ref=6925432&#34;&gt;Vultr &lt;/a&gt;using a few of their VPSs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After i got my space and ASN, i started to announce the V6 addresses over Vultr and Hurricane Electric, and all was good. I had 2 Vultr servers: 1 in London, UK, and one in New Jersey, USA. I had my home machine announce to HE, and then also link to both Vultr servers using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zerotier.com&#34;&gt;Zerotier&lt;/a&gt;. All worked well, but due to some family issues, i never got around to putting it into production&amp;hellip; till now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those 3 servers now share an IPv6 address on the loopback port. When you (well, Cloudflare) asks for that IP, the closet (network) with that IP responds, and the NGinx server on that box sends back the contents of the site. This site is hosted on each box, since its fully static, but both &lt;a href=&#34;https://as204994.net&#34;&gt;AS204994 &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&#34;https://tiernanotoole.net&#34;&gt;TiernanOToole.net&lt;/a&gt; are hosted in Ghost, so Dublin (my machine in the house) serves them, and both Lon1 and Nyc1 do proxying. so, most requests from the US are hitting the box in NYC and the ones in Europe share either Dub1 or Lon1. I have some tweaks to do with which servers will be running where, and may add more, but currently its working well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you figure out what server responded? Simple. Open your Dev tools on your browser, go to network tab, refresh, and see the response headers for anything on this domain. You should see something like below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/uploads/2018/04/01/responding-server.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next while, i will be updating tiernanotoole.net with more details on how this works, and more stuff will end up on AS204994.net too. If anyone notices any weird and wonderful issues, shout. If you have more questions, shout.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging on an iPad Pro</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/blogging-on-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/blogging-on-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, a few months back I bought myself an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/ipad-pro&#34;&gt;iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. I got a 10.5&amp;rdquo; with 64GB Storage and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MPTL2LL/A/smart-keyboard-for-105‑inch-ipad-pro-us-english?fnode=37&#34;&gt;Smart Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, i have been mostly using it for playing around: watching YouTube, Netflix, surfing on the couch, etc. but i started to wonder how &amp;ldquo;Pro&amp;rdquo; this was&amp;hellip;so i went and did some testing, and in the end nearly all of this post is being written on it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;first, the good stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ai/app/microsoft-remote-desktop/id714464092?mt=8&#34;&gt;Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Remote Desktop Connection&lt;/a&gt; works perfect on the iPad Pro. I have RDPed into machines (with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zerotier.com&#34;&gt;ZeroTier&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/prompt-2/id917437289?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=11l4BV&#34;&gt;Panic&amp;rsquo;s Prompt&lt;/a&gt; works well too&amp;hellip; again, with ZeroTier, i can SSH into boxes and remote manage them. Handy for checking on docker instances&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panic also have &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/coda/id500906297?mt=8&amp;amp;at=11l4BV&#34;&gt;Coda for iOS&lt;/a&gt;. its a very nice (if somewhat expensive at $25) editor for the iPad. This post is being written on there now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for Git stuff, i am using an app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/working-copy/id896694807?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=6&amp;amp;at=1000lHq&amp;amp;ct=workingcopyapp&#34;&gt;Working Copy&lt;/a&gt;. Its free, to an extend, but if you need to do stuff like push changes, which is kind of important, then you need to pay a fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coda and Working Copy work together with some magic built into Working Copy. It can act as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://workingcopyapp.com/manual/webdav-server&#34;&gt;WebDav server&lt;/a&gt;, which Coda can the connect to. you open, edit, change and create docs, and Working Copy keeps note. then you swap to them and checkin. You need to have both apps on the screen at the same time (the docking feature works well for that) since iOS seems to kill some background tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unrelated to blogging, but i have also tried editing photos using &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ai/app/adobe-lightroom-cc-for-ipad/id804177739?mt=8&#34;&gt;Lightroom&lt;/a&gt;, and so far so good. I have used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/ie/shop/product/MJYT2ZM/A/lightning-to-sd-card-camera-reader&#34;&gt;Apple SD Card adapter&lt;/a&gt; to download 50MP photos (upwards of 60MB) from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usa.canon.com/internet/portal/us/home/products/details/cameras/dslr/eos-5ds&#34;&gt;Canon 5Ds&lt;/a&gt; quick enough, add them to Lightroom, make some changes and send them to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tiernano&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook (not Instagram just yet&amp;hellip;) and it works well. I have managed to hook it to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnarbox.com&#34;&gt;Gnarbox&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad Stuff?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keyboard takes a bit of getting used to. the Stupid &amp;ldquo;Global&amp;rdquo; button to swap keyboards (from
English to Emoji) is in the place you would expect to find CTRL. and CTRL, Option and Cmd (remember, this is a &amp;ldquo;Mac&amp;rdquo; style keyboard) and all shifted one place&amp;hellip; I would have preferred if they moved that somewhere else, or removed it altogether&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a mouse would be very handy! I have tried pairing a bluetooth mouse to it, and no luck&amp;hellip; it would be handy especially for editing documents and code, since touchscreen is &amp;ldquo;handy&amp;rdquo; some of the time, but not all the time&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. Blogging on an iPad. Would i give up my daily driver of my Surface Book and GodBoxV2 and just uses an iPad? Hell No&amp;hellip; for basic stuff, it works well. Basic photo editing, blogging, surfing, etc, yes. But there is a reason my workstation has 16 processor cores and 160GB RAM: I need it. I have multiple copies of Visual Studio running, SQL Server, multiple VMs running different tasks, multiple web browsers, multiple monitors, etc. the iPad can do a good chunk of stuff, but not the major stuff&amp;hellip; not yet. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook. all the major office tools work grand. But Visual Studio? SQL Management Studio? just not there yet&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what did i not do on the iPad, and ended up doing on the PC? Well, so far, nothing&amp;hellip; using Coda and Working Copy, i wrote the text, previewed it and checked it into GitHub. Then, Prompt is being used to build it on my docker box, check into the static site and push, which will then publish. unless you see an update below, all went as planned and all was done on an iPad&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Backup Plans</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/new-backup-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/new-backup-plans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, a few weeks back, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crashplan.com&#34;&gt;CrashPlan&lt;/a&gt;, one of my chosen backup services, decided to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crashplan.com/en-us/consumer/nextsteps/&#34;&gt;kill their consumer backup plans&lt;/a&gt;. Which made me have to rethink my backup plan for the house&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This is how I am backing up files, and may or may not work for you. Some of this is already in &amp;ldquo;production&amp;rdquo; as of today, but others are planned&amp;hellip; Any questions, comments, etc, leave them in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first, as mentioned above, CrashPlan&amp;rsquo;s consumer backup options are now dead. They are giving you the option of either upgrading to their Small Business Plan for free till the end of your current contract + 2 months, or moving to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.carbonite.com/&#34;&gt;Carbonite&lt;/a&gt;. For me, i just moved to their Small Business option, since its free, and meant that most of my backups just migrated over&amp;hellip; i did not, how ever, look too much into Carbonite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just checking their site now, i would have to go for a minimum of the Plus plan, and that only allows me to backup 1 machine&amp;hellip; I have 2 (currently) that get backed up&amp;hellip; and probably more at a later date&amp;hellip; and, given their yearly price for Plus is $75 per year, thats $150 for 2 current machines, and an extra $75 per machine after&amp;hellip; Granted, they are saying its unlimited storage. but the extra fee per machine puts it out of contention&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For CrashPlans Small Business Plan, their plan is $10 per machine per month&amp;hellip; So, my 2 machines would cost $240 per year to backup. They are giving me the next few months for free, and then for the first year, they are offering a discount of 75%, but we will see what happens when renewal comes along&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, where does that leave me? Well, its looking like i will be using a mix of &lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.backblaze.com/r/01px2w&#34;&gt;BackBlaze&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hubic.com&#34;&gt;Hubic&lt;/a&gt;. The current idea is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;GodBoxV2 and the Mac Mini both have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drobo.com&#34;&gt;Drobos&lt;/a&gt; plugged into them: the GodBoxV2 has a Drobo 5D, and the mini has a Drobo mini. There is also a Drobo FS on the network. I know they are not backup solutions, but its better than having stuff on single drives&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Windows boxes, I am backing up files to the cloud using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duplicati.com/&#34;&gt;Duplicati&lt;/a&gt;. These are backed up to both Hubic and BackBlaze B2. Photos and importing files are backed up to both, and stuff i want backed up, but not in 2 places, is just backed up on Hubic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my Mac mini, i use a a mix of Duplicati and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arqbackup.com/&#34;&gt;Arq Backup&lt;/a&gt;. Arq got B2 support recently, so its very handy for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For some of my Linux Boxes, i use &lt;a href=&#34;http://duplicity.nongnu.org/&#34;&gt;Duplicity&lt;/a&gt;. You may need to walk though the steps i have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2015/04/01/Duplicity_Hubic.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to get it working with Hubic, and it also works with B2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some further notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hubic are charging about EUR5 a month for 10Tb of storage. If you refer people, that can go up. I have maxed mine out at 12.5Tb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hubic is limited to 10mb/s for uploads and downloads. I never got anywhere close to that speed with CrashPlan (I&amp;rsquo;m based in Europe, they are in the US, so speed of light and what have you&amp;hellip; maxed most of the time at 4ish). That being said, even those its &amp;ldquo;limited&amp;rdquo; to 10mb/s, i have seen higher.,.. might be 10 per thread&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did, for a while, use the BackBlaze app and service. I just didn&amp;rsquo;t renew because of the move to B2. If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to mess with stuff, their App works great.And if you use &lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.backblaze.com/r/01px2w&#34;&gt;this referal link&lt;/a&gt; you get a free month&amp;hellip; Also, its FAST AF! it actually manged to max out my upload connection to their server! wont complain about that!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;B2 is cheap. 0.5c per gig stored&amp;hellip; So, it works out at about $5 per TB per month, minus your usual bandwidth fees&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Duplicati and Duplicity both have options to send emails on success or failure, or the like. I recommend having the emails on failure turned on at a minimum&amp;hellip; also, on headless boxes, like my Linux box, i recommend checking the backup every week&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there we have it. Any questions?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Forestry</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/testing-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/testing-forestry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, as you probably know, this site is built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll is a Static Site Generator, basically taking an input of a load of text files (see the source repo for this site on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie/&#34;&gt;Github here&lt;/a&gt;) and generating a load more HTML (the static HTML is hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie-static&#34;&gt;Github here&lt;/a&gt;, which auto publishes to &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/app-service/web/&#34;&gt;Azure App Service&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous posts, i have talked about using the likes of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2017/05/06/vscode-with-powershell.html&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code and Mark Down Monster&lt;/a&gt; to build the site. Well, a few days back, i found &lt;a href=&#34;https://forestry.io&#34;&gt;Forestry.io&lt;/a&gt;. Its a web application which, in my case, is linked with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; repo (the Jekyll source one) and allows me to make changes to the code easily. Because the way i build my site is a little different, i manually build the site and push to the destination GitHub project, but they have features allowing you to push directly to SFTP or FTP servers, GitHub, or some other options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interface is nice and easy to use, and you can use drafts, etc. Mind you, even with drafts, because files are written into a public repo, they are not fully private&amp;hellip; I suppose I could just make the source repo private&amp;hellip; Anyway, they are free for single user sites (like this) or they have paid plans for teams (say, your business blog with more than 1 user updating it, for example).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSCode and Markdown Monster with Powershell</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/vscode-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/vscode-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back, i created a post showing you how to add an Alias to PowerShell &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/30/SublimeText-With-Powershell.html&#34;&gt;to easily start Sublime Text from a PowerShell command line&lt;/a&gt; . This worked well, but this is 2017 (that post is from 2012!) and my daily text editor has changed. I have moved to &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; for most of my daily work. It works well 95% of the time. I still use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Pro&lt;/a&gt; for C# Development, but for quick fixes and work on, say &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; or smaller edits, Code is great. For blogging, on the other hand, I am trying out &lt;a href=&#34;https://markdownmonster.west-wind.com/&#34;&gt;MarkDown Monster&lt;/a&gt; but code still has some nice features. We will see how tests go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to upgrade the post, and to be able to use VS Code and MarkDown Monster from your PowerShell command line, I added the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-Alias code &amp;quot;C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft VS Code\Code.exe&amp;quot;
Set-Alias mm &amp;quot;C:\Program Files (x86)\Markdown Monster\MarkdownMonster.exe&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can either run this each time you open PowerShell (a bit of pain) or you can add it to your &lt;code&gt;Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1&lt;/code&gt; which lives in your &lt;code&gt;Document\WindowsPowerShell&lt;/code&gt; folder. If you dont have one, just create the file, add that piece of text, and next time you open PowerShell, you are good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, i am actually in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/insiders&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code Insiders&lt;/a&gt; group, so my alias is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-Alias code &amp;quot;C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft VS Code Insiders\Code - Insiders.exe&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When these are set (and you have restarted your PowerShell windows), you can now run the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;code filename.txt
code folder
mm filename.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VSCode will open either files or folders, but it seems Markdown Monster only opens files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zerotier and Minio Followup</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zerotier-minio-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zerotier-minio-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2017/01/19/distributed-s3-storage-minio-zerotier.html&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about setting up a distributed S3 like data storage system using &lt;a href=&#34;https://minio.io/&#34;&gt;Minio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zerotier.com/&#34;&gt;ZeroTier&lt;/a&gt;. Well, this week, the ZeroTier guys tweeted about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Distributed S3 data storage using &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Minio&#34;&gt;@minio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ZeroTier?src=hash&#34;&gt;#ZeroTier&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MAXTjo3muh&#34;&gt;https://t.co/MAXTjo3muh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; ZeroTier, Inc. (@ZeroTier) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ZeroTier/status/859557214997970944&#34;&gt;May 2, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few people then started asking questions, and looking for a follow up, so here it is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, a quick recap. I had 4 machines, all running Linux. Three of them were in 1 time zone (GMT+1) and one was in another (GMT). Looking at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.minio.io/docs/distributed-minio-quickstart-guide&#34;&gt;Distributed Minio Quickstart Guide&lt;/a&gt; again, there is a mention of times being in sync&amp;hellip; which is probably why this did not work as planned&amp;hellip; and by &amp;ldquo;not work as planed&amp;rdquo;, I mean that Minio would crash, or not be responsive, or not write data in the place it should have&amp;hellip; which was a pain. But looking at the documentation again, they do mention that Windows support is &amp;ldquo;experimental&amp;rdquo; which means, hopefully, some day it will be not so experimental, and might work&amp;hellip; Given that most of my machines in house are Windows boxes, this would be a nice feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what about ZeroTier? Given they posted it to their twitter? Well, it worked. it did the inter connect stuff well, and, given bandwidth limitations on a home broadband connection, it was still quite fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the question is, how fast? Well, on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/surfacebook.html&#34;&gt;Surface Book&lt;/a&gt; on a WiFi connection in the house, behind a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meraki.com&#34;&gt;Meraki&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;MX64&lt;/a&gt; firewall, connecting to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/GodBoxV2.html&#34;&gt;the GodBoxV2&lt;/a&gt; over FTP though ZeroTier, i get the following result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/ftpdownload-zerotier.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/ftpdownload-zerotier-rs.png&#34; alt=&#34;FTP over ZeroTier&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the same download over FTP direct (no ZeroTier) does the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/ftpdownload-direct.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/ftpdownload-direct-rs.png&#34; alt=&#34;FTP direct&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, direct over FTP is faster&amp;hellip; in this instance by about 70%, but, over the download, it did get slower (seen it hit 12 at one stage) and because its over WiFi, those are a bit wonky&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did get one last screen shot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/networkspeed.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/networkseed-rs.png&#34; alt=&#34;network speed&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as you can see, the Zerotier network adapter is showing 77.3Mbps, but the main network adapter is showing 80.8Mbps. There would be other traffic there, but if we assume there is nothing but ZeroTier traffic being sent, there is about 5% of an overhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to wrap up: Minio and its distributed storage system over ZeroTier needs more testing. Ideally, all hosts need to be in the same time zone, or at least have the same time&amp;hellip; Will try work on that soon. As for ZeroTier? I am extremely happy with them. Its fast, easy to setup, and easy to configure. What more could you ask for? Oh, and free, unless you need a pro account!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Class Broadband... finally here....</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/business-class-broadband/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/business-class-broadband/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, after many (MANY) years messing with dual cable modems, struggling to get them working together, to get websites to even allow me in, having to use hacks and kluges to get it to work at all&amp;hellip; I have given up. It has been a struggle getting two modems working properly. Load blanching &lt;em&gt;kind&lt;/em&gt; of works&amp;hellip; but it&amp;rsquo;s messy at best. Some sites kick you out every now and again because your IP changes. Some sites wont let you login at all&amp;hellip; Mind you, some sites work grand and don&amp;rsquo;t ask questions&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the whole idea of multiple modems, to allow you to download things faster, doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for everything&amp;hellip; Anything you download in the browser is single threaded, so its limited to one modem&amp;hellip; you can use use download accelerators, and they do work, but its an extra step, and some sites don&amp;rsquo;t work for that either (MSDN for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, i have given up, bit the bullet, and moved to business class broadband from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virginmedia.ie/business/&#34;&gt;Virgin Media&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s actually cheaper than the two residential lines i had, but it is also slower than the two combined: previously, it was two x 360/36mb/s. Now i am am on a single 400/40mb/s modem. That being said, there are definite advantages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static IPs pretty much as standard, and option of either one or five (no unbeaten!) Guess which one i went with? Its &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; a /29 range, but the first usable IP is given to the modem, which acts as a gateway, so i end up with five usable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proper business class SLA. Any issues, someone who knows what they are talking about can help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone lines on a separate modem. So, i got phone lines with them, and they give a separate modem for those lines, so as not to interfere with the internet. that modem has no internet connection and is just for calls. They are also working on a VoIP/SIP offering, which is something i am interested in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guaranteed speed! They guarantee a minimum speed to the modem at all time. Business customers have a priority on the network, which is nice. And, during testing, so far, i am getting the advertised speed most of the time. I needed to download a Windows 10 ISO yesterday from the MSDN, and it came in at between 45 and 48MBytes/s!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, only had it installed a week, and so far, so good. I have one IP given to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSesne&lt;/a&gt; box, and the rest given to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vyos.io&#34;&gt;VyOS&lt;/a&gt; VM. The plan is to use the VyOS box for all network traffic, but first i need to do some testing and learning&amp;hellip; Expect some posts on this soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed S3 data storage using Minio (and Zerotier)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/distributed-s3-storage-minio-zerotier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/distributed-s3-storage-minio-zerotier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, something i have been looking into in recient times has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_data_store&#34;&gt;Distributed Storage&lt;/a&gt;, and, more specifically, how to use the storage in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/&#34;&gt;many, many machines&lt;/a&gt; to protect data, and also increese my usable space&amp;hellip; There are a few projects on the market that do this (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceph.com/&#34;&gt;Ceph&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noobaa.com/&#34;&gt;NooBaa&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gluster.org/&#34;&gt;Gluster&lt;/a&gt; all spring to mind) but some are more painful to setup than others&amp;hellip; which brings me nicely to &lt;a href=&#34;https://minio.io/&#34;&gt;Minio&lt;/a&gt;. Minio is a 20ish MB executable you download from their site, mark it as executable (on Linux or Mac Boxes) and run&amp;hellip; and you have yourself a S3 compatable storage server&amp;hellip; Simples!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Wait!&amp;rdquo; i here you screem! &amp;ldquo;thats not distributed!&amp;rdquo;. Well, yes&amp;hellip; but, it can be! Their &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.minio.io/docs/distributed-minio-quickstart-guide&#34;&gt;Distributed Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt;, which is where i started with this, allows you to run a distributed copy of your data. I will let their documentation explain more, but this is what i did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;download the minio server (single executable file) on a minimum of 4 machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on each machine, run a command like the following:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/a6617921976eef0c1c79b3175bd76bf7.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;replacing accesskey and secretkey with keys (check minio documentation to get these) and foldertoexport with, well, the folder you want to export!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, i have 4 servers currently clustered. 2 are in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.online.net&#34;&gt;online.net&lt;/a&gt; (one in Paris, one in Amsterdam), 1 in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.net&#34;&gt;OVH.NET&lt;/a&gt; (France, somewhere) and one in Dublin (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/GodBoxV2.html&#34;&gt;GodBoxV2&lt;/a&gt; currently). They are all interconnected using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zerotier.com/&#34;&gt;ZeroTier&lt;/a&gt; (I will explain that later) and so far, so good&amp;hellip; only ran some basic tests, but with it, i could loose 2 machines and still have data&amp;hellip; Not bad for free! I will run some speed tests soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Jekyll and Mr ngrok</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/docker-jekyll-and-mr-ngrock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/docker-jekyll-and-mr-ngrock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See what i did with the title?! Anyway, in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/11/02/building-jekyll-sites-with-docker-on-windows.html&#34;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt;, i explained how i was building this site with Docker running on Windows 10 with the Anniversary update. Today, i am going to show you how to host it using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nginx.com/&#34;&gt;Nginx&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ngrok.com/&#34;&gt;ngrok&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first, you should know what Nginx is at this stage&amp;hellip; If not, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nginx.com/&#34;&gt;their site&lt;/a&gt;. Next &lt;a href=&#34;https://ngrok.com/&#34;&gt;ngrok&lt;/a&gt; is basically a way of tunneling your localhost to the web. So, how do we build the whole lot together and serve your site to the internet? Well, this is what i have so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, build your site in jekyll. for me, the command is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run --rm -v &amp;quot;$(pwd):/src&amp;quot; -w /src ruby sh -c &#39;bundle install --path vendor/bundle &amp;amp;&amp;amp; exec jekyll build -s www.tiernanotoole.ie/ -d www.tiernanotoole.ie/_site/&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next, run an nginx server with that output folder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run --name tiernanotoolenginx -v &amp;quot;$(pwd)/www.tiernanotoole.ie/_site/:/usr/share/nginx/html:ro&amp;quot; -d -p 8881:80 nginx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the docker container is called tiernanotoolenginx, since i could have multiple ones, and port 8881 is being redirected to port 80 on that container, but technically, it might not be needed due to the next command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run --rm -it --link tiernanotoolenginx wernight/ngrok ngrok http tiernanotoolenginx:80
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;essentially, what we are doing here is running ngrok and pointing it at post 80 on the nginx container&amp;hellip; you see i did not point at 8881, since we are using the continer directly&amp;hellip; it might be different if you were not&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when that command runs, you get a screen telling you the URL of your site with some basic stats. your site is now hosted publically, via an ngrok tunnel! you could run that container as a daemon, and leave it running, but for me, i wanted to do some minor testing, so i can kill it when i want&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, all is good with the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Jekyll sites with Docker on Windows</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/building-jekyll-sites-with-docker-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/building-jekyll-sites-with-docker-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some of you probably know (or based on the footer of the site) this site is built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll is a static web site builder, written in Ruby, and is a bit of a pain to build on Windows. Earlier on this year, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/04/11/installing-jekyll-on-bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows.html&#34;&gt;wrote up a post&lt;/a&gt; explaining how to use Jekyll on Windows using Bash on Ubuntu on Windows&amp;hellip; It was a bit complicated, and, well, worked a few times, but was not too successfull&amp;hellip; So, were do we go next? Well, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.docker.io&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am running the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2016/08/02/how-to-get-the-windows-10-anniversary-update/&#34;&gt;Windows 10 Anniversary edtion&lt;/a&gt; witch has &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualization/windowscontainers/quick_start/quick_start_windows_10&#34;&gt;container&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine/getstarted/step_one/&#34;&gt;docker support&lt;/a&gt;.  using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie-docker&#34;&gt;repo for this site&lt;/a&gt; and the scripts (specifically &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie-docker/blob/master/build-tiernanotooleie&#34;&gt;build-tiernanotooleie&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie-docker/blob/master/geekphotographer.com&#34;&gt;geekphotographer.com&lt;/a&gt;) i can build the docker site on my local Windows machine and upload the sites as required (I host on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nearlyfreespeech.net&#34;&gt;NFSN&lt;/a&gt; and upload via &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rsync&#34;&gt;RSync&lt;/a&gt;). The docker image i build from is a Linux docker image, do i need a Linux container running (and the docker tooling). I also use Bash on Ubuntu on Windows to upload using RSync. All is going well so far&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Desktop becoming a reality</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/cloud-desktop-becoming-reality./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/cloud-desktop-becoming-reality./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have talked about the theory of the &amp;ldquo;Cloud desktop&amp;rdquo; twice on my older blog (&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.lotas-smartman.net/rackspaces-hosted-virtual-desktop/&#34;&gt;Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s Hosted Virtual Desktop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.lotas-smartman.net/more-on-desktop-in-the-cloud/&#34;&gt;More on the desktop in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;) way back since 2011. Since then, a few things have changed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon have released &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/workspaces/&#34;&gt;AWS Workspaces&lt;/a&gt;, which is a cloud based desktop using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teradici.com/pcoip-technology&#34;&gt;Teradici&amp;rsquo;s PCoIP technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/&#34;&gt;EC2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/services/virtual-machines/&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; now have GPU enabled VMs to spin up and use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NVidia have released &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nvidia.co.uk/grid/&#34;&gt;NVidia Grid cards&lt;/a&gt;, specifically for the &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;remote&amp;rdquo; desktop services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-ie/windows/continuum&#34;&gt;Windows Continuum&lt;/a&gt; now allows you to use your Windows Phone with a keyboard, monitor and mouse, allowing you to replace your desktop. basically, plug your continuum enabled phone into a docking station, and use it as a Windows Desktop. Email, Browsing, Office Apps, etc. anything that supports UWP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and now &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neowin.net/news/vmware-releases-horizon-beta-client-for-windows-10-mobile-continuum-compatible&#34;&gt;VMWare has just released a Windows UWP app that works with Continuum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the increased bandwidth for mobile devices (4 and 5G, expanding wifi, etc) the idea of having your desktop live in the cloud is getting nearer&amp;hellip;  interesting times, my friend&amp;hellip; interesting times&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Update] Thinking a bit more about this, and if this was to work correctly, your phone could be everything required. Get up in the morning, check your emails on your phone, calander items, and news. head off, head to the coffee shop and plug your phone into a &amp;ldquo;laptop&amp;rdquo; style device like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://nexdock.com/&#34;&gt;NexDock&lt;/a&gt; and catch up on some emails, checking more news sites, etc. When you get into the office, plug your phone into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-ie/mobile/accessory/hd-500/&#34;&gt;docking station&lt;/a&gt; and Remote Desktop in to your cloud desktop to do your development work, or whatever needs to be done. basic Office apps and Email can be run direct from the phone. When you get home, you can use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/accessories/en-us/products/adapters/wireless-display-adapter-2/p3q-00001&#34;&gt;Microsoft Wireless Display adapter&lt;/a&gt; to watch videos on the big TV, or show web pages. And if your cloud desktop is available outside of your work network, you could work anywhere also&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 9 - Going Back</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-9-going-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-9-going-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 9 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the double internet experiment is about ready to be finished&amp;hellip; After 9 posts, 4 months, lots of sweating, many painful nights trying to figure out why something stopped using, shouting when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netflix.com&#34;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; did not work, wondering why my internet connection was so slow, and many, many other problems, i have decided to wind down the project. in the last 9 posts, i have learned a lot, and i hope i have helped someone figure out some stuff on their end. Even though this is a wind up of the project, there are still new things i have to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found another project that has potential for speeding up the internet: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vrayo.com/how-to-set-up-a-bonding-vpn-connection-in-linux/&#34;&gt;VTrunkd&lt;/a&gt;. after some testing, i does seem to manage to speed up the connection, but either limits on hardware i have in house, or limits of hardware in the cloud, or even the software, stopped me in my tracks&amp;hellip; i did see 400mb/s out of it at one stage, using 200mb/s from each modem&amp;hellip; its close, but its not the full 720&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;messing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga/Zebra&lt;/a&gt; as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/06/08/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around.html&#34;&gt;the previous post&lt;/a&gt; has been, well, interesting&amp;hellip; I did manage to get all &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.ie&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt; traffic sent though their server, &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; traffic sent over that box, and everything else over &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;. I added an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azure.com&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; box to the mix for a while, aswell as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vultr.com/?ref=6925433&#34;&gt;Vultr&lt;/a&gt; box, but it got very messey, very quickly. if i had something automated, it would be better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the idea of having a /29 IP range in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; and forwarding it though the tunnels back to the house did work. My &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;Meraki MX64&lt;/a&gt; had one IP address, i had a mail server on a second, everything else on a third, and was planning on using more&amp;hellip; but its just, well, again, messy. So, i will be going back to the idea of 2 IP addresses, and hoping whatever i put infront of the network can figure stuff out&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what am i moving to? well, thats a question&amp;hellip; Currently, i have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;Meraki MX64&lt;/a&gt; plugged directly into the modems, and protecting my LAN. So far, so good, but due to hardware limits, it maxes out at around 260mb/s. So, thats out of the question for the main network! I did at one stage have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en/products/free-tools/sophos-utm-home-edition.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM Home edition&lt;/a&gt; running. Sophos also have their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/free-tools/sophos-xg-firewall-home-edition.aspx&#34;&gt;XG firewall&lt;/a&gt; available for home use, so i might try that&amp;hellip; There is also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pfsense.org/&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; which i used before also&amp;hellip; And there may be more&amp;hellip; Maybe there will be a new series reviewing these home firewalls? we will see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meraki and Ubiquiti networks gear Update</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/meraki-gear-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/meraki-gear-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/05/17/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition.html&#34;&gt;part 6&lt;/a&gt; of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;Double Internet Series&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned i was running a &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/&#34;&gt;Meraki&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;MX64&lt;/a&gt; in the network, and said i would write up about it. I am taking this oppertunity to also write up about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubnt.com&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti networks&lt;/a&gt; gear in the house also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First on the list is my older &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti Edgerouter POE&lt;/a&gt;. It currently in the process of being decommissioned, or used for something else. It was the main edge router for the network: it had both internet connections connected, and did routing, firewalls, etc, but with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/proliantml110.html&#34;&gt;Proliant&lt;/a&gt; taking over as a router, it is not requried as much any more&amp;hellip; Its still on, mainly because its still a DHCP server, but not much else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/switches/ms220-8&#34;&gt;Meraki MS220-8&lt;/a&gt; switches next. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/godbox.html&#34;&gt;GodBox1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/GodBoxV2.html&#34;&gt;Godbox2&lt;/a&gt; both connect in here, and are bonded, as is everything else on the network. The MS220-8 has 8 GigE ports, but also has 2 SFP ports. I bought 4 SFP Ethernet adapters and have a short calbe running between the switches. That uplink is also bonded. All going well so far!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All meraki hardware can be managed though the meraki dashboard. check out their site for more details and examples of how to use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bought one of the MS220&amp;rsquo;s from ebay a few months back, and loved it. Then i realized that you can get your hands on free gear, the MX64, an MS220 and a Wifi Access point if you attend their &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/webinars&#34;&gt;webinars&lt;/a&gt;. Terms and conditions apply, but check them out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/unifi/unifi-ap/&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti UniFi APs&lt;/a&gt;, one in the front of the house, one in the back. They are connected to one of the MS220&amp;rsquo;s, but dont work with its POE (maybe the EdgeRouter could do that, since its POE&amp;hellip;) so there are injectors for them. Anyway, the network ports on there are VLANed to the MX64 (more on that later) and the detault traffic is going to a management VLAN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;MX64&lt;/a&gt; has a static internal IP on my DMZ network, and uses the Proliant as an upstream connection. Upstream on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; server, all traffic coming from the MX64 ip uses one of my /29 ip block. all traffic to that ip is also forwarded directly to the MX64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I has 2 small, unmanaged switches (a cheap 8 port Linksys and a 8 port TP Link) which are used for seperate things: the Linksys has 4 Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s, which run a [GlusterFS] cluster, plugged into it and the TP Link connects to my printers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/CRS226-24G-2SplusIN&#34;&gt;Mikrotik CRS226-24G-2S+IN&lt;/a&gt; which has 2 10Gbit SFP+ Ports, and plan on using this for higher speed networking soon, aswell as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/switches/catalyst-3560-series-switches/index.html&#34;&gt;Cisco 48 port 3560&lt;/a&gt; which also has 4 SFP ports (GigE) and may come in handy for something soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thats the network currently. any questions, please leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 8 - Routing Around</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 8 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/05/31/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of.html&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I asked the question about routing traffic to different servers based on thier distances, etc&amp;hellip; Well, after a bit of messing, i can say it kind of works! here is a quick over view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;server in the house has now got multiple OpenVPN connections (2 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;, 1 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.ie&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt; (with a plan to double), 1 to &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; (again, to be doubled) and i am planning 2 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azure.com&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; as well).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga/Zebra&lt;/a&gt; has static routes (currently static, planing on dynamic soon&amp;hellip; more eventually) to different servers depending on where they are. for example, all traffic to the hetzner network (including their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hetzner.de/en/hosting/produktmatrix/storagebox-produktmatrix&#34;&gt;Storage Boxes&lt;/a&gt;) go though the hetzner link. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hubic.com&#34;&gt;Hubic&lt;/a&gt; traffic goes though OVH, Azure (currently) and AWS traffic, aswell as some CDNs go direct over either WAN1 or WAN2 in the house, and some other stuff (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crashplan.com&#34;&gt;CrashPlan&lt;/a&gt; currently) goes though Digital Ocean. Everything that has no static route goes though Hetzner&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally, the static side of things should be removed, and a more dynamic setup done. How that works, i have no idea&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spotify.com&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; have 2 posts about their SDN Internet Router (&lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.spotify.com/2016/01/26/sdn-internet-router-part-1/&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.spotify.com/2016/01/27/sdn-internet-router-part-2/&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;) which is an interesting idea&amp;hellip; More digging and research is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. Everything currently seems to be working, mostly, and tweaks can be made easily&amp;hellip; I have a couple posts i have in my head, including something to do with automating bringing up new machines (probably with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ansible.com/&#34;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; or something like it), more monitoring, and some other stuff too&amp;hellip; Any questions, leave a comment, and i will get back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[UPDATE] I wrote a quick and dirty app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/whoistozebraconfig&#34;&gt;WhoIsToZebraConfig&lt;/a&gt; which takes an AS Number, looks up the info in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radb.net/&#34;&gt;Merit RADb&lt;/a&gt; (with the help of some code from &lt;a href=&#34;https://coderbuddy.wordpress.com/2010/10/12/a-simple-c-class-to-get-whois-information/&#34;&gt;Coder Buddy&lt;/a&gt;) and outputs what you need to put into your Zebra Config&amp;hellip; should save me some time, and it might save you time too&amp;hellip;  shout if you have questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 7 - ECMP (kind of)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 7 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/05/17/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition.html&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned I am now using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; for hosting a dedicated box. Thats still live, and going well. I have a /29 IP range (6 usable) and also 2 other IPs. So far, so good&amp;hellip; But because i was using a Socks Server, I was not fully able to use the /29 ips&amp;hellip; I use something like as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/68894593dd44acb4820617aef2889fd6.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;essentially, for each public IP i have that i want to map to an internal IP, i have a POST and PRE ROUTING rule, plus the required forward rules&amp;hellip; But, if socks are used, then that goes out the Window, since TCP traffic will look like its coming from the socks server&amp;hellip; So, i killed the socks server, removed the IPTables rule, and then realized that while outgoing traffic was being balanced somewhat (2 default rules on the internal box pointing at the OpenVPN IPs from the Hetzner box) incoming was a problem. Hetzner knew how to get to my internal network, but only though one ip&amp;hellip; enter Quagga and Zebra&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga&lt;/a&gt; is a routing software suite, which can do protocols like OSPF, BGP and RIP, and Zebra is the component that does static routing. using their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/docs/docs-info.html#Static-Route-Commands&#34;&gt;documentation on static routes&lt;/a&gt;, I created a static route to my internal network with 2 next hops, the OVPN IPs from the internal box&amp;hellip; and, after restarting Quagga, all works! happy days! now i can forward ips from outside the network to inside the network correctly, and they look like they are the public ip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, whats next then? well, I now have a server in Germany (Hetzner) and one in France (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.com&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt;), and can spin one up in the UK or the US (&lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;). Given that i have Quagga running on the box, i am now thinking of trying to see if its possible to route traffic depending on distance or something similar&amp;hellip; If i am trying to hit a server in Hetzner&amp;rsquo;s DC, i should go though Germany. If its in Digital Ocean, go though either US or UK servers, same with OVH. Then figure out who has the fastest links to, say, Amazon, Azure, Netflix, BBC, Dropbox, etc, and add either static or dynamic links to the router&amp;hellip; essentially, thats the theory&amp;hellip; lets see how that works&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 6 - Hetzner Edition</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 6 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its been a while, since I posted, and there are some, well, pretty major changes since the last time&amp;hellip; Lets start are the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; for my hosting provider. I was using their $20 a month server (2 cores, 2GB RAM, 40GB SSD, 3TB transfer), and it was all good&amp;hellip; But I noticed that every now and again I would need to reboot the box. I also noticed that when transferring large files or using higher bandwidth (400mb/s+) the 100% of both cores were being used. So, I wanted to move to something with more power&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also was limited to IP addresses. Yes, Digital Ocean do offer IPv6, but I could only get 1 IPv4 address&amp;hellip; and I wanted more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I went back to some old friends of mine, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;, and bought a dedicated server with a Quad Core Xeon E3, 32GB RAM, 4*3 TB HDDs, 1Gbit/s network connection with 30TB transfer per month and a KVMoIP plugged in. I also got 2 extra standard IPs and a /29 (8 IPs, 6 usable). I will explain that next. I installed Debian 8.4 on the first disk, and I am planning on using the other 3 for storage of some sort. I then installed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multipath-tcp.org&#34;&gt;MPTCP kernel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt;, Squid and a Socks server (same as the Digital Ocean box) and reconfigured the home machine&amp;hellip; All good! Now when browsing the web, everywhere thinks I am in Germany, but so far, so good&amp;hellip; Speed tests are about the same, but I have my theory about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equal-cost_multi-path_routing&#34;&gt;ECMP&lt;/a&gt; to try this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the extra IPs, I am working on doing full IP forwarding, not just port forwarding. One of my IPs in pointing directly at my &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;Meraki MX64&lt;/a&gt; in house (a post on the Meraki stuff is coming, eventually&amp;hellip;) and another at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/proliantml110.html&#34;&gt;Proliant box&lt;/a&gt;, and I plan on pointing other IPs at machines in the DMZ or a firewall of some sort. the /29 is routed though the IP pointing at the Proliant, so that makes life easier. The original IP is only used for SSH and OVPN from the house. it should not do much else. All network traffic in house is coming from other of the other IPs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, so far, so good. Hopefully the ECMP stuff works correctly, so I will do an updated post soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Web and Desktop Apps 2016 edition</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/useful-web-and-desktop-apps-2016-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/useful-web-and-desktop-apps-2016-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided to do a post on some of my favourite tools to use for development, administration, etc. It’s kind of like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/ScottHanselmans2014UltimateDeveloperAndPowerUsersToolListForWindows.aspx&#34;&gt;Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s Ultimate Tools list&lt;/a&gt;, but not as popular and about 2 years newer&amp;hellip; Anyway, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/ToolsList/&#34;&gt;list is available here&lt;/a&gt;, and will be updated over time, much like my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/DailyCarry/&#34;&gt;Daily Carry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/&#34;&gt;Computers&lt;/a&gt; pages. If you are interested, you add links though &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; by editing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie/blob/master/_data/toolslist.yml&#34;&gt;toolslist.yml data file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Mad) Max Speed - The Road Warrior (Internet connection) (double speed internet Part 5)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 5 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is going to be an update and theoretical post. probably very little &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; stuff going on here, mostly updates, and what I am planning on doing later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.technet.com/b/exchange/archive/2004/07/12/180899.aspx&#34;&gt;OOF&lt;/a&gt; sick, so I have not done much work, but I have been surfing the web, watching videos, downloading stuff, etc., so I have an idea of how things are going. First, as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/04/14/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4.html&#34;&gt;the previous post&lt;/a&gt; I have MPTCP, Squid, Socks Servers, OpenVPN and IPTables doing their magic. 2 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt; tunnels between the house and &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;. All TCP Traffic (bar port 80) is sent over socks to the box in the cloud using RedSocks. All UDP traffic is sent direct over OpenVPN. Since MPTCP is in the mix, all socks traffic is actually split over the 2 connections. All port 80 traffic, and 443 (if the client is using local Squid as their proxy) is sent round-robin between the 2 upstream IPs to Squid (2 OpenVPN end points).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I have noticed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every now and again, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/darkk/redsocks&#34;&gt;RedSocks&lt;/a&gt; crashes&amp;hellip; just full on dies. It’s just a matter of starting again, but it’s a pain&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have had to restart squid a couple of times&amp;hellip; not too often though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was a power outage in the house a few days back&amp;hellip; so, when everything came back online, it was a bit of a pain bringing all connections back to life. I do have to figure out a better plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have to read more on this ECMP stuff. Hopefully it will do what I am hoping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the theoretical stuff. I started thinking, could this work outside the house? Could you build this into something smaller, like a Raspberry Pi, and stick 2 or more USB Modems in, connect it back to a server in the cloud, setup P2P OpenVPN connections and then get more than a single modem speed download? The problems I can see are around MPTCP. I am not sure if it has been ported to ARM to run on a Raspberry Pi. Second, the max you could ever get out of it is 100Mbit/s, given the 10/100mb network port on board&amp;hellip; and you may need extra power for the USB dongles. Also, getting P2P connections may be complicated, given the non-static IPs on the modems, though, in theory, non-P2P OpenVPN could work&amp;hellip; Again, it’s a theory. I had the though and that’s where the title came from&amp;hellip; anyway, throwing it out there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable Modems = Double Speed? Part 4</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 4 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double%Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this week I went in a completely different direction that I have been thinking recently&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the basic theory is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am still using MPTCP kernels on both upstream and local machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;now have 2 P2P UDP &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt; tunnels between house and cloud. Example config is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/09c6928d1d8f6752ea84fd895451bbe5&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all TCP traffic (bar port 80) that hits the router in house is redirected to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/darkk/redsocks&#34;&gt;RedSocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RedSocks uses a socks server, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inet.no/dante/&#34;&gt;Dante&lt;/a&gt;, as an upstream server on the cloud box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;since the socks traffic is over TCP (inside the UDP OpenVPN tunnel) it uses MPTCP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;having socks running, gives me quite the download speed, turning it off does not, hence the following tweet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Hmmmm&amp;hellip; If I have socks on, the Internet is fast 400mb/s+). But without socks, it&amp;#39;s down to 60&amp;hellip; Feck&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tiernan (@tiernano) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tiernano/status/720186883905626112&#34;&gt;April 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am also noticing that I am starting to hit the limits of my upstream VM. If downloading or uploading at speed, the processor cores (2 in the case of the box I am currently running) are pegged at pretty much 100% full&amp;hellip; Well, 80ish, but that because the other 20% is being used by Dante. I am noticing I can hit a full 72Mbit/s up, but the max currently downloading is about 400, maybe 450&amp;hellip; Need a faster box now&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I mentioned port 80 not being set over socks. That&amp;rsquo;s because its redirected to Squid. Squid (in house) then uses Squid (in cloud) as a parent. There are 2 round-robin parents for squid, one on each OpenVPN connection IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all other traffic (UDP, ICMP, etc.) are sent over the OpenVPN connection&amp;hellip; currently only one is picked, but I have a cunning plan&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube AsXKS8Nyu8Q %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cunning plan? Well, if I am reading the internet correctly, and I would like to think I am, I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equal-cost_multi-path_routing&#34;&gt;ECMP&lt;/a&gt;, or Equal Cost Multi-Path Routing, could help&amp;hellip; Again, it’s a fledgling idea currently, and I am still reading the documentation, but if it works&amp;hellip; Well&amp;hellip; I not sure&amp;hellip; let’s see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Jekyll on Bash On Ubuntu on Windows</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/installing-jekyll-on-bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/installing-jekyll-on-bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the 2016 Build conference, Microsoft announced that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/31/bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows.html&#34;&gt;Bash on Ubuntu on Windows&lt;/a&gt; was coming. Well, it &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/commandline/2016/04/06/bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows-download-now-3/&#34;&gt;came out last week&lt;/a&gt;, and I installed it as soon as I could! My next challenge was to get &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to run and install on it, so I can build and preview this site on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/surface/en-us/devices/surface-book&#34;&gt;Surface Book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first, I needed to install version 2.0 of Ruby. There is a bit of messing involved for this, but first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get update
apt-get install ruby2.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when you run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby -v
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you will still see ruby 1.9.x installed&amp;hellip; and the github-pages gem, which includes Jekyll 3, requires ruby 2.0&amp;hellip; ugh. after reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/ruby2.0/+bug/1310292&#34;&gt;this very long bug report&lt;/a&gt; I got this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Rename original out of the way, so updates / reinstalls don&#39;t squash our hack fix
dpkg-divert --add --rename --divert /usr/bin/ruby.divert /usr/bin/ruby
dpkg-divert --add --rename --divert /usr/bin/gem.divert /usr/bin/gem
# Create an alternatives entry pointing ruby -&amp;gt; ruby2.0
update-alternatives --install /usr/bin/ruby ruby /usr/bin/ruby2.0 1
update-alternatives --install /usr/bin/gem gem /usr/bin/gem2.0 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when I run ruby -v, I am told I am on version 2.0! Happy days! Next, i installed bundler using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which uses a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie/blob/master/Gemfile&#34;&gt;Gemfile&lt;/a&gt; to install the required gems, so running&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; install all required gems but no luck&amp;hellip; I tried adding ruby2.0 dev to the mix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install ruby2.0-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but running jekyll from bash said it did not exist, and running&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle exec jekyll build
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;failed with a memory issue&amp;hellip; ugh&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, next, I tried&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install github-pages -V
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-v makes it verbose, so you can see what&amp;rsquo;s going on&amp;hellip; after a bit of time, and lots of output to the screen&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll build
bash: /usr/bin/jekyll: No such file or directory
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FECK! So, after a bit more digging, i find that jekyll is actually in /usr/local/bin/jekyll&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln /usr/local/bin/jekyll /usr/bin/jekyll
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;solves that problem!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now running&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll build
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;works perfectly, as does&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll serve
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAPPY DAYS! Mind you, I am only using this as a testing and writing system. I have not tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/laurilehmijoki/s3_website&#34;&gt;s3_website&lt;/a&gt; just yet, but that is being sorted elsewhere anyway. Maybe my next post will explain that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable modems = Double speed? Part 3</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 3 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/22/2-Cable-Modems-Double-Internet-Speed-part1.html&#34;&gt;Part 1 of this series&lt;/a&gt; I explained the why and what I wanted to do for this &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo;. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/30/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2.html&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; I did some basic testing of both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multipath-tcp.org&#34;&gt;MPTCP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://zehome.github.io/MLVPN&#34;&gt;MLVPN&lt;/a&gt;. I also mentioned trying &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Point-to-Point_Protocol#PPP_Configuration_Options&#34;&gt;MMPPP&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;http://vtun.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;vtund&lt;/a&gt; but it has been a while since I did that testing, and it had not been on bare metal. So, this post is a follow up, where I am using bare metal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first, the setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ProLiant box is running Debian 8.3 x64, and has both vtund and ppp installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digtial Ocean&lt;/a&gt; box also has Debian 8.3, vtund and ppp installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walked though the guide from &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnlewis.ie/bonding-teaming-internet-connections/&#34;&gt;John Lewis&lt;/a&gt; and made some changes to the configs. the main ones are mentioned below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once done, i installed both iperf and iftop on both boxes, and ran&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iperf -s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the Digital Ocean box and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iperf -c 192.168.10.1 -d
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the local box. And, well, the results where not as expected. Pretty poor actually:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, using Squid installed on the DO box, i tried using WGET to download a file using it. If I did this on the DO box itself, i was getting 100MBytes/s&amp;hellip; When I ran it over the MLPPP box, well, under 7 was achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-downloading-over-mlppp-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-downloading-over-mlppp.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;WGET over Squid over MLPPP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then i though it might have been Squid. So, since the file had been downloaded to DO, i SFTPed into the box over the MLPPP link, and tried again&amp;hellip; Again, pretty poor result. I think i seen it hit about 7MB a sec at one stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp2-over-mlppp-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp2-over-mlppp.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;SFTP over MLPPP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what is showing on the DO box when running the SFTP download. You can see 2 connections from the 2 WAN links at home hitting the box, and they are balanced. Its just nowhere near the speed they are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp-over-mlppp-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp-over-mlppp.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;iftop running on server&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not get a screen shot of this, but when I tried with iperf, thinking it might have been overhead of SFTP or Squid, I was getting results matching what I was seeing with SFTP. Downloads in the 55-60mbit/s range for download and 40ish for upload. 40 is still faster than 1 link, mind you&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned that I had made some minor tweaks to the configs from what John had written. Well, mostly it was config changes to how routing was done. In Johns case, he is bonding a DSL and a HSDPA connection, so he had setup to do for logging into his PPP modem and connecting. Also, when he setup the interfaces, he routing tables in there. I have mine setup in a single config file, like as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/a9a642c4d029c0dcf8beb926b3588991.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have changed the names from adsl1 and 2 to WAN1 and 2, and the IPs are changed from internal IPs to my public IPs. I manually run this when setting up my connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing else on his config files have changed. I did not do any of the masquerading stuff, mainly cause this was testing. I just want a tunnel to start with. When reading the vtund.conf file, you can see that encryption and compression are both turned off, and and the same in the ppp configuration. I also don&amp;rsquo;t think the issue is to do with the CPU performance, since these are the screenshots of top running on both boxes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-server-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-server.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Top on Server&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-client-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-client.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Top on Client&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in both cases, CPU usage is sub 6% for VTUN and SSH seems to be using less than 10%. So, now, I&amp;rsquo;m baffled as to why this is not performing as expected&amp;hellip; More testing required!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[update 4/4/2016] - fixing images so they are clickable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash on Ubuntu on Windows</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buildwindows.com/&#34;&gt;Build 2016&lt;/a&gt; is on this week, and there were a lot of interesting developments yesterday, but the one that interested me the most is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/DevelopersCanRunBashShellAndUsermodeUbuntuLinuxBinariesOnWindows10.aspx&#34;&gt;Bash on Ubuntu on Windows&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.dustinkirkland.com/2016/03/ubuntu-on-windows.html&#34;&gt;Dustin from Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; has a more details, and Scott Hanselman has posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/Build/2016/C906&#34;&gt;a technical video&lt;/a&gt; about this. This is very interesting, and I CANT WAIT TO GET MY HANDS ON IT! But, I do have some questions, which I thought I would put down in blog format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the post by Dustin, it seems that low level Linux calls are being handled and translated to Windows system calls. Which makes me think, could &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; Linux Distro work? Could &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.org&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redhat.com&#34;&gt;RedHat&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centos.org&#34;&gt;Centos&lt;/a&gt; work in the same way?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will this Work on Windows Server 2016 when it launches?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given that it calling down to a low level, could GUI applications work too?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shut up and take my money! I WANT IT NOW!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there are my questions&amp;hellip; This is very cool, and I cannot wait to get my hands on this. Just wondering if this will be available to &lt;a href=&#34;https://insider.windows.com/&#34;&gt;Windows Insiders&lt;/a&gt; sooner, rather than later?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPTCP, SSH, Squid, OpenVPN (and 2 Cable modems) = Double Speed? Not quite... Part 2</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 2 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/22/2-Cable-Modems-Double-Internet-Speed-part1.html&#34;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt; I explained what i was trying to do&amp;hellip; This post explains what i have been working on recently, and performance results&amp;hellip;
So, first, what have i tried&amp;hellip; There are 3 different things i have tried, and here are some of their details. Some will need to be updated (other parts of this series), and others i will try get back to eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware-and-servers-used&#34;&gt;Hardware and servers used&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test this, i am using my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/proliantml110.html&#34;&gt;HP Proliant ML110 G5&lt;/a&gt; running either Ubuntu or Debian Linux, with 2 GigE connections directly to the cable modems, and 1 connection to the LAN (for SSH and testing). The LAN has no gateway set, and the 2 WAN connections have DHCP enabled. They get fully public IP addresses. Upstream, I am using either &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scaleway.com&#34;&gt;ScaleWay&lt;/a&gt; VPS boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Ocean has the advantage of allowing different Kernels, so i have been using them for testing MPTCP. As for ScaleWay, well, their BareMetal C2S/M/L boxes have between 4 and 8 cores (4 for the S, 8 for the M and L) and between 8 and 32Gb RAM (S=8, M=16, L=32GB). The L model also comes with 256GB SSD (plus the boot disk, which seems to be a network disk of some sort) and they all come with lots of bandwidth (i use the L because its got about 800MBit/s to the internet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ping wise, Digital Ocean is about 20-30ms away from the house (I picked London to host the servers) and Scaleway is a little further at about 50ms (They are based in France).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mptcp-multipath-tcp-http-www-multipath-tcp-org&#34;&gt;MPTCP (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multipath-tcp.org&#34;&gt;MultiPath TCP&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MPTCP (their site is a bit wonky as of writing, so bare with me&amp;hellip;) is a Linux Kernel patch that allows TCP connections to use multiple paths&amp;hellip; Essentially, if you have Wifi and 4G in a phone, and MPTCP is enabled, it should allow you to use both connections for TCP traffic, as long as the server upstream supports it. It also allows for easy fail over if, say, you lose your wifi connection. There is an example &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/VWN0ctPi5cw&#34;&gt;video of it on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; which should show the fail over parts and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VMdPI9Cfi9k&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; shows how they managed to get 50Gbit/s out of a 6 10Gb Ethernet connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When i was using MPTCP, I had a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; on both boxes, and told Squid locally to use Squid on the upstream box (over a SSH tunnel, which was over the MPTCP link) as a parent cache. Using this method, i could see (using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ex-parrot.com/pdw/iftop/&#34;&gt;iftop&lt;/a&gt;) that both connections were being used. When trying proper performace testing, I setup a RAM disk on both machines and copied a Linux ISO to the Digtial Ocean Box. Then, using wget and &lt;a href=&#34;http://axel.alioth.debian.org/&#34;&gt;Axel&lt;/a&gt; I downloaded the files using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nginx.com/&#34;&gt;Nginx&lt;/a&gt; on the server, and checked the results. I can max out 1 single connection, plus use about 60-80mbit/s from the second. about 420-440mbit/s total. Disk was not the bottleneck, since I was writing to RAM, so more tests are required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mlvpn&#34;&gt;MLVPN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zehome.github.io/MLVPN&#34;&gt;MLVPN&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty interesting project that caught my eye. The idea is quite simple: you configure the local box and server, as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;http://mlvpn.readthedocs.org/en/latest/linux_example.html&#34;&gt;their example guide&lt;/a&gt; and run the MLVPN program on the server, then the client. It creates 2 VPN tunnels between the 2 boxes, and bonds them&amp;hellip; In my case, i was given an IP of 10.42.42.1 on my box in house and 10.42.42.2 on the server. Any traffic over that tunnel is bonded&amp;hellip; Problem is, it seems to be quite processor intensive: my Digital Ocean box was showing one cpu core (out of 2) maxing out at around 80% and my Proliant in house maxing around the 70% mark&amp;hellip; all while transferring data at around 100mbit/s. I tried iperf and got the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20160330-mlvpn-speed-test.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;mlvpn speed test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;getting 50mbit/s upload is good, in reality, since in theory my max speed would be 72, without overhead. but 116mb/s down is less than a third the max speed of a single connection. So, I tried just uploads and downloads&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upload Only (from local machine to server)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20160330-mlvpn-speed-test-upload-only.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;mlvpn upload only test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download Only (from server to local machine)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20160330-mlvpn-speed-test-download-only.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;mlvpn download only test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the download speed has increased a little, to 176Mbit/s, but the upload speed is now at over 60MBit/s!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still.. download is as important as upload, and given I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to get it to max out one connection, never mind 2, even more testing is required&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mlppp-using-vtun&#34;&gt;MLPPP (using VTUN)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one i need to come back to&amp;hellip; Used the guide from &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnlewis.ie/bonding-teaming-internet-connections/&#34;&gt;John Lewis&lt;/a&gt; but was only managing to get about 100Mbit/s&amp;hellip; I was originally using a VM (so disk may have been the issue) and also had the connection behind my EdgeRouter, so it might have been firewall rules causing a slow down. But I do need to come back to this soon&amp;hellip; Watch this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, at the moment, all I can conclude is that there is more testing required. Upload wise, i can somewhat use most of my bandwidth with MLVPN, and I did see promising results with MPTCP. I gave up a bit too early with MLPPP, so more testing is required with that. Also, all tests are using just iperf between boxes. I did use squid with the MPTCP box for a while, but not for proper performance testing. So, even once this is all sorted out, i will need to turn this into a proper &amp;ldquo;router&amp;rdquo; too&amp;hellip; So, conclusion? this was originally meant to be a 2 parter&amp;hellip; now it looks like I will require a lot more parts&amp;hellip; Watch this space&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration and Blogging</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/continuous-integration-and-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/continuous-integration-and-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in August of 2012, I started this site using Git and Jekyll. I hosted most of it at home, pushing to a server in house. Then, a few years back, I moved to pushing the files to &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/s3/&#34;&gt;Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt; and had &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/&#34;&gt;Cloud Front&lt;/a&gt; doing distribution. The last moved had me hosting the files in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nearlyfreespeech.net&#34;&gt;NearlyFreeSpeech.NET&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudflare.com&#34;&gt;Cloud Flare&lt;/a&gt; doing the content distribution&amp;hellip; Well, that changed over the last few days&amp;hellip; again&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, you are still hitting Cloud Flare when you hit this site, but the backend is back to being hosted on Amazon S3. But the files getting to S3 is more interesting now. All the &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; for this site is up on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie&#34;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; and any time something is checked in, &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie&#34;&gt;Travis CI&lt;/a&gt; kicks off, builds the files using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie/issues&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and pushes to S3 using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/laurilehmijoki/s3_website&#34;&gt;s3_website&lt;/a&gt;. All my &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; keys are hidden in Travis-CI, so no one can access them but me. This makes updating the site a lot easier. I can create a file in GitHub directly, preview it, make changes, etc., and then check in. Once checked in, Travis kicks off, builds and deploys. All Good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also means that if &amp;ldquo;bugs&amp;rdquo; are found on the site (by you, my dear reader), or if you have queries for some things, a &amp;ldquo;bug report&amp;rdquo; can be opened on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie/issues&#34;&gt;issues log&lt;/a&gt;. I already have a bug for making the site faster&amp;hellip; Anything else you want me to change?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable modems = Double Internet Speed? Well... not really... Part 1</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-internet-speed-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-internet-speed-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 1 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, a bit of background, and then I will explain what I am currently running in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/30/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2.html&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 15 or so years, I have had at least 2 internet connections in to the house&amp;hellip; 2 of them have always been Cable Modems from NTL, which became UPC, and now is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virginmedia.ie&#34;&gt;Virgin Media&lt;/a&gt;. When I started, i think the modems where 150/50kbit/s and 600/150kb/s, and have steadily increased in speed, currently at 360/36Mbit/s each&amp;hellip; But they have always been somewhat separate, and single thread downloads have always been limited to 1 of the connections&amp;hellip; I have been looking for ways around this for years&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/routers/rv042-dual-wan-vpn-router/index.html&#34;&gt;Linksys RV042 router&lt;/a&gt; which allowed me to load balance my connections&amp;hellip; At the time, and i cant even remember when this was, my total bandwidth would not exceed the router. The RV042 has 2 10/100mbit WAN links and 4 100mb/s LAN links&amp;hellip;So, when the connection bandwidth increased, I moved to a new router&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next router vendor i tried was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mikrotik.com&#34;&gt;Mikrotik&lt;/a&gt;. I tried a few different options, including an &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB1100&#34;&gt;RB1100&lt;/a&gt; and running their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mikrotik.com/software&#34;&gt;RouterOS&lt;/a&gt; on x86 hardware&amp;hellip; Both worked, well, ok, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Load_Balancing#Nth&#34;&gt;Load balancing with nth&lt;/a&gt; stuff did do what i needed, along with other stuff, like routing traffic destined for some sites (like BBC iPlayer) to go over a VPN. But in the end, hardware issues and performance problems with the x86 machine (Mikrotik at the time was limited to 2GB of RAM on x86 hardware) I ended up at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PfSense&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PfSense was installed on the same hardware, a HP ProLiant ML110 G5 with 8GB RAM, a Core2Quad processor and 12 GigE Network cards&amp;hellip; And, on PfSense, things were good&amp;hellip; Performance was stable, load balancing worked as expected, I could set some traffic to go over certain links, etc. all was good&amp;hellip; But I lacked IPv6&amp;hellip; Plus, the HP used a LOT of power&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current instalment of my network uses a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubnt.com&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti Networks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Edge Router POE&lt;/a&gt;. To show the difference in power, check out the graphs from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/mfi/mpower/&#34;&gt;Ubnt MPower&lt;/a&gt; device. ProLiant first, EdgeRouter second:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-proliant-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Proliant Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-edgerouter-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;EdgeRouter POE Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, the EdgeRouter does not produce as much heat, and its a LOT smaller that the PowerEdge! It does all the same things I could get PfSense to do, in a lot smaller package (I could, in theory, get a smaller box for PfSense).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, where does that leave us? Well, I now have 720Mbit/s down and 72Mbit/s up, if I can do multiple threads for uploading&amp;hellip; But what if I don&amp;rsquo;t? What&amp;rsquo;s next? Well, in the second post, I will explain what I have been trying to do in resent weeks, and what I can do now&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing B2 Uploader and Hubic Testing 2.0</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/announcing-b2uploader-hubictesting20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/announcing-b2uploader-hubictesting20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have 2 new side projects to announce on the site today. First has been running for a while (first check-in was December 28th) and it’s called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/b2uploader&#34;&gt;B2Uploader&lt;/a&gt;. Its a fairly simple Windows application to upload files to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&#34;&gt;BackBlaze B2&lt;/a&gt;. If you are not familiar with &lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.backblaze.com/r/01px2w&#34;&gt;BackBlaze&lt;/a&gt;, they provide unlimited backup storage for the low price of a fiver a month. They are the guys who design the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/cloud-storage-hardware/&#34;&gt;BackBlaze storage pods&lt;/a&gt; (I want one, by the way!) that allow them to provide unlimited storage for the fiver a month (I currently backup over 4Tb to them!), and late last year, they started offing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&#34;&gt;B2&lt;/a&gt; which is a storage platform on their pods, and it has a (somewhat) easy to use API. AND ITS CHEAP! half a cent, up 0.5c, per gig stored per month! That’s crazy cheap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/b2uploader&#34;&gt;B2Uploader&lt;/a&gt; uses the B2 API to upload files (it could do more, but currently, as the name suggests, its upload only). Its quite simple, and all the code is available. More stuff coming over the next few weeks. some of the usual badges for open source applications are below. if you want to shout at me, shout in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://Gitter.im/tiernano/b2uploader&#34;&gt;Gitter chatroom&lt;/a&gt; and I will reply. You can see the latest builds over on &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/tiernano/b2uploader&#34;&gt;travis-ci&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/b2uploader/releases&#34;&gt;latest releases&lt;/a&gt; are available on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://Gitter.im/tiernano/b2uploader?utm_source=badge&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge&amp;amp;utm_content=badge&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://badges.Gitter.im/tiernano/b2uploader.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Join the chat at https://Gitter.im/tiernano/b2uploader&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/tiernano/b2uploader&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/tiernano/b2uploader.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second project is still in the planning phase, and it’s an update to an older project I was working on called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/HubicTesting&#34;&gt;HubicTesting&lt;/a&gt;. The name is very cleverly called, wait for it&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/HubicTesting2.0&#34;&gt;HubicTesting 2.0&lt;/a&gt;! I have mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hubic.com&#34;&gt;Hubic&lt;/a&gt; before &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2015/03/31/HubiC_SWIFT_CURL.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Cheap (about a tenner a month) for lots of storage (10TB!) but an odd API.. It uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.openstack.org/developer/swift/&#34;&gt;Swift&lt;/a&gt; for storage, but has a weird(ish) API for authentication. Anyway, more details will be on the site once I write it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, anyone needing to upload files to B2, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/b2uploader&#34;&gt;B2Uploader&lt;/a&gt;. Want to work with stuff on Hubic, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/HubicTesting2.0&#34;&gt;HubicTesting 2.0&lt;/a&gt;. Any questions, drop me a mail or find me on the Gitter channel. Have a good one!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge Router, Sophos UTM, DMZ and LAN Networks</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/edgerouter-sophosutm-dmz-lan-firwwalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/edgerouter-sophosutm-dmz-lan-firwwalls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;EdgeRouer POE&lt;/a&gt; as my main router for most of the network (some of the network still uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; as a router, but thats being removed soon) for the last few weeks, and i am quite happy with it. I also have a second router, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/unified-threat-management.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM&lt;/a&gt; VM between my first LAN (essentially a DMZ) and my client LAN (there will be more &amp;ldquo;LANs&amp;rdquo; over there soon). The Client LAN is NATed between the DMZ and the LAN, which means anything on the LAN i want to access from the DMZ has to be port forwarded&amp;hellip; Ideally, not much from the LAN should be accessible though the DMZ, but in my initial setup, stuff like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plex.tv&#34;&gt;Plex&lt;/a&gt;, etc, is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What i wanted to do was setup a proper firewall between both networks, without the use of NAT&amp;hellip; Do do this, i first had to disable th masquerading rules in Sophos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530620916/20150930-masquerading-off.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next, on the EdgeRouter, i added a static route to point at the new network:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530620916/20150930-static-route.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, under firewall rules, i allowed what i wanted to allow (in this case, SSH from any DMZ client (not advised) to my Mac Mini).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530620916/20150930-firewall-rules.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, as they say, is that! So far, so good!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 4)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, after some messing, tweaking, and thinking, I have made some progress with the home lab&amp;hellip; or at least broken some stuff&amp;hellip; I mentioned previously that i had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2015/08/05/Ubiquiti-EdgeRouter-POE-In-the-lab.html&#34;&gt;Ubiqititi networks EdgeRouter POE&lt;/a&gt; in the home lab. Originally, the plan was to use a Virtual &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; box for my core router&amp;hellip; Given the power usage of the current PfSense Box (I have 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/mfi/mpower/&#34;&gt;MPower Pro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s watching power in the lab) I am now thinking of moving to just the EdgeRouter for, well, edge routing&amp;hellip;  below is the usage of the ProLiant for the last 12 hours or so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-proliant-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Proliant Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for the same period, here is the usage for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Edge Router&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-edgerouter-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;EdgeRouter POE Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also setting up a DMZ for front facing services, and then a LAN for inside facing machines. There will be a firewall (currently thinking &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/unified-threat-management.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM&lt;/a&gt; or similar) between the DMZ and the network. Some machines will be able to access the DMZ, and there may be machines allowed into the LAN, but only some things&amp;hellip; not even sure if that would be done&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also need to work out the VLAN side of things. I have currently though of the following VLAN setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WAN 1 (connected directly to the Cable modem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WAN 2 (again, direct to cable modem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LAN Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DMZ Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VoIP Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IOT (stuff for running the house, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/ie/thermostat/meet-nest-thermostat/&#34;&gt;Nest&lt;/a&gt;, the MPower devices or the like)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Media Network (Plex, Roku, Apple TV, Chrome Cast, etc. Not sure if i need to separate this, but it might be done&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/switches/catalyst-3560-series-switches/index.html&#34;&gt;Cisco 3560G switch&lt;/a&gt; should do all that, without problems, so no new switch needed&amp;hellip; lets see what i can break over the next while&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Server 2012 R2 returning to The GodBoxV2</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/windwsserver2012r2-returing-to-the-godboxv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/windwsserver2012r2-returing-to-the-godboxv2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few months of running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sabayon.org&#34;&gt;Sabayon&lt;/a&gt; Linux on the GodboxV2, i am going back to Windows Server. Back around October of last year, i installed Windows 10 Preview on the GodBoxV2, and, well, there where issues with graphics drivers, etc. Then, some time after, i cant remember off hand when, i moved to Sabayon Linux. Its based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gentoo.org&#34;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt; but has a lot of the components pre-built. Gentoo is a &amp;ldquo;Build from scratch&amp;rdquo; sort of OS. You get a basic kernel and a basic set of components, but you build everything else from scratch&amp;hellip; including rebuilding the kernel if you want. Sabayon, on the other hand has all that mostly prebuilt, though you can still use Gentoo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/Portage&#34;&gt;Portage&lt;/a&gt; to build stuff yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for the last few months, all was going mostly well&amp;hellip; but I miss Windows. And, given i have pretty much always ran a server OS on my main workstations, I am heading back to Server 2012R2. I was tempted by 2016, but its still very early days&amp;hellip; Maybe i will run it as a VM for a while, but we will see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFS Home storage pool</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zfs-home-dir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zfs-home-dir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://btrfs.wiki.kernel.org/index.php/Main_Page&#34;&gt;BTRFS&lt;/a&gt; pool for my /home directory on Linux failed&amp;hellip; Not sure what happened, but it made me
do something i wanted to do for a while: Build a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ZFS&#34;&gt;ZFS&lt;/a&gt; pool for my home dir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, the pool consists of 4 2Tb hard drives and 1 128Gb SSD. Its setup in RAIDZ1 (equivilent of RAID 5)
and then the SSD is set for caching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create the pool i ran&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;zpool create home raidz sda sde sdf sdg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then, to add the cache drive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;zpool add home cache sdd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the pool (in my case) got mounted to /home, and then i restored my backup to it. to do some tests, i can the
following&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 638891a7d9acac8e396f %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;614MB/s write and 5.3GB a second read is nothing to be sniffed at! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquiti EdgeRouter PoE in the lab</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ubiquiti-edgerouter-poe-in-the-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ubiquiti-edgerouter-poe-in-the-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti EdgeRouter POE&lt;/a&gt; arrived in the house. I got it hooked up to both UPC connections (as secondary connections) and all seems to be working grand. Some notes i wanted to put up here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;out of the box, the install was quite simple. set my Ethernet connection to a static ip in the 192.168.1.x/24 range,
using 192.168.1.1 as gateway and dns, and then point at &lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.1&#34;&gt;http://192.168.1.1&lt;/a&gt; for admin. login (ubit for both username and
password) and heay presto. I was asked did i agree to the license, and then im in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by default, NAT is off&amp;hellip; i turned it on, and enabled DNS and was able to surf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also noticed the software was out of date&amp;hellip; Oddly, there did not seem to be an option to update automatically, but
you can manually download the tar and upload it, which i did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;so far, so good&amp;hellip; not sure yet if i will be using it as my main router, but it may end up being a VoIP router.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, speed test result below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/tiernanotoole/image/upload/v1530620885/20150805.ubiquiti.speedtest.compressed-resized.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Speed Test Result&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti&lt;/a&gt; stuff arriving tomorrow&amp;hellip; will post more stuff then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, this part of my article set will be talking specifically about the router and wireless network. At the moment, my router is way overkill:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old HP Proliant ML110 G5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/29765/Intel-Core2-Quad-Processor-Q6600-8M-Cache-2_40-GHz-1066-MHz-FSB?q=Q6600&#34;&gt;Intel Core2Quad Q6600&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 Gb RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;total of 12 Gigabit network cards (of which 4 are currently used&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;500Gb HDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been playing with some networking in the house and have managed to build some VLANs. The modems are connected both directly to the Router
and to a dedicated switch port for a given VLAN. The plan for the upgrade, which i hope to complete sooner than the rest of the network is as
follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get the ML110 running &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/products/vsphere-hypervisor&#34;&gt;ESXi&lt;/a&gt; and visualize &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt;. Give it 2gb of RAM and some processor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take some of the network cards out of the box. It does not need 12 ports, but maybe leave the 2 quad ports in there. They should be connected
to the main switch trunked. 8 may be overkill, but i never do things by half.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the PFSEnse VM should be connected to all 3 WAN VlANs (900, 901 and 902) and should also have at least one port to the LAN. There may also be
other ports for other internal VLANs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with the spare processor, i can then add other (small) VMs to this machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, in my last post i talked about the requirements for the home lab, and in this post, im going to talk about a few more updates i have made in the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the processors: in the first post, i talked about Xeon D or Xeon E3&amp;hellip; Well, i missed one&amp;hellip; The Xeon E5. I have 2 of these in GodBox 2, and you can get them into a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servethehome.com/asrock-rack-epc612d4i-review-mitx-xeon-e5-platform/&#34;&gt;microATX board&lt;/a&gt;. There does seem to be some limits with the microatx boards, but hopefully enough searching will find me what i am looking for. Ideally, i want it to take &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; DDR3/4 memory (not SODIMMs like the ASRock one above) and also take enough of them to run 64 or 128Gb of ram (thinking 8 would do the job!). Also, i would like to have 4 GigE ports onboard and 1 management port. 4 onboard is not a hard requirement: If i can get one with 2 ports, i can always get a 4 port card for the PCI-Express slot&amp;hellip; Finally, i would like it to have at least 6 SATA ports and possibly an MSATA port. Thinking Boot off MSATA (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Server_2016&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2016 Nano Server&lt;/a&gt; would be used), 2 SSDs and 4 HDDs. Using Storage Spaces, use the 2 SSDs as &amp;ldquo;Fast&amp;rdquo; storage for the pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think i moved off the idea of 10Gb. I like the idea of it, but given a small 10Gb switch costs upwards of a grand, and the plan is to build a machine for that price, i would prefer a fifth machine and using my existing Cisco 48 port switch and leave 10Gb as a future upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, changed from last time round is machine count. Originally i was saying 3-4 machines&amp;hellip; now i am thinking 6-7&amp;hellip; 5-6 of them should be Hyper-V boxes and the last one would be a Media Box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think the Synology or SAN requirement is out&amp;hellip; Hyper-V can be setup to do replication between hosts, and with a 4Gb link to the LAN, i think i should be OK. Also, if i have the media box separate, i should be ok there too. I will detail the media center in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, any suggestions or thoughts on what should and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be looked at?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and Homelab V.Next (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, its that time again&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/Computers&#34;&gt;HomeLab&lt;/a&gt; upgrade time&amp;hellip; Or at least the planning for it. I am in the process of rebuilding my home lab, which involves pull all old servers out of the rack and replacing them with new ones&amp;hellip; It also means rewriting the network, possibly upgrading some existing gear and hopefully getting the whole lot done on a budget of some sort&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why? Well, biggest reason for all this is currently heat and power usage. We use about 4-6x more electricity than the average house here in Ireland, which means our electricity bill is fairly high. It also means that the lab, which is also my office/bedroom, gets quite warm and uncomfortable during the summer month. There is an Air-Con unit in the room, and, well, that&amp;rsquo;s costing the most on electricity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what I got is a basic overview of what I want from the homelab and hopefully in the next post, I will have an idea of what it will look like..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-4 machines running a Hyper Visor (HyperV, VMWare ESXi or other). Leaning more towards Hyper-V purely because its what I got currently and its what we use in our main office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each machine should be connected to at least 2 networks: one for storage and migration, one for &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; to the LAN. There may be more VLANs for other networks, but 2 is a start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ideally, 10Gb connections would be nice, but multiple 1Gb connections would also work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shared storage (iSCSI, SMB3, etc) would also be a nice to have, but may bump up the server count (not actually a problem) but would increase power and cooling costs. An off the shelf box, like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.synology.com&#34;&gt;Synology&lt;/a&gt; could do the job&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower power usage and less heat produced is also a major requirement. Most of the boxes I am decommissioning are older Xeon hardware (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/family/28144/Intel-Xeon-Processor-5000-Sequence#@All&#34;&gt;5000&lt;/a&gt; series upto a &lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/series/33092/Intel-Xeon-Processor-5200-Series#@All&#34;&gt;5200&lt;/a&gt; series process and even an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xeon#Netburst-based_Xeon&#34;&gt;older Xeon P4&lt;/a&gt;!). The newer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.ie/content/www/ie/en/processors/xeon/xeon-processor-e3-family.html&#34;&gt;Xeon E3&lt;/a&gt; and the even newer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.ie/content/www/ie/en/processors/xeon/xeon-processor-d-family.html&#34;&gt;Xeon D&lt;/a&gt; are a lot more efficient, use less power, produce less heat and are way faster than what I currently have. The E3 can use up to 32Gb of RAM and the Xeon D top out at 128Gb&amp;hellip; Me being me would like more than 32Gb RAM&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smaller machines would also be nice. I have been looking at both Xeon D and Xeon E3 Mini-ITX boards and cases for them. I do have a half height Dell Rack, which I host these machines, and ideally, these machines should be rack mountable, but micro ATX cases could work. 2 per shelf would work grand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboard IPMI and KVM support is something I want too&amp;hellip; I do have a KVMoIP switch in the house, and it works, most of the time, but getting a box that has this embedded into the board would be ideal&amp;hellip; A lot of the server boards had it as standard or allowed it to be speced, so that&amp;rsquo;s all good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am also thinking of upgrading the router to a similar spec board&amp;hellip; Possibly a Xeon E3, or even an i5&amp;hellip;. Ideally it should have IPMI and KVMoIP on board and should produce less heat. Biggest issues is getting enough network cards into the box&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are my requirements at a  high level overview. Over time things may change, but lets see how we get on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PFSense with Multiple Public IPs</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/pfsense-with-multiple-public-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/pfsense-with-multiple-public-ips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, a few weeks back, i got my hands on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; Dedicated box. It has a quad core Xeon, 32Gb ram, 3x3Tb hdds, RAID controller and KVMoIP. one of the first thing i did was get myself a /29 IP pool (8 total, 6 usable IPs). There where already 3 IPs given to me: 1 for the KVM, one for the box itself, and 1 as the router for the IP block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, i need to setup my own router, so i picked &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; since its what i run in house. I gave it 2 network connections: 1 connected to the main network adapter on the VMWare ESXi box (public) and one to a virtual switch, which is only used by VMs. The public is the WAN link and it gets a static IP from Hetzner, and the virtual switch is then my &amp;ldquo;LAN&amp;rdquo; link. This allows me to have standard NATed network connections to any VM i have, but then, what do i do with those IPs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after a lot of digging, i found the answer. So, this should help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under firewall, click on Virtual IPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click the plus. I then selected IP alias, selected the WAN interface and set the IP to my first public IP i wanted to give. in my case, i was given a /29 block, and my first address was 176. This is the network address. I used 177. Likewise, my last address is 183, but that cannot be used either as its a broadcast address. give it a description and then hit OK. Repease for all IPs you want to use. TIP: Give each a meaningful description!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, click firewall, NAT and 1:1. Click the add button and select your interface as WAN. set the External Subnet IP as the one you want to use and your internal IP as the machine that will have it. Thats all i did on that screen&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then go to Firewall, NAT, outbound&amp;hellip; this is where things got complicated. Set the mode to &amp;ldquo;Manual outbound NAT rule generation (AON - Advanced Outbound NAT)&amp;rdquo; and click save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then create a new rule: Interface: WAN, Source, Network, IP of the internal machine and then under translation, under address select the IP you want to give it. If you followed my tip in step 2, you should see the descriptions in here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After saving everything and reloading the firewall, visiting a page like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whatsmyip.org&#34;&gt;WhatsMyIP&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://icanhazip.com&#34;&gt;ICanHazIP&lt;/a&gt; should show you your public IP. You can then create firewall rules to allow access. Quick idea would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firewall/Rules, Add, Interface WAN, Destination: Local IP you want to use, and give whatever &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; rules you would (HTTP, lock down to source address, etc). Click apply and hitting that address using what ever method (SSH, HTTP, etc) should work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YMMV, but hopefully this helps! Any questions, leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick tip for internet facing ESXi servers</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/quick-tip-for-internet-facing-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 08:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/quick-tip-for-internet-facing-esxi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick tip for all you with internet facing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/vsphere-hypervisor&#34;&gt;VMWare ESXi&lt;/a&gt; Hosts. I
have just got my hands on a box on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; network (more on
that later) and using their LARA system i installed ESXi on it. All was good, then I tried login in a couple hours later and i kept getting errors about my password being wrong&amp;hellip; So, i tried a few more times,  got pissed off and rebooted the box (had to do a hard reboot, since i couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get in over KVM). I though this was a hardware issue, or a config issue, and left it&amp;hellip; yesterday, i had the console open most of the day, and when looking at something i noticed this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/tiernanotoole/image/upload/v1530620877/20150520-esxi-login-errors.png&#34; alt=&#34;ESXi Errors&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s why I couldn&amp;rsquo;t login! So, tip: create a second user account, name it something other than root, give it a secure password and use that to login to your ESXi box. Ideally, your ESXi box should be behind a firewall, but in the case of a dedicated server, that may not be financially feasible&amp;hellip; Hope this helps someone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLANs, Wifi and Mikrotik</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/vlans-wifi-and-mikrotik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/vlans-wifi-and-mikrotik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, while i was recovering from surgery, i attended a Webinar on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meraki.com&#34;&gt;Cisco Meraki&lt;/a&gt; devices. After the webinar, i was contacted by Maraki and given a &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/wireless/mr18&#34;&gt;MR18&lt;/a&gt; with a 3 year license, to play with and evaluate. So, i set it up in the house and all was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thing is, the wifi in the house was grand previously. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB951G-2HnD&#34;&gt;Routerboard RB951G&lt;/a&gt; which does the job and has no issues. And because i am mostly offsite in the office i work, and because i need to remotely manage the network, the MR18 is going into the office from tomorrow morning. I may talk about the MR18 and the rest of the Meraki gear later on, but this is not that post. This post is about something the MR18 did, and i wanted to do on the RB951.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the MR18 allows you to create multiple Wifi SSIDs, each with different encryption and security and can use different VLANs. Now, the Mikrotik does the same, but the VLANs stuff is not that easy to figure out. but essentially, what i needed to do was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;create your new wifi SSIDs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/interface wireless
add master-interface=wlan1 name=wlan1.10 ssid=vlan10
add master-interface=wlan1 name=wlan1.20 ssid=vlan20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next, create your vlans. these need to be connected back to your main
ethernet connection. In the case of my RB951, there are 5 ethernet
ports. 1 is the gateway back to my Cisco switch and on to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; router. 2-5 are all slaves of number 1, which is a master. So, 1 is essentially a trunk network. So, vlans are created on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/interface vlan
add name=vlan10 interface=ether1-gateway name=ether1.10 vlan-id=10
add name=vlan20 interface=ether1-gateway name=ether1.20 vlan-id=20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next, a bridge to connect them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/interface bridge
add name=vlan10
add name=vlan20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and connect them to the bridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/interface bridge port
add bridge=vlan10 interface ether1.10
add bridge=vlan10 interface wlan1.10
add bridge=vlan20 interface ether1.20
add bridge=vlan20 interface wlan1.20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thats all i needed to do. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/free-tools/sophos-utm-home-edition.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM Home edition&lt;/a&gt; running on a vm for testing, which vlan10 is connected to. It has an upstream connection back to the PFSense box, which has it firewalled off and allows it outside the network, not nothing else. I am planning on doing this with other firewalls, just to do some testing with. This allows me to connect my phone or laptop, or any other wifi device, to a given wifi connection and then be on my way. I also have an older Dell PowerConnect switch, which, if i ever get around to it, will have multiple connections back to the Cisco and then allow physical devices to connect to different vlans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any questions, comments, etc, leave a comment blow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using git and Route53 together</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/using-git-and-route53/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/using-git-and-route53/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;so, earlier on today, i was talking about using &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2015/05/07/git-push-dns.html&#34;&gt;Git with a DNS service called LuaDNS&lt;/a&gt; to update your DNS records. Well, thing is, i have 30+ domains registered, and of them about 25 are hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Route53&lt;/a&gt;. So, moving ALL of them seems, well at the moment, excessive&amp;hellip; So, i went digging&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there is a tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/barnybug/cli53&#34;&gt;cli53&lt;/a&gt; which will allow you to manage route53 objects from the command line. It can also export your zones to BIND format and then re-import them if you have made changes&amp;hellip; This all came out of a blog post by the guys and gals at &lt;a href=&#34;https://netguru.co/blog/ci-your-dns-setup&#34;&gt;netguru&lt;/a&gt; who showed how they integrate their DNS records with their Continuous Integration&amp;hellip; Now, i have not gotten to that stage, just yet, but its only 1 step more down the road&amp;hellip; but I don&amp;rsquo;t have my zones in bind format&amp;hellip; So, how do i do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tweaked their block of ruby code (first time playing with ruby, be gentle with me) and got the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist f11fbec2075b8bf19d57 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;essentially, it runs cli53 (you may need to change your path) and then creates .bind files for each zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then, using their code below, you can re-import them to Route53:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 7249547 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i have exported all mine, added them to git and done some testing&amp;hellip; All seems to be in order&amp;hellip; once i do some tweaks, i can get that CI piece working and it should be all magic&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Push DNS</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/git-push-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/git-push-dns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are now a lot of services that have &amp;ldquo;git push&amp;rdquo; options available&amp;hellip; you can build websites with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azure.com&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, books using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sharelatex.com/&#34;&gt;ShareLaTeX&lt;/a&gt; and now, DNS using &lt;a href=&#34;http://luadns.com&#34;&gt;LuaDNS&lt;/a&gt;. I have one zone
running at the moment (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tiernanotoole.net&#34;&gt;tiernanotoole.net&lt;/a&gt;) and you can see the DNS records on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/dns&#34;&gt;github here&lt;/a&gt;. I am
tempted at moving other records over soon&amp;hellip; but i am currently on &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;Amazon Route53&lt;/a&gt; and 1: its works, so
dont break it, and 2, not sure how to bulk export records from Route53 to Bind or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.luadns.com/help.html#lua-zone-file-format&#34;&gt;Lua&lt;/a&gt; format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[update] 2 quick updates: 1) their free account, which is what i am using, allows 3 domains and 30 host
records. they also charge less than &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;Route53&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;route 53 for 10 domains per year cost 50c per domain (first 25) per month, then query charges. total,
about $60 + queries (@40c per million).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;luadns cost $29 a year for 10 domains, 5 million (ish) querys a month and 500 host records&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think i have nearly 30 domain on AWS&amp;hellip; so, their $59 a year package, which include 30 domains, would
probably save me money&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and 2) i forgot about one of those git push services&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://developermail.io/&#34;&gt;DeveloperMail&lt;/a&gt; is a service, for developers,
for managing email servers. IMAP, SMTP, Git&amp;hellip; all supported! just signed up&amp;hellip; $2 a month per user. Lets
see how this works&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulk compressing images for the Web</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/bulk-compressing-images-for-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/bulk-compressing-images-for-the-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that all my sites are running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; I am trying to get them optimized for &lt;strong&gt;SPEED&lt;/strong&gt; which meant
looking at all the stuff that takes time to download&amp;hellip; There are more tweaks (and possibly posts) coming down
the road, but to start, I needed to look at images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first. I&amp;rsquo;m running this on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sabayon.org&#34;&gt;Sabayon Linux&lt;/a&gt; box, so some of the install commands will be different&amp;hellip; (Also, i do need to explain why I moved from Windows to Linux on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/GodBoxV2.html&#34;&gt;GodboxV2&lt;/a&gt;, but that&amp;rsquo;s a different post&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, install &lt;a href=&#34;http://optipng.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;OptiPNG&lt;/a&gt; (they have a Windows build too&amp;hellip;) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kokkonen.net/tjko/projects.html&#34;&gt;JPEGOptim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo equo install optipng
sudo equo install jpegoptim
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[UPDATE] I tried this on an Ubutnu Box, and to install both of these, the package names are the same. so, to install both:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install optipng jpegoptim
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, using the Linux find command (this should work also on OSX&amp;hellip;) run OptiPNG and JPEGOptim on all pngs and
jpgs in your given directory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;find . -iname &amp;quot;*.png&amp;quot; -exec optipng {} \;
find . -iname &amp;quot;*.jpe?g&amp;quot; -exec jpegoptim {} \;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;depending on how many images (and how fast your machine is) it should take a min or two&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! I did a git status, which showed me all the changed images, and then deployed the Jekyll sites&amp;hellip; All
good! That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All blogs moved to Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/all-blogs-moved-to-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 12:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/all-blogs-moved-to-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, its finally happened. All my blogs, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net&#34;&gt;Tiernan&amp;rsquo;s Comms Closet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekphotographer.com&#34;&gt;GeekPhotographer&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://podcast.tiernanotoole.ie&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/a&gt; have been
moved to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote up &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/blog-move-details/&#34;&gt;a long and complicated&lt;/a&gt; post explaining how I did it&amp;hellip; Now, i dont have to worry
about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordpress.org&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; security issues on my home sites! Happy Days!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubic and Duplicity</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/duplicity_hubic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/duplicity_hubic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://hubic.com/home/new/?referral=GMSQVQ&#34;&gt;HubiC&lt;/a&gt; in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2015/03/31/HubiC_SWIFT_CURL.html&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, and in it i said that you could use &lt;a href=&#34;http://duplicity.nongnu.org/&#34;&gt;Duplicity&lt;/a&gt; for backups. Well, this is how you get it to work&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, i am using Ubuntu 14.04 (i think&amp;hellip;). I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; in house for a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its running &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net&#34;&gt;Tiernan&amp;rsquo;s Comms Closet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekphotographer.com&#34;&gt;GeekPhotographer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://podcast.tiernanotoole.ie&#34;&gt;Tiernan&amp;rsquo;s Podcast&lt;/a&gt; all in house, aswell as being used to &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/29/NewSite.html&#34;&gt;build this site&lt;/a&gt;. The Web Server and MySQL Server are seperated, MySQL running on Windows, web on Ubuntu&amp;hellip; but thats a different story&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a couple of proxy servers running Ubuntu also&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other general servers running Ubuntu&amp;hellip; dont ask, cause i cant remember what they do half the time&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;a href=&#34;http://duplicity.nongnu.org/&#34;&gt;Duplicity&lt;/a&gt; is a backup application. From their website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duplicity backs directories by producing encrypted tar-format volumes and uploading them to a remote or local file server. Because duplicity uses librsync, the incremental archives are space efficient and only record the parts of files that have changed since the last backup. Because duplicity uses GnuPG to encrypt and/or sign these archives, they will be safe from spying and/or modification by the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The duplicity package also includes the rdiffdir utility. Rdiffdir is an extension of librsync&amp;rsquo;s rdiff to directories&amp;mdash;it can be used to produce signatures and deltas of directories as well as regular files. These signatures and deltas are in GNU tar format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do we get it working? Well, givin that i am on Ubuntu, these are the steps i needed to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first, we need some credentials and API keys&amp;hellip; If you havent signed up for &lt;a href=&#34;https://hubic.com/home/new/?referral=GMSQVQ&#34;&gt;HubiC&lt;/a&gt; Do so now&amp;hellip; That url gets you an extra 5Gb if you sign up for free (usually 25Gb) or if you pay 1EUR a month, you get 110Gb (usually 100Gb) and 5EUR a month gets you a staggering 10TB (yup! Terabytes!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to Hubic, and in the menu go to &amp;lsquo;My Account&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Developers&amp;rsquo;. in here, create a new application (name and URL to redirect to&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost&#34;&gt;http://localhost&lt;/a&gt; seems to work correctly). Get the Client ID and Secret ID that was given to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take the contents of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/86ab2e08ba4e588a343a&#34;&gt;the following gist&lt;/a&gt; and replace your own details&amp;hellip; I know, i am not a fan of sticking my password in a txt file&amp;hellip; but it should be your local machine&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that file should be in your home directory and should be called .hubic_credentials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add the duplicity PPA project (&lt;a href=&#34;https://launchpad.net/~duplicity-team/+archive/ubuntu/ppa&#34;&gt;https://launchpad.net/~duplicity-team/+archive/ubuntu/ppa&lt;/a&gt;) to ubuntu using the add-apt-repository command (details on the link above, under the link &amp;lsquo;read about installing&amp;rsquo;). for me, i just called &amp;lsquo;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:duplicity-team/ppa&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install duplicity by doing &amp;lsquo;sudo apt-get install duplicity&amp;rsquo;. Dont forget (its in the tutorial above!) to do an &amp;lsquo;sudo apt-get update&amp;rsquo; first!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When i ran that, there where a few extra Python packages to be installed, so i was asked did i want to install them&amp;hellip; Say, yes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, to run a backup we run the following command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;duplicity ~/ cf+hubic://location&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cf+hubic is the backend to use, ~/ is the url to backup (my home directory in this case) and location is where on Hubic we want it stored. If this doesent exist, not a problem&amp;hellip; it will create it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after we run this we&amp;hellip; ahhh&amp;hellip; i get an error:
&lt;pre&gt;BackendException: This backend requires the pyrax library available from Rackspace.&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;right&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rackspace/pyrax&#34;&gt;pyrax library&lt;/a&gt; is from Rackspace and is available to download though pip&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I seem to have python and a few other bits installed on this machine, so running &amp;lsquo;sudo pip install pyrax&amp;rsquo; works&amp;hellip; Your millage may vary&amp;hellip; [eg, this is out of scope for this tutorial! your on your own!]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other problem&amp;hellip; I got a load of weird and wondering errors like this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;AttributeError: &#39;Module_six_moves_urllib_parse&#39; object has no attribute &#39;SplitResult&#39;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fixed these by running:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt; sudo pip install furl --upgrade&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FINALLY! ITS ALIVE!!! by default, it asks you for a key for the GnuPG encryption&amp;hellip; and its all good! the first backup creates the directories, required files, etc. the next time you run the command, it will only upload changes. it will also ask for your GnuPG code you entered, so remember it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thats all folks! Any questions, leave them in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubic, OpenStack Swift and Curl</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/hubic_swift_curl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 22:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/hubic_swift_curl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hubic.com/home/new/?referral=GMSQVQ&#34;&gt;HubiC&lt;/a&gt; is an online storage site, built by the guys at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.com&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt;. They are currently offering 30Gb free (if you use the link above) or if you pay, you get 110Gb (insted of the usual 100Gb) for EUR1 a month, or 10.5TB (yup&amp;hellip; TERABYTES!) for EUR5 a month&amp;hellip; Thats a crazy amount of storage for a not crazy amount of money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while playing around with different things, I found they have an &lt;a href=&#34;https://api.hubic.com/&#34;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;, so other than the usual apps to play with (like the Hubic Apps for iPhone, Android, Windows Phone, Windows Desktop and OSX, &lt;a href=&#34;http://duplicity.nongnu.org/&#34;&gt;Duplicity&lt;/a&gt; for backing up *nix boxes, and a few others) you can build your own&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, i needed to figure out how&amp;hellip; So, after a lot of arsing around in Linux shells with &lt;a href=&#34;http://curl.haxx.se/&#34;&gt;curl&lt;/a&gt; i finally got some stuff working!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, i used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://api.hubic.com/sandbox/&#34;&gt;Hubic sandbox&lt;/a&gt; to get the keys&amp;hellip; its quite simple to walk though&amp;hellip; this gets you your Access Token (see step 3). next, we need to get the Endpoint from Hubic: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/9c061ae8d1312190f152#file-gistfile1-txt&#34;&gt;This GIST shows more&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/9c061ae8d1312190f152.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick walkthough:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the first CURL request is to the HubiC API to get the credentials&amp;hellip; this gives you a JSON response with a token and a endpoint URL aswell with an expire time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next request gets you a list of all files (or at least a load of files in my case) of whats in your folder. the &lt;pre&gt;default&lt;/pre&gt; name here is my folder&amp;hellip; I think its what everyone starts out with in HubiC&amp;hellip; if you remove it, you will see all your top level folders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next request i tried was to upload a file&amp;hellip; the &lt;pre&gt;filename&lt;/pre&gt; part is where you want it to be stored. this must exist on your local machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;finally, downloading of a file&amp;hellip; pass in the location of the file on the server (listing files will give you the location) and then &lt;pre&gt;-o&lt;/pre&gt; in curl shows the output location&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simples! now to get this working in c#&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.openstack.org/api-ref-objectstorage-v1.html&#34;&gt;Full OpenStack Swift API is available&lt;/a&gt; to show how to do more&amp;hellip; hopefully it will help in my C# coding&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Carry, March 2015 Edition</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/daily_carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 21:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/daily_carry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of years back, i did a post about my &lt;a href=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/2013/01/27/college_bag_contents.html&#34;&gt;Daily Carry for college&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; Well, I have finished (ish) college, but i still cary a lot of weird and wonderful stuff&amp;hellip; So, this is the update&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The details are on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/DailyCarry/&#34;&gt;Daily Carry page&lt;/a&gt;, and, in theory, should always be up to date&amp;hellip; Thats the theory anyway&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Phone as a Service</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mobile_phone_as_a_service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mobile_phone_as_a_service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2013/05/29/RaspberryPi_Astrisk_Box.html&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about the Raspberry Pi acting as a VoIP server, and being able to add a 3G Dongle and allowing it to act as a Mobile Phone gateway, it got me thinking&amp;hellip; Why not have something that allows you to rent a mobile phone number in a country, send and recieve text messages, phone calls, etc, all from anywhere in the world? Thats where &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mpaas.co&#34;&gt;Mobile Phone as a Service&lt;/a&gt; comes in&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theory behing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mpaas.co&#34;&gt;MPaaS&lt;/a&gt; is quite simple: A SIM Card for a mobile phone is placed in a USB Dongle, plugged into a VoIP server (Asterisk box, probably a Raspberry Pi) and shared with the user who requests it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its only a theory at the moment&amp;hellip; Any interest?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDN Hosted Blog</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/cdnhostedblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/cdnhostedblog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, if you can read this, this site is now hosted fully on &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt; with both &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/s3&#34;&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront&#34;&gt;CloudFront&lt;/a&gt;. More details eventually&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[UPDATE] How did i host this on S3 and CloudFront? Check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulstamatiou.com/hosting-on-amazon-s3-with-cloudfront/&#34;&gt;this article by Paul Stamatiou&lt;/a&gt; for details&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi as an Asterisk Box</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberrypi_astrisk_box/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberrypi_astrisk_box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty amazing peice of kit for its price and size. And now, you can make it even more amazing by using it as a VoIP server for your house!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberry-asterisk.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Asterisk&lt;/a&gt; for downloads, documentation, etc, on how to setup a Raspberry Pi and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asterisk.org/&#34;&gt;Asterisk&lt;/a&gt;. I have a couple Pi&amp;rsquo;s in the house, and plan on setting this up in the next few days. Keep your eyes on the site&amp;hellip; more posts coming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as an added bonus: You can now use a 3G/HSDPA modem to make and recieve calls using Asterisk and your Pi! &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.carrier-connect.com/raspberry-gsm-gateway/&#34;&gt;Carrier Connect&lt;/a&gt; has details of how they setup a couple of Raspberry Pi devices in Germany and Cambodia and anyone ringing from Germany got redirected to Cambodia, with no noticable issue. Very cool stuff! Have to try this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Double Bonous: Chan-Dongle (the software that you use to make and recieve calls with GSM) also allows the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.e1550.mobi/doku.php?id=usage#receive_sms_and_ussd&#34;&gt;device to accept SMS messages&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College Bag Contents</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/college_bag_contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 22:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/college_bag_contents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, Monday the 28th January, 2013, will be the start of my final real Semester in College. I have been studying part time for the last 3 and a bit years, and tomorrow marks the begining of the end&amp;hellip; Its the final REAL semester, meaning at the end of this i will have exams, but i wont be &amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo; as such&amp;hellip; I have a final semester from September to December where i hand up my final year project, which i plan on documenting here soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, thats a long way of saying that today, i have been working on the contents of my college bag: What do i bring with me to college&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;well, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/lsmartman/8420806885/&#34; title=&#34;College bag contents by TiernanO, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8326/8420806885_9aa2c31674.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;College bag contents&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot in this photo, so you may want to click though to see the full size, but lets start, shall we:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptop: MacBook Pro, Late 2008, 8Gb RAM, 500GB Hybrid HDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phones: HTC Titan (Windows Phone 7.5, main phone), HTC One X (Android, backup phone), , HTC HD2 (Windows Phone 6.5/Android hack, test phone (VOIP Stuff)), iPhone 4 (iOS, Data Phone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB Keys: Multiple USB Keys ranging from small 4Gb sticks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005039I32/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B005039I32&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;fast 32Gb USB 3.0 Keys&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; total space: 140GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HotSpot: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003DNYW0U/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003DNYW0U&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;Zoom Travle Router with Wireless-N&lt;/a&gt; connected to the iPhone to give me a wireless access point for up to 254 devices&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0063W8XAS/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0063W8XAS&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;Veho Pebble&lt;/a&gt;. enough power to charge both the iPhone and HotSpot at the same time (hotspot powers iPhone while its on, and the Pebble powers the hotspot). May replace it with something more powerfull eventually&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mouse: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001C4ETU0/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B001C4ETU0&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;Microsoft Arc Mouse&lt;/a&gt;. Small, light, foldable and works perfect for what i need it for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory card Reader: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013TRZI2/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0013TRZI2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;Lexar Dual Slot USB 2.0 Memory Card Reader&lt;/a&gt;: this is very fast&amp;hellip; Has UDMA support for faster CF and SD cards&amp;hellip; Used mainly for reading memory cards from cameras, but given my project uses a Raspberry Pi, and i have 2 of these, one in my main bag is handy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera: I carry my a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008K29OHK/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B008K29OHK&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;Samsung Galaxy Camera&lt;/a&gt; with me at all times. This is my new years resolution and its something that i handy to have with me. Taking photos of notes, videos of lectures, etc, is handy&amp;hellip;. and given its a full Android device, i can send and read emails, tweets, facebook, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MISC: I have a small USB Hub pictured (no link, dont know where i got it). I also have all the required cables (iPhone, mini and micro usb, power, etc) and what ever else is needed to run the whole show&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hoping that if i manage to build the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2013/01/18/raspberry_pi_as_a_mobile_wifi_hotspot_-_part_1.html&#34;&gt;Ultimate Mobile HotSpot&lt;/a&gt; with a Raspberry Pi, I can get rid of a few things (mobile hotspot, battery charger, replace the iPhone with an iPod Touch) and maybe a lot of cables&amp;hellip; Ideally, the Ultimate Mobile Hotspot should have enough power to charge other devices, and be charged while running also&amp;hellip; but thats another post for another day&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi as a Mobile WiFi HotSpot (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_as_a_mobile_wifi_hotspot_-_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 07:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_as_a_mobile_wifi_hotspot_-_part_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using an iPhone 4 as a wifi hotspot for a while now. It does not have a &amp;ldquo;phone&amp;rdquo; SIM in it, with calls and texts enabled, instead it has a 3G Data SIM from a dongle&amp;hellip; It works OK, but there are a few issues i have with it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No easy way to see how much data is being used, unless you Jail Break, and then battery life goes away&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not very hackable&amp;hellip; other than Jail Break, and thats not hackable enough&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not a lot of storage: 16Gb, and most of that is takin up by Music and Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no background network daemons&amp;hellip; more on that in a second&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Network Daemons i am thinking would be useful for a WiFi Hotspot would be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt;, SSH, PPTP or OpenVPN Client and possibly a downloader of some sort. What i am thinking is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a device, that is small enough to fit in a bag, possibly small enough to fit in a jacket pocket. It will probably not be as small as the iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should have storage on board. Boot storage and cache storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 1, possibly more, WiFi Adapters, with optional antennas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 1, possibly more, 3G or 4G Modems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 1 ethernet port, again possibility for more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battery that can run the whole system for at least 4-5 hours, and should be able to run while being charged. charging via USB would be ideal also&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optional Screen, but more likley, some sort of web interface to show whats going on (Bandwdith usage, clients connected, connection details)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this turns on, it should automatically start the 3/4G connections (if there are multiple connections, it should do some balancing of the connections). if there are more then 1 WiFi Connection, one should be a Client (connect to an external WiFi connection, like home, college, work) and one should be an Access Point (Your Phone, Tablet and Laptop connect to this one). Ethernet can also be used in a simular way (if one only, it could be client or server, if multiple, one can be client, one can be server). DHCP addresses will be given out on Access Point or Server connections, and on Client connections, DHCP will be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squid would be installed and listen on its usual port. Optionally, all port 80 and 8080 traffic could be routed though Squid. Ideally, HTTPS traffic should be automatically routed, but i think thats a bit harder to setup&amp;hellip; If VPN Clients are enabled, it could also allow All or Some traffic to be routed over the VPN connections. SSH could also be used to compress traffic between multiple Squid boxes (one in house, one on the device). WANProxy could be used in a simular manner to save bandwdith and make the connection faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with all that, i am looking at using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; for the job. I am still working on this, but here is what i have so far&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have put a Wifi adapter into my Raspberry Pi (A Linksys, but forget the exact model number). Using a tutorial on &lt;a href=&#34;http://exain.wordpress.com/2011/03/31/making-a-wifi-hotspot-access-point-using-linux-wifi-lan-cardusb-adapter/&#34;&gt;Vivek&amp;rsquo;s blog on making a wifi hotspot on linux&lt;/a&gt; i managed to get the AP showing up on my laptop, but could not connect. I am not sure if its the adapter causing the problem, or what, but i am going to change out the adapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the moment, i am sharing the ethernet connection, not the 3G connection&amp;hellip; I have posted here before the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2012/07/3g-internet-on-raspberry-pi-success/&#34;&gt;link to Terence Eden&amp;rsquo;s post on getting the Raspberry Pi to connect to 3G&lt;/a&gt;. All that i will need to do is connect to 3g and then NAT the connection from Wifi to 3G&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there are a few more bits and pieces to get done over the next while&amp;hellip; I will keep posting here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving sites to NearlyFreeSpeech</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/moving_sites_to_nearlyfreespeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 19:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/moving_sites_to_nearlyfreespeech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been running a Dedicated Server from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, but have started to look at what i am running on the site, and reailized i under utilize the machine a lot&amp;hellip; For example, this site is generated using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/vsphere-hypervisor/overview.html&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, which takes up very little power, and becomes static HTML files. My other blogs (&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net&#34;&gt;Tiernan&amp;rsquo;s Comms Closet&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekphotographer.com&#34;&gt;GeekPhotographer&lt;/a&gt;) are both low traffic &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordpress.org&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; sites, and I run a couple of other static sites also for friends&amp;hellip; All in all, not a lot of power&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its not a fortune to run the server, the box i have has a Quad Core, Hyper threaded Intel i7, 32Gb RAM, 2 3TB Hdds (not raid&amp;hellip;) and runs a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&#34;&gt;VMWare ESXi&lt;/a&gt;, and it costs about EUR60 a month, including a couple of IP addresses&amp;hellip; But, i dont use it all that often&amp;hellip; So, i am in the process of getting rid of it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the 2 other blogs (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekphotographer.com&#34;&gt;GeekPhotographer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net&#34;&gt;Tiernan&amp;rsquo;s Comms Closet&lt;/a&gt;) have already moved. They where easy enough&amp;hellip; Export the Wordpress DB, copy the file up, tweak the config, import the DB, DNS updates, etc&amp;hellip; All done&amp;hellip; but this site&amp;hellip; that is more &amp;ldquo;Complicated&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it is generated on a &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/29/NewSite.html&#34;&gt;git push&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;, Jekyll and Ruby needs to be installed on the box&amp;hellip; I am using static sites on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nearlyfreespeech.net/&#34;&gt;NearlyFreeSpeech&lt;/a&gt; which only charge me per meg (about 0.1c, but that reduces as you transfer more) transfered and per 5 meg stored (1c). Thats for STATIC sites&amp;hellip; if you are running a dynamic site, its about 1c per 1mb stored, plus 1c per day, plus another 2c for MySQL instances. Check out their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nearlyfreespeech.net/estimate&#34;&gt;pricing calculator&lt;/a&gt; to see the magic at work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my GIT repo is on a machine in the house. It has Jekyll and all required bits installed. In the &amp;lsquo;post-receive&amp;rsquo; hook (check &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.zerosum.org/2010/11/01/pure-git-deploy-workflow.html&#34;&gt;the original zerosum post&lt;/a&gt;), i generate the site, and then do an rsync copy to NFSN servers. That is it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any question, leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[update] forgot to add the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/4545178&#34;&gt;gist&lt;/a&gt; which shows how i do the rsync call&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 4545178 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[update2] you in my case, the folder that Jekyll is being built in needed to be chmoded and chowned&amp;hellip; I chowned the the folder to the gitolite user and i chmodded the folder to 777&amp;hellip; before i did this, some files where unreadable on NFSN&amp;hellip; with this, all works grand&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Emails as a Distribution Group in Office365</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/send_emails_as_a_distribution_group_in_office365/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 13:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/send_emails_as_a_distribution_group_in_office365/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am in the process of moving my Email domains from one &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.office365.com&#34;&gt;Office365&lt;/a&gt; plan (a Professional) to an Enterprise Plan. During the move, i set up some Email Aliases for older email addresses, which are still being used, but i dont send a lot of email from. But if i do need to send emails from these addresses, with the help of Powershell, I managed to set it up. The full details are listed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cogmotive.com/blog/office-365-tips/send-as-an-alias-in-microsoft-office-365&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;how to send as an alias in Office 365&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. It works perfectly! And, as a bit of shamless self promotion, if you are interested in Office365, why not drop me a mail at Tiernan at LimitedSlipNetworks dot com and i can set you up with a trial and more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Firewall rules for MikroTik RouterOS</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_firewall_rules_for_mikrotik_routeros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 11:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_firewall_rules_for_mikrotik_routeros/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/12/19/ipv6_%2B_mikrotik_%2B_linux_%2B_windows.html&#34;&gt;yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post on IPv6 Networking in the house&lt;/a&gt;, I realized that all machines internally had publically facing IPv6 addresses! I started to panic, then went looking online, and found the following script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/4344701.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This script, when run on your RouterOS board, will allow Established and Related connections, allow outgoing connections, and drop anything incoming that has not been requested&amp;hellip; so, now everything inside the network should be more secured&amp;hellip; I am new to this IPv6 stuff, so I am still learning&amp;hellip; but, i am getting there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 &#43; MikroTik &#43; Linux &#43; Windows</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_%2b_mikrotik_%2b_linux_%2b_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 16:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_%2b_mikrotik_%2b_linux_%2b_windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to setup an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ipv6&#34;&gt;IPv6&lt;/a&gt; network for a while now, but never had the hardware or network to support it. My broadband Modem, a Cisco EPC3925, was pretty useless&amp;hellip; But with the advent of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/02/Enabling-true-briding-mode-on-Cisco-EPC3925.html&#34;&gt;Bridging on the Cisco EPC3925&lt;/a&gt; it now works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing i needed to do was setup a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tunnelbroker.net/&#34;&gt;Tunnel Broker Account&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.he.net&#34;&gt;Hurricane Electric&lt;/a&gt;. I got a /64 block of IPv6 addresses, which should do me for a while&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I followed the config example from the MikroTik Wiki Page: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:My_First_IPv6_Network&#34;&gt;My First IPv6 Network&lt;/a&gt;. In my case, i only ran though most of router 1&amp;rsquo;s config, and did not create the &amp;ldquo;routing between segments&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ospv-v3&amp;rdquo; backbone&amp;hellip; I did give my internal LAN port an IPv6 address, as well as an IPv4 address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, on my Windows Server machine, i gave it a static IPv6 address (since i dont have an IPv6 DHCP setup&amp;hellip; yet&amp;hellip;) and told it to use the IPv6 address i gave the RouteBoard as its gateway. Then i told it to use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendns.com&#34;&gt;OpenDNS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendns.com/ipv6&#34;&gt;public IPv6&lt;/a&gt; address. I then visited &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipv6-test.com&#34;&gt;IPv6 Test&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ipv6.google.com&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s IPv6 page&lt;/a&gt; to confirm connectivity&amp;hellip; SUCCESS!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my Linux box, I followed &lt;a href=&#34;http://knowledgelayer.softlayer.com/questions/468/Adding+IPv6+to+Ubuntu+systems&#34;&gt;Soflayer&amp;rsquo;s Adding an IPv6 IP&lt;/a&gt; tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compressing and UnCompressing Protobuf items in C#</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/compressing_and_uncompressing_protobuf_items_in_c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 11:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/compressing_and_uncompressing_protobuf_items_in_c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of a project i am working on required sending large amounts of data between different instances. To get this to work efficially, we started using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/protobuf/&#34;&gt;ProtoBuf&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/protobuf-net/&#34;&gt;ProtoBuf-net&lt;/a&gt; in .NET. but the files where still quite large (17mb, give or take). So, we looked into compression&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here is some examples of how we managed to compress the protobuf files. We got some decient compression: 3mb files, down from 17mb. very happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to compress an object (obj) and write to a temp file (tmpfile):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/4267147.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to decompress the object back to a known type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/4267157.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIT tips and tricks</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/git_tips_and_tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 15:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/git_tips_and_tricks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;GIT&lt;/a&gt; a lot for different things, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/29/NewSite.html&#34;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;. so, here are a few tips and tricks i have found useful over the while&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/using-dropbox-as-a-personal-git-and-mercurial-storage-area/?utm_source=tiernanotoole&amp;amp;utm_medium=web&amp;amp;utm_campaign=gittipsandtricks&#34;&gt;Using Dropbox as a local GIT/Mercurial Repository&lt;/a&gt;: my own post from a while back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://durdn.com/blog/2012/12/05/git-12-curated-git-tips-and-workflows/&#34;&gt;Twelve GIT curated Tips and Workflows from the Trenches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://durdn.com/blog/2011/07/06/using-git-with-subversion-tips-that-will-make-your-life-easier/&#34;&gt;Using GIT with Subversion: tips that will make your life easier&lt;/a&gt;: The office has an SVN server, but i like GIT. This doc, with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kernel.org/pub/software/scm/git/docs/git-svn.html&#34;&gt;git-svn&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4883453/seamless-git-svn-setup&#34;&gt;this post on StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt; allows me to use GIT locally, and then push to SVN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://andyjeffries.co.uk/articles/25-tips-for-intermediate-git-users&#34;&gt;25 tips for intermediate git users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gitready.com/&#34;&gt;git ready: learn git one commit at a time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mislav.uniqpath.com/2010/07/git-tips/&#34;&gt;A few git tips you dont already know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1430218339/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1430218339&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;The ProGIT book (paperback amazon)&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004TTXLGI/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B004TTXLGI&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;Kindle Edition&lt;/a&gt;. Also available &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/book&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symform - P2P Backup</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/symform_-_p2p_backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 09:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/symform_-_p2p_backup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have previously &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/30/CrashPlan-Backups.html&#34;&gt;posted about CrashPlan&lt;/a&gt; as my Backup System. I also, a long time ago, talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/new-backup-plan-out-with-jungle-disk-and-zmanda-cloud-backup-in-with-crashplan-mysqlbf-and-sqlbf/&#34;&gt;Backing up SQL, MySQL and other stuff&lt;/a&gt; on my other blog. Well, CrashPlan is all good, but there are 2 &amp;ldquo;niggly&amp;rdquo; bits with it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its not FREE (well, this year i got it Free on Black Friday&amp;hellip;) but it is cheap ($120 a year to backup 10 machines to the cloud aint bad.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its NOT FAST! The CrashPlan Datacenters all live in the US, and my servers live in Europe (either Dublin or Germany). So, bandwidth is limited&amp;hellip; Getting less than 1Mbit/s most times, but have seen it reach 3&amp;hellip; I have 20Mbits/s upload&amp;hellip; even half that would be nice&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thats where &lt;a href=&#34;https://control.symform.com/Organization/Referral?referralId=96E53D9DC4501633F2294EF202734DB08C00F044&#34;&gt;Symform&lt;/a&gt; comes in. Symform is a P2P Backup Service, which runs on Windows, Linux and MacOSX. In theory, it should run anywhere that has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page&#34;&gt;Mono&lt;/a&gt; runtime since its written in .NET. Anyway, you start with 10Gb of free storage, and you can increese that by one of 2 ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay money: for $0.15 per month, you get 1Gb of storage in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay Bytes: For every 2Gb &amp;ldquo;Contributed&amp;rdquo; (which is actually more like a pledge than a contribution&amp;hellip; more on that later) you get 1Gb storage in the cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works very well, and is nice a fast too. I have a few machines in house which are contribting stoage, a total of about 2Tb, and I have been given 1Tb storage in &amp;ldquo;The Cloud&amp;rdquo;. There is a lot more on how this works on their &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symform.com/join-the-revolution/how-symform-works/&#34;&gt;How Symform Works&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; section of their site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned the &amp;ldquo;Contribution&amp;rdquo; VS &amp;ldquo;Pledge&amp;rdquo; up above&amp;hellip; I have a machine in the house where i have Pledged 1Tb of storage. In reality, Symform can use the full 1Tb of storage, if it needs to, but is currently only using 168Gb. Now, that could just be that the machine is still getting files, and it will end up using the full 1Tb eventually, but either way, its all good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as a couple of notes on Contribution and Backups:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The machine needs to be online and accessable on the internet at least 80% of the time, but &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; is ideal. If you drop below the 80%, your account can be suspended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your machine needs to be publically accessable, meaning port forwarded. I have a couple contribution machines in house, so they each have seperate ports forwarded to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given the P2P nature of the software, lots of connections to different machines are made&amp;hellip; if you are behind a firewall, you may need to allow all or most outgoing connections. If you are on a really restrictive firewall, you may want to stick a contribution box in your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DMZ_(computing)&#34;&gt;DMZ&lt;/a&gt; and probably use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symform.com/our-solutions/key-features/turbo-seeding/&#34;&gt;Turbo Seeding&lt;/a&gt; feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turbo Seeding is a handy feature, especially for Laptops&amp;hellip; only problem is its Windows Only&amp;hellip; So, importing and exporting does not work on Linux or OSX.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The software can managed Work and Non Work hours, and will limit the upload and download speed during this time. Also a nice feature&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good. Very happy with the software, but would like a nicer interface to see whats going on. At the moment, you are either limited to using the web interface, which aint bad, but not great, or watching the log files&amp;hellip; I would also like the ability to prioritize certain files or folders, so, for example, upload my documents folder before anything else, and if anything changes in there, even if its uploading from somewhere else, pause and upload the documents folder&amp;hellip; Just a thought&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>enabling VNC from SSH on OSX</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/enabling_vnc_from_ssh_on_osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 16:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/enabling_vnc_from_ssh_on_osx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/Computers/MacBookPro.html&#34;&gt;Late 2008 MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; in the house, and SSH is enabled on it. I usually leave it on when in work. Anyway, SSH is enabled, but VNC access is not&amp;hellip; I found the following command on &lt;a href=&#34;http://technotes.twosmallcoins.com/?p=279&#34;&gt;Ryan&amp;rsquo;s Tech Notes&lt;/a&gt; allowing you to enable it though SSH:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 4170122 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** NOTE ** Change &lt;em&gt;mypasswd&lt;/em&gt; to your own password!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to disable it, use the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 4170129 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, of note, I am using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.realvnc.com/&#34;&gt;RealVNC client for Windows&lt;/a&gt; to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moving your TMG SQL server Logs DB and other TMG tips</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/moving_your_tmg_sql_server_and_other_tmg_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 08:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/moving_your_tmg_sql_server_and_other_tmg_tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In house, I have been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/tmg&#34;&gt;Microsoft TMG 2010 Server&lt;/a&gt; for a while now. I use it as a firewall for some of the machines on the network, and also as a proxy for most, if not all, machines. When acting as a Firewall, all traffic flows though the machine, be it HTTP/HTTPS, SMTP/POP3/IMAP, or anything for that matter. You can also lock down ports on the box, which is a feature of most firewalls, but i like TMG due to its relitive ease of use&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, one problem with routing all traffic from different machines though TMG is after a while, the logging starts getting big. Single TMG by default is set to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/sql&#34;&gt;SQL Server&lt;/a&gt;, it can start using lots of memory, hard drive space, etc. So, there are a couple of articles which should make moving your TMG&amp;rsquo;s SQL DB to a different machine easier&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb794937.aspx&#34;&gt;Configuring Forefront TMG Logs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dd441079.aspx&#34;&gt;Configuring (TMG) logging to a remote server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.isaserver.org/tutorials/How-configure-Forefront-TMG-logging-into-central-Microsoft-SQL-Server-database.html&#34;&gt;How to configure Forefront TMG logging into a central Microsoft SQL Server database&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other tips you may find useful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have Malware Inspection turned on, but you know there are certain sites that wont serve Malware (for example, Ubutnu Archives or YouTube.com) you can add these to the &amp;ldquo;Destination Exceptions&amp;rdquo; list. Under &amp;ldquo;Web Access Policy&amp;rdquo;, click &amp;ldquo;Malware Inspection&amp;rdquo; and click &amp;ldquo;Destination Exceptions&amp;rdquo;. Double click on the &amp;ldquo;Sites Exempt from Malware Inspection&amp;rdquo; and add your URL. I put *.ubuntu.com and *.youtube.com in here (Microsoft Updates are already on the list). Now, when downloading files from these locations, they do not run though inspection and save CPU cycles. &lt;strong&gt;WANRING&lt;/strong&gt; You need to trust these sites!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a nice little app to add into TMG called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bsplitter.com/&#34;&gt;Bandwidth Splitter&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to not only monitor what traffic is going though your network, but also put limits on different machine sets, users, etc. There is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bsplitter.com/download.aspx#trial_restrictions&#34;&gt;Free editon&lt;/a&gt; which works with only 10 clients, but does what i need it to do to start with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RouterOS Dynamic IP Updates</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_dynamic_ip_updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 10:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_dynamic_ip_updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mikrotik.com&#34;&gt;MikroTik&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB750G&#34;&gt;RouterBoard RB750&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, and i love it! Over the weekend, i upgraded it to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB1100&#34;&gt;RB1100&lt;/a&gt;. Its the same software running the device, but the device is faster (800Mhz PowerPC chip VS MIPS-BE at 680Mhz), has more memory (512Mb upgradable to 1.5Gb vs 32Mb) and more storage (think its 512Mb on board, plus 4Gb MicroSD card vs 32mb&amp;hellip;). It also has more ports (13 GigE VS 5) and 2 Switch Groups, which i have no idea what they do just yet&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, part of getting the RB1100 online and taking over from my existing router was getting Dynamic DNS updating. I use both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dyndns.org&#34;&gt;Dyndns&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://no-ip.com&#34;&gt;NoIP&lt;/a&gt; for DNS, but I also like the look of &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;Amazon Route 53&lt;/a&gt;. For updating NoIP, I am using the Alternitive script from &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Dynamic_DNS_Update_Script_for_No-IP_DNS&#34;&gt;The Mikrotik Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. To get this to work with DynDNS, it would just be a matter of chaning the URL you point to&amp;hellip; I am going to write a web script which will sit internally on the network, use that instead of the No-IP url. When that script gets called, i can log the info, update DynDNS, NoIP and Router53 all in one go. I will be posting more about that soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we are on the topic of Scripting RouterOS, checkout the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Scripts&#34;&gt;Mikrotik Script Example Page&lt;/a&gt;. Lots of good stuff up there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom MSDeploy OverWrite Rules</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/custom_msdeploy_overwrite_rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 09:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/custom_msdeploy_overwrite_rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a project which we are trying to automate the deployment system. The plan is to automatically deploy the project to a staging server anytime the build succeeds from SVN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had a few problems with this, but here are some of the links which may come in handy for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/12576662/msdeploy-skip-rules-when-using-msbuild-publishprofile-with-visual-studio-2012&#34;&gt;MSDeploy skip rules when using MSBuild PublishProfile with Visual Studio 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.alanta.nl/2011/02/web-deploy-customizing-deployment.html&#34;&gt;Web Deploy : Customizing a deployment package&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7100751/how-to-set-msdeploy-settings-in-csproj-file&#34;&gt;How to set MSDeploy settings in .csproj file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.iis.net/p/1170702/1953807.aspx#1953807&#34;&gt;MSBuild target VSMSdeploy doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to support skip with a skipAction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still some tweaks to get this to work&amp;hellip; If i find any more links i will put them here&amp;hellip; The problem we are haivng is when a deploy happens, the WebDeployment tool cannot overwrite the log files directory, since they are in use&amp;hellip; one option would be to restart IIS, which would be ok in staging, but we want to keep the logs in test and production, so, we need to figure out how to tell Web Deploy not to over write the files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WANProxy and Squid with Upstream Servers</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/wanproxy_and_squid_with_upstream_servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 13:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/wanproxy_and_squid_with_upstream_servers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/24/building_wanproxy_on_ubuntu_12.04.html&#34;&gt;previous post on WANProxy&lt;/a&gt;, i did not really go into detail about what it actually was. The direct quote from their site is &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wanproxy.org&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt; is a free, portable TCP proxy which makes TCP connections send less data, which improves TCP performance and throughput over lossy links, slow links and long links. This is just what you need to improve performance over satellite, wireless and WAN links.&lt;/em&gt; This is something that has interested me for a while, so i have been looking into it, and so far so good&amp;hellip; In my last post i mentioned i was proxying &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; traffic, in todays post, i still am, but with some tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i have a Squid box running in the house. It is connected to 2 Cable Modems, giving me 250Mbits/s down and 20Mbits/s upload connection. It is caching data locally also.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on my laptop i have Squid running also. It connects to a WANProxy server at home and proxies the Squid server. The local squid box is using the home Squid box as an upstream connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for upstream connections i used the following lines in the squid.conf:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 3958472 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have set it to never use a direct connection, which is probably silly, since if i loose the WANProxy connection, i loose connectivity&amp;hellip; Also, port 3300 is the WANProxy port its listening on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good&amp;hellip; I am also thinking this could be an interesting thing to get working on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;. Just a though&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building WANProxy on Ubuntu 12.04</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/building_wanproxy_on_ubuntu_12.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 14:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/building_wanproxy_on_ubuntu_12.04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Updated 2016/04/09] I had to use this today to build on Debian 8.3 for 2 different boxes. So, making minor changes (url to git proxy, and where you build from) to make sure this works now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been looking into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wanproxy.org&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, but never successfully got it to build&amp;hellip; I have been more successfull reciently, so here is what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** NOTE **: I built this on Ubuntu 12.04, so these are the tips for that&amp;hellip; Not sure about other Distros&amp;hellip;
** Second NOTE ** : I am using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/diegows/wanproxy&#34;&gt;Digows GitHub Repo&lt;/a&gt; for downloads&amp;hellip; There is also the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/svn/trunk&#34;&gt;WANProxy SVN Server&lt;/a&gt; and their official &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/get.shtml&#34;&gt;downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install build-essential git-core libssl-dev uuid-dev

git clone https://github.com/wanproxy/wanproxy.git

cd wanproxy/programs/wanproxy

make
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note -: git-core is needed to checkout code, build-essentails gives you your essential build utils, and the -dev files are needed for the build
*- NOTE -: I have tried it on a couple VMs and they take about  5 min to build&amp;hellip; If you are building on Physical hardware, it may be faster. Also, as a general note, if you are building with multiple processors, try add the -jX option, where x is your CPU count +1. for example, make -j5 if you have CPUs or Cores. or make -j17 if you have 16 cores&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cp wanproxy ~/local/bin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~Now, this is, so far, as far as i have gotten&amp;hellip; but given its building, and its further than I was a few weeks back, i though i would post incase i can help someone else&amp;hellip; ~~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** UPDATE ** I have successfully managed to get a WANProxy working. The way i have it setup is as follows:
** UPDATE 2016 ** as part of my series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Projects/&#34;&gt;getting double internet speed&lt;/a&gt;, I am back looking at WANProxy&amp;hellip; more on that later..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux box in house, and VM on laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;both have WANProxy installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use the ** Proxying over SSH ** example &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/examples.shtml&#34;&gt;from the WANProxy examples site&lt;/a&gt; which shows you how to proxy a single web server over SSH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in my case, i pointed the port at my proxy server inhouse. I also changed the if0.host address from 127.0.0.1 (only accessable from that machine) to its internal IP address (can be seen by anyone on that network)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally, I told my browser to use the WANProxy ip and port 3300 (see the if0 config section) as its proxy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Works grand so far. no idea yet if its &amp;ldquo;faster&amp;rdquo; but its working, which is a start&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boot Raspberry Pi with SSH Enabled, Enable Wifi on Boot, and more</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/boot_raspberry_pi_with_ssh_enabled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 16:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/boot_raspberry_pi_with_ssh_enabled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some interesting links for the Raspberry Pi today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, you just bought a new Raspberry Pi and need to enable SSH, but dont have a screen? &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/38/prepare-for-ssh-without-a-screen&#34;&gt;Prepare for SSH without a Screen&lt;/a&gt; shows you what to do!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/3200/wifi-bring-wlan0-up-on-boot&#34;&gt;How to Bring up WLAN0 on boot&lt;/a&gt; shows you how to start your Wifi adapter when you boot your Pi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPS and Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/gps_and_raspberry_pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 16:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/gps_and_raspberry_pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Need to add GPS to your Raspberry Pi? &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/547/how-do-i-attach-a-gps-receiver&#34;&gt;How do i attach a GPS to a Raspberry&lt;/a&gt; answers your question!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi now with 512MB RAM, other random links...</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_now_with_512mb_ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 12:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_now_with_512mb_ram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier on today, the Raspberry Pi Foundation announced that the Model B will now be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/archives/2180&#34;&gt;shipping with 512Mb RAM as standard&lt;/a&gt;, with no price change. I posted the link up on &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4654251&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and its caused quite a lot of happy people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with the news of extra RAM, its started making me think of more things the Pi could be used for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Austrian hosting company &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edis.at/en/server/colocation/austria/raspberrypi/&#34;&gt;are offering free Co-Location for Raspberry Pis&lt;/a&gt; with a 100Mb/s uplink and 100Gb bandwidth! FREE! with 512Mb RAM (or even 256Mb RAM) thats enough for a small site. or even a medium site (like this one) running statically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2012/07/3g-internet-on-raspberry-pi-success/&#34;&gt;Pi can connect to the internet using 3G&lt;/a&gt;, you could install a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org/&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; and use an SSH tunnel back to your main office or home, have have multiple levels of caching going on&amp;hellip; It would also secure your browsing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2012/06/raspberry-pi-python-and-3g-dongles-oh-my/&#34;&gt;Sending SMS messages though the Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; could be useful for sending diagnostic info if the device is remote&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[XBMC on the Raspberry Pi] would make your media center a lot smaller, use less power, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;just a note on the idea of using 3G and Squid for the Pi&amp;hellip; This is something i am interested in, so its something i want to start playing with. The idea would be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have a linux box in house with Squid and SSH enabled, and port forward SSH to the linux box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tell the pi, on boot, to try and connect to a 3G connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once connection is live, connect to SSH tunnel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squid should already be configued to load and use the upstream Squid box as an upstream cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;local squid should use some storage on either USB or SD for local cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, using something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt; on both ends should make things faster also&amp;hellip; Having the Pi, a 3G modem, USB key (optional) and a battery pack, all in a small box, with a Wifi Adapter, should give you a faster mobile internet connection&amp;hellip; And if you could get 2 or more 3G modems (using a Powered USB Hub of some sort), you could do load balancing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more raspberry pi and camera antics</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more_raspberry_pi_and_camera_antics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 15:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more_raspberry_pi_and_camera_antics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/09/06/Rasberry-Stuff.html&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, and in the post was a link to a Photographer who was &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidhunt.ie/?p=2641&#34;&gt;embeding a Raspberry Pi into a Canon 5D MKII battery grip&lt;/a&gt;. Well, its been a while, and i have been thinking about the Pi and Cameras, so I went looking around&amp;hellip; Here is what i found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://islandinthenet.com/2012/08/23/hdr-photography-with-raspberry-pi-and-gphoto2/&#34;&gt;HDR Photography with a Raspberry Pi and GPhoto2&lt;/a&gt;: It was linked at the end of David&amp;rsquo;s post, and i missed it completely. David mentions he was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gphoto.org/proj/gphoto2/&#34;&gt;GPhoto2&lt;/a&gt; to take photos from the Pi, so its a good place to start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://skowron.biz/artikel/gphoto-raspberry/&#34;&gt;GPhoto2 and the Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;: starters guide on getting the Pi to talk to your Camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not specifically Pi+Camera released, but the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/&#34;&gt;Stackoverflow Raspberry Pi Page&lt;/a&gt; is a handy resource for asking questions&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing i have not been able to figure out is how to tell the Pi to take the photos out of the camera &lt;strong&gt;wihtout having a monitor plugged in&lt;/strong&gt;. I was thinking either tell it, on boot, to start monitoring the camera and download everything. This way, if you have it plugged into a external power source, it will be monitoring and downloading to somewhere&amp;hellip; USB HDD, USB Key, etc. If there is a Wifi spot around, try uploading them to a location, posibily manageable via web interface of some sort&amp;hellip; Lots of interesting ideas can be done&amp;hellip; its just a matter of doing them&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RouterOS Using Host names in Firewall Rules</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_using_host_names_in_firewall_rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 07:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_using_host_names_in_firewall_rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow up to yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/11/routeros_blocking_machine_access.html&#34;&gt;RouterOS Blocking Machine access to all but one IP&lt;/a&gt; I tought i would show how to add extra IPs to that list, without having a shedload of firewall filters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First things first, get your list of IPs you allow access to. In my case, i just did an NSLOOKUP on the name and got the IPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an &amp;ldquo;Address List&amp;rdquo; in RouterOS. This can be done on the Web Interface by going to IP / Firewall / Address List and clicking Add. I had none previously, so i created a new rule, naming it &lt;a href=&#34;www.expressvpn.com/?referrer_email=tiernan@tiernanotoole.ie/&#34;&gt;ExpressVPN&lt;/a&gt; (the lads i use for VPN access) and added the first address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this is where things get interesting. for extra IP (for ExpressVPN, i have 4) you create a new address with the SAME name, but different IP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in your firewall rule, you should have either a src address or dst address. in my case, i had both, but this was a change for the dst address. I removed the address from the rule, i added it as a dst address list entry. If you have multiple address lists, you will see them here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to do this at the command prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 3877692 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this will block any traffic, other than the IPs in the expressVPN address list, for the machine 192.168.0.123.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RouterOS Blocking Machine access to all but one IP</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_blocking_machine_access/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 13:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_blocking_machine_access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, i have a machine on my network, which should be only connecting to the internet though a VPN. I needed to tell my RouterOS box to block all access, except to this said IP address&amp;hellip; The following &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do the trick&amp;hellip; YMMV&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 3871919 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this will drop any packets from the srcaddress (IP address) that are not for destination dstaddress (IP address). in my case, dstaddress is the VPN server i want to connect to. So, in theory, all packets should just go though the VPN and not leak out in to the rest of the network&amp;hellip; again, still testing this so be careful!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFS iSCSI NFS SFTP Hyper-V and more</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zfs_iscsi_nfs_sftp_hyper-v_and_more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 09:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zfs_iscsi_nfs_sftp_hyper-v_and_more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my new task to make my files safer and backups faster, and, well, cheap, I am looking into &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ZFS&#34;&gt;ZFS&lt;/a&gt; for my storage needs. My needs are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow me to store lots of different types of data (Photos, Videos, Music, VMs) in different formats (RAW and JPG photos, MP4, AVI and DivX Videos, with DVD and BluRay rips also a posibility, MP3 music and VHD files from HyperV, inclduing ISOs and Snapshots). I also need to store different file systems using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISCSI&#34;&gt;iSCSI&lt;/a&gt; (Mac and Windows clients will be mounting the storage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;must be safe. DO NOT LOSE DATA!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;must be somewhat fast. I have VHDs weighing in at 100Gb&amp;hellip; my photo collection is 600Gb. If i need to move or copy files to the storage system, it must be fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, ZFS offers all these features. I can export a file share as iSCSI, NFS, SMB, etc. All works well. But the replication stuff is the interesting part&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan, which i am working on, is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have 2 machines setup: one in house and one in a datacenter (I have a dedicated box in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; data center). both could be VMs (the one in the datacenter will more than likley be a VM).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use the storage on the local system for whatever i need backed up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have a script which will take a snapshot of a given pool every 4 hours or so&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that script should also dump the snapshot to a temporary location on the machine using ZFS send.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that file should be checked, compressed, broken up into little bits and checked again&amp;hellip; checking is important!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take those little bits and send them to the datacenter, which will do lots more checking and import the files into the ZFS pool over there&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there may even be a two way system to send from the datacenter back to the house&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally, the remote pool should be dumped to an SFTP backup system that Hetzner give me&amp;hellip; Currently set at 100Gb, but can be increesed as needed&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats the &amp;ldquo;plan&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; Lets see how it actually works out&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, parts of the process i need to tweak:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uploading and using as much of my upload bandwidth as possible (2x10mb upload connections&amp;hellip;) if i am backing up 800Gb, which should be my first backup, i would like to use both pipes to the fullest&amp;hellip; on a single connection, at 50% capacity, it would take 15.1 days to upload. if i can get both connections to work at 80% capacity, giving me 16Mbits/s, it would be down to 4.7 days. With compression and Deduplication, i can probably bring that down a bit more&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;backing up to SFTP&amp;hellip; Reading different things is telling me this might not be such a good idea&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some links which you might find useful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nexenta.com/corp/&#34;&gt;Nexenta&lt;/a&gt;: I am using their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nexentastor.org/projects/1/wiki/CommunityEdition&#34;&gt;Community Edition&lt;/a&gt; product for the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servethehome.com/create-nexentastor-vmware-esxi-virtual-machine/&#34;&gt;Create a Nexenta Store device in ESXi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servethehome.com/configure-passthrough-vmdirectpath-vmware-esxi-raid-hba-usb-drive/&#34;&gt;Configure passthough VMDirectPath in VMWare ESXi&lt;/a&gt;: ideally, you should let Nexenta manage your disks&amp;hellip; Dont think i can do it wiht the dedicated server, but might be possible with the server in house&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Jekyll Stuff</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more_jekyll_stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 20:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more_jekyll_stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Couple of bits and pieces on Jekyll stuff today&amp;hellip; I am tweaking the outline of the site, so i am surfing around finding stuff&amp;hellip; here is what i have found&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.layouts-the.me/2011/03/16/hosting-on-amazon-s3/&#34;&gt;Host a static site on Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt;: Interesting idea, and something i would look into eventually&amp;hellip; And with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront&#34;&gt;CloudFront&lt;/a&gt; you could host your whole blog on a CDN!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.layouts-the.me/rake/2011/04/23/rake_tasks_for_jekyll/&#34;&gt;Rake tasks for Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;: Rake is the Ruby version of make&amp;hellip; and a RakeFile can have tasks, which are in Ruby&amp;hellip; They can do, from what i can gather, pretty much anything&amp;hellip; So, some examples of what you can do with them are linked here&amp;hellip; I especially like the New Post generator&amp;hellip; very handy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://recursive-design.com/projects/jekyll-plugins/&#34;&gt;Jekyll Plugins&lt;/a&gt;: Various different plugins for Jekyll&amp;hellip; I am interested in a few of these, mainly the Generate_projects one, which generates a page for your projects based on your &lt;a href=&#34;http://vitobotta.com/how-to-migrate-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; projects&amp;hellip; very cool stuff&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strictly speaking, this is not just a Jekyll how to, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://vitobotta.com/how-to-migrate-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/&#34;&gt;Migrating from Wordpress to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a handy read. my &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net&#34;&gt;main blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://podcast.tiernanotoole.ie&#34;&gt;my podcast&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://geekphotographer.com&#34;&gt;photography blog&lt;/a&gt; both run WordPress. migrating them to Jekyll would mean i could move them directly to a CDN and make things a lot faster&amp;hellip; Maybe something i plan doing soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any tips or tricks, why not leave a comment and i can add them to the post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handbrake Cluster</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/handbrake-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/handbrake-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[UPDATED] someone asked in the comments if there was an binary build for this file. there is now! &lt;a href=&#34;http://handbrakecluster.codeplex.com&#34;&gt;http://handbrakecluster.codeplex.com&lt;/a&gt; now hosts the code and binaries, and will soon have help files and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days back, i wrote a post titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/09/28/Powershell-HandBrake-AppleTV-iTunes.html&#34;&gt;Powershell + Handbrake + AppleTV + iTunes = Automatic TV&amp;hellip; ish&lt;/a&gt;. In it i included a block of Powershell code to bulk convert TV shows from whatever format you had them in to a M4V format for the AppleTV. Well, as they say &amp;ldquo;If necessity is the mother of all invension, lazyness must be the father&amp;rdquo;. I have a lot of shows i wanted converted to the AppleTV, so i built something&amp;hellip; Its called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/HandbrakeCluster&#34;&gt;HandBrake Cluster&lt;/a&gt; and is written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=30653&#34;&gt;.NET 4.5&lt;/a&gt;, uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa967729.aspx&#34;&gt;MSMQ&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://handbrake.fr/&#34;&gt;Handbrake&lt;/a&gt; to do the processing&amp;hellip; The workflow is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setup the system as described on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/HandbrakeCluster&#34;&gt;HandBrake Cluster&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run the adder program with the paramaters required (location of files you want converted, type of files to find, where you want the files to be placed, output file type)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run the cluster EXE on as many machines as you want. each machine will need to point to the correct MSMQ on the head node, have their own copy of Handbrake, and must have access to the fileshare that you are reading and writing to&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each node will take a message of the queue, process the file and then mark it as completed. There is code to see if the message has failed, so, in theory, if something goes into the queue, it should always be processed&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have run this at home on a couple of different machines, and so far so good&amp;hellip; my room gets a bit warmer when i kick this off, and between the 3 machines i ran it on, my FPS count went from just 80-120 on the Godbox, to a total of about 160 - 240 FPS (Godbox = 80-120, Server 1 and 2 are about 40-60FPS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing i managed to do was tweak my import process for iTunes. I am using a program called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bizmodeller.com/iHomeServer_for_iTunes.aspx&#34;&gt;iHomeServer for iTunes&lt;/a&gt; which is running on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/godbox.html&#34;&gt;GodBox&lt;/a&gt;. It monitors a folder, which is where &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/HandbrakeCluster&#34;&gt;HandBrake Cluster&lt;/a&gt; is writing to, and adds them to iTunes. I can then tweak the metadata using the tool, so i can add art work, tell it which shows are related, and it sets up Art work, title info, etc. It is very handy, and something i am very happy with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling True Bridging modem on a Cisco ECP3925 Cable Modem (UPC Ireland)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/enabling-true-briding-mode-on-cisco-epc3925/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/enabling-true-briding-mode-on-cisco-epc3925/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.upc.ie/&#34;&gt;UPC Ireland&lt;/a&gt; customer, and have 2 cable modems into the house, both Cisco EPC3925s. These are not exactly great modems for power users, but are grand for normal use&amp;hellip; Me, however, being a poweruser wanted something a little more, how should I put it, powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months back, a tutorial was posted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boards.ie&#34;&gt;Boards.ie&lt;/a&gt; which showed you &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boards.ie/vbulletin/showthread.php?p=79448674&#34;&gt;How to enable &amp;ldquo;bridging&amp;rdquo; on your UPC modem&lt;/a&gt;. When i say &amp;ldquo;Bridging&amp;rdquo;, they used DMZ, turned off firewalls, static IPs internally, turned off Wifi and DHCP, etc. It worked, quite well actually, but was &amp;ldquo;odd&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; Today, however, there is a new tutorial &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boards.ie/vbulletin/showthread.php?t=2056758726&#34;&gt;Enabling REAL bridging on a Cisco EPC3925&lt;/a&gt;. I have tried this, and so far, it works! now just to set my router to work correctly, and update my IPs if they change&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell &#43; HandBrake &#43; AppleTV &#43; iTunes = Automatic TV... Ish...</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/powershell-handbrake-appletv-itunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/powershell-handbrake-appletv-itunes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/appletv&#34;&gt;AppleTV&lt;/a&gt; in the house (3, actually) and i am very happy with its ease of use, size and cost&amp;hellip; You cant really argue with the small price!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a lot of content that works great with the AppleTV in iTunes, but i have content which does not work so great with the AppleTV&amp;hellip; So, i needed to find a way to convert files quickly and easily&amp;hellip; thats where PowerShell and &lt;a href=&#34;http://handbrake.fr/&#34;&gt;Handbrake&lt;/a&gt; come in&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 3798509 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the code above, you need to set the path of where your files live. in my case they live on a NAS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;next, set the location of HandBrake&amp;hellip; i have a 64 bit copy of Windows, and a 64 bit copy of HandBrake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set the new file name to where you want the file to go. in my case i have it set to my &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://support.apple.com/kb/HT3832&#34;&gt;Automatically Add to iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; folder, which is a magic folder for iTunes that copies any files dropped in there to your iTunes library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally, conversion is run&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may take a few min, depending on a few factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how many files you are converting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how fast your machine in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how fast your machine can read and write the files&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have set files to convert on 3 different machines (the GodBox and 2 other servers) and i am getting speeds of anywhere between 250FPS (on the GodBox running 2 instances of HandBrake CLI) and 40 - 60 FPS on the older servers&amp;hellip; on the remote machines, they are sending files to the GodBox folder also, so once everything completes, its just a matter of opening iTunes and we are good to go&amp;hellip; Now to figure out how to automate the Metadata import&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crashplan Backups</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/crashplan-backups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 11:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/crashplan-backups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crashplan.com&#34;&gt;CrashPlan&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, and, other than some minor issues (backup speed to their central location is the big one), everything has been going grand. I use it to backup about 600GB of photos and videos, 500GB+ of VMs, documents, source code and a fair whack of other stuff&amp;hellip; In total, about 2TB of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here are some tips i have figured out over the last while for making Crashplan work a little better&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://support.crashplan.com/doku.php/recipe/speeding_up_your_backup&#34;&gt;Speeding up your backup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nerdwa.com/index.php/2011/05/crashplan-on-ubuntu-server/&#34;&gt;Installing CrashPlan on a headless (no monitor or GUI) Ubuntu Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uncorneredmarket.com/2012/02/crashplan-backup/&#34;&gt;How to get terabytes of data into the cloud using Crashplan Seed Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also in the process of doing some further tests with iSCSI drives linked to the Cloud, and other weird and wonderful things&amp;hellip; once I have finished, i will upload extra stuff here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More VoIP Stuff</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more-voip-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more-voip-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my ongoing plan to upgrade the house to VoIP, and as a follow up to my first &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/09/11/VOIP-Stuff.html&#34;&gt;VoIP stuff&lt;/a&gt; post, here are some more things i have found&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have added &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sipdiscount.com&#34;&gt;SipDiscount&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sipgate.co.uk&#34;&gt;SipGate&lt;/a&gt; for making and recieving calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SipDiscount allows me to set pretty much any number as my Caller ID, as long as i &amp;ldquo;own&amp;rdquo; that number (they either text or call you with a code, and you enter it on their site). They also allow me to make cheap calls to Irish Mobiles (check their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sipdiscount.com/rates&#34;&gt;rates here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SipGate gave me a incoming UK phone number. Its an 0845 number, which I dont know what that means&amp;hellip; but it was free, so its all good. Not sure if i can recieve text messages on it though&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blueface.ie&#34;&gt;Blueface&lt;/a&gt; account, which gives me an Irish 076 VoIP number. 076 is the standard VoIP number here in Ireland&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipkall.com/&#34;&gt;IpKall&lt;/a&gt; number, which is based in Washington State. You need to recieve a call on this line at least once every 30 days to keep it active.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://voice.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Voice&lt;/a&gt; accepts calls and forwards them to my IpKall number, which then rings my BlueFace SIP account (since i know they will be up all the time, by my home server may be offline since i am only testing) which, if a SIP device is connected, will forward it again&amp;hellip; if i am offline, or no sip devices are active, that call is redirected to voice mail&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its all very complicated at the moment, but the plan will be that any incoming calls should go directly to the machine in house, which will ring the desk phone and any other SIP clients. Any incoming PSTN calls will also do the same. Outgoing calls will depend on the dialing plan, which i still need to figure out, but the theory goes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Irish landline calls at certin times should go though the PSTN (since we get some free calls with our line). Other times they should go though SipDiscount or BlueFace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if the PSTN is busy, fall over to one of the other providers&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Irish Mobile calls should go though SipDiscount and then fall back to land line, or if i ever get the BlueTooth setup working, SipDiscount, then bluetooth, then landline&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International calls should be sent though SipDiscount or Blueface, whichever is cheaper&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its going to be an interesting setup&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cross Compiler for your Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry-pi-cross-compiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry-pi-cross-compiling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My main machine at home, known as &amp;ldquo;The GodBox&amp;rdquo; is a Dual Processor, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001QCEMFA/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B001QCEMFA&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;Quad Core Xeon 5520&lt;/a&gt; with 60Gb RAM, 2 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005CGDSDI/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B005CGDSDI&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;300Gb 10,000 RPM Western Digital Velociraptor&lt;/a&gt; in RAID 0 for boot, 4X1Tb 7200RPM drives for storage, 2 more 300Gb 10,000 RPM drives for &amp;ldquo;scratch disk&amp;rdquo; and a couple high(ish) end graphics cards with 3 monitors plugged in&amp;hellip; Hence the name, GodBox!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, on the other hand, has a 700Mhz processor, 256Mb RAM and not much else&amp;hellip; So, if you need to write code for your Pi, and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait a long time to compile, check out this tutorial on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bootc.net/archives/2012/05/26/how-to-build-a-cross-compiler-for-your-raspberry-pi/&#34;&gt;how to build a cross compiler for your raspberry pi&lt;/a&gt; which will allow you to build your apps on a different machine&amp;hellip; I have a college project which the Raspberry Pi will be used for, and i am thinking this will be how i build code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MicroTik RouterOS VPN Setup</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/microtik-routeros-vpn-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/microtik-routeros-vpn-setup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have been running a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.routerboard.com&#34;&gt;MikroTik RouterBoard&lt;/a&gt; in the house for a couple of months now (the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.routerboard.com/RB750G&#34;&gt;RB750G&lt;/a&gt;) and I am very much loving the thing. But one thing you may need to do is setup VPN connections&amp;hellip; Here are some tips on how to create a VPN Server and Client on your RouterBoard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;client-setup&#34;&gt;Client Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to setup a client, you need to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 8581643 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does that all do? the first line creates an l2tp-client interface, pointing at &amp;ldquo;servername&amp;rdquo; with the username and password set. encryption, etc is enabled&amp;hellip; Line 2 then enables the client. Line 3 sets all traffic comming from networkaddress/24 (for example, 192.168.0.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;24&lt;/sub&gt;) to be sent though the VPN. any traffic going into networkaddress (same example) is not sent though the VPN. Line 4 creates a gateway, for all addresses (0.0.0.0/0) to use the VPN address. finally, NAT Masquerading is enabled on the VPN interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there are more advanced things you can set above&amp;hellip; some examples I can think of are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be no good reason to limit the amount of VPN connections you have&amp;hellip; in theory, you could have multiple&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for the mangle rule, set the src-address to a single machine in your network. that way, it gets VPN only connections. Also, you could set the dst-address to a single address or network to send only traffic going to a given server though the VPN&amp;hellip; Example would be Netflix US traffic to a US VPN server, BBC iPlayer traffic to a UK VPN, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the example above uses L2TP, but PPTP, SSTP and OpenVPN are also available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;server-setup&#34;&gt;Server Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, L2TP, PPTP, SSTP and OpenVPN servers are available on RouterOs. Details on setting them up are available on MicroTik&amp;rsquo;s Wiki at the following locations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Interface/OVPN&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Interface/PPTP&#34;&gt;PPTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Interface/L2TP&#34;&gt;L2TP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Interface/SSTP&#34;&gt;SSTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Tunneling made simple</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ssh-tunneling-made-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ssh-tunneling-made-simple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something I do on a regular basis is use the internet while &amp;ldquo;out and about&amp;rdquo;. This could be college, which has a semi open network, or it could be a coffee shop, which also usually has a semi open connection. There is also the possibility of using the a mobile internet connection on my iPhone, which can be slow, but at least its only shared with me&amp;hellip; Anyway, over on RevSys.com, there is a post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.revsys.com/writings/quicktips/ssh-tunnel.html&#34;&gt;SSH Tunneling made simple&lt;/a&gt; which shows you how to open an SSH tunnel to your machine somewhere else (could be at home, as is my case, or a VPS/Dedicated server somewhere, or even on Amazon&amp;hellip;) and use that for different things&amp;hellip; In the case he shows, its for SMTP access. For my case, i am forwarding my local port 3128 to my Microsoft TMG 2010 Server in house on port 8080. Then my system proxy on my laptop is set to use localhost:3128 for all web and HTTPS requests. Very handy. One other tip: Using the -C flag, so your command may look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh yourname@remotemachine -L 3128:remoteMachine:8080 -C
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will compress data between you and the SSH server, which for basic web browsing (HTML, CSS, JS) will make things faster, but for stuff like images, etc, may not work so well&amp;hellip; Your Mileage may Vary&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, while on the subject of SSH, Linux Journal has an article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/6602&#34;&gt;Eleven SSH tricks&lt;/a&gt; which mentions compression, Encryption Cyphers, X11 Forwarding, Config files and other interesting bits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VOIP Stuff</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/voip-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/voip-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been very interested in VOIP stuff for the last while now, and finally started looking at implementing it in the house. Here are some links which may be useful. I will do a full post soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.stocksy.co.uk/wiki/Asterisk_1.8_with_chan_mobile_on_CentOS_6&#34;&gt;Asterisk 1.8 with chan_mobile on Centos 6&lt;/a&gt;: chan_mobile allows you to use a Bluetooth phone to make calls with Asterisk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stocksy.co.uk/articles/Networks/use_an_old_mobile_phone_as_a_gsm_gateway_in_asterisk/&#34;&gt;Use an old Mobile Phone as a GMS Gateway in asterisk&lt;/a&gt;: again, similar to above, but with Ubuntu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.3cx.com/&#34;&gt;3CX&lt;/a&gt;: my current choice in VOIP software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main VOIP hardware I use is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B000TSJ5JK/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000TSJ5JK&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=tiescomclo-21&#34;&gt;Cisco Small Business Pro SPA3102 Voice Gateway with Router (Amazon UK)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000FKP55U/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000FKP55U&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;Cisco Small Business Pro SPA3102 Voice Gateway with Router (Amazon US)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also use the 3CX software on both my iPhone and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tcx.sip.ui&#34;&gt;3CX phone for Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?grid=621&amp;amp;GR_URL=http%3A%2F%2Fitunes.apple.com%2Fie%2Fapp%2F3cxphone-for-iphone%2Fid392927995%3Fmt%3D8&#34;&gt;3CX phone for iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Stuff</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/rasberry-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/rasberry-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple months back, I got my hands on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, a tiny development board that can run a full copy of Linux, has a HDMI port, a couple USB ports, Ethernet and a few other little bits and pieces. The full specs, from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raspberry_Pi&#34;&gt;Wikipedia Article&lt;/a&gt; are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating system: Linux (Debian GNU/Linux, Fedora, and Arch Linux ARM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power: 2.5 W (model A), 3.5 W (model B)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU: ARM1176JZF-S (armv6k) 700 MHz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage capacity: SD card slot (SD or SDHC card)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory: 256 MByte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphics: Broadcom VideoCore IV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a few things i have wanted to play with it for, but have not implemented all them yet&amp;hellip; still learning&amp;hellip; but some interesting projects have come to my attention&amp;hellip; here they are, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://davidhunt.ie/?p=2641&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi embedded into a Canon 5D MKII Battery Grip&lt;/a&gt;: The idea of this is epic! the possibilities are endless&amp;hellip; GPS, Wifi, FTP, Processing RAW images (ok, maybe not with a 700Mhz processor&amp;hellip;), auto upload to the internet, auto add watermark, resize images before upload, send to iPad&amp;hellip; I could go on and on&amp;hellip;. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://liliputing.com/2012/08/raspberry-pi-mini-pc-crammed-into-a-keyboard.html&#34;&gt;Embedding a Raspberry Pi into a Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;: this is pretty cool too&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/phpBB3/viewtopic.php?f=26&amp;amp;t=12017&amp;amp;p=129471#p129471&#34;&gt;Quick setup of a Web Server on the Raspberry PI&lt;/a&gt;: Install Apache, SSH, PHP, MySQL and an FTP server, all on your Pi!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all fairness, the Pi makes a lot of ideas possible. with such a small size, and such a cheap price ($25-35), you are only limited by your imagination&amp;hellip; Wonder could i get Windows 8 installed on one of these&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there are also a few interesting things that may make the Pi work more portable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seeedstudio.com/depot/lipo-rider-pro-p-992.html?cPath=155&#34;&gt;LiPo Rider Pro&lt;/a&gt;: takes input from Batteries and Solar Panels and outputs as USB 5V. should run the Pi off solar and batteries for a while&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build your own Private GIT server</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/build-your-own-private-git-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 10:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/build-your-own-private-git-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This site is built with GIT, GitoLite and Jekyll&amp;hellip; I posted about this &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/29/NewSite.html&#34;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;. but how do you setup your own Git Server? checkout &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mmncs.com/2011/07/how-to-install-and-setup-a-git-repository-server-using-gitolite-on-linux-ubuntu-11-04-server-and-client/&#34;&gt;How to install and Setup a Git Repository Server using Gitolite on Linux Ubuntu 10.04 and 11.04&lt;/a&gt; on mmncs.com. I am using Ubuntu 12.04, but its mostly the same&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Storage Spaces in Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/understanding-windows8-storage-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 09:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/understanding-windows8-storage-spaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, Windows Server 2012 and Windows 8 have both RTMed in the last couple of weeks and will be available to the public in the next month or so (September for Server, October for Client). If you are an MSDN Subscriber, you already have Client, and will (hopefully) get server in the next couple of weeks&amp;hellip; Fingers crossed&amp;hellip; Anyway, one of the interesting features i am waiting for is &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/b8/archive/2012/01/05/virtualizing-storage-for-scale-resiliency-and-efficiency.aspx&#34;&gt;Storage Spaces&lt;/a&gt;. Tim Anderson&amp;rsquo;s Gadget Writing blog has some information on &lt;a href=&#34;http://gadgets.itwriting.com/1462-understanding-windows-8-storage-spaces-confusing-but-powerful.html&#34;&gt;how Storage Spaces works&lt;/a&gt;. handy notes on what to do and what not to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text 2 with Powershell</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/sublimetext-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 09:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/sublimetext-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My new Favorite cross platform text editor is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com/2&#34;&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt;. It works on Windows, Mac OS and Linux, and i am very happy with it. My only problem is the path to start it is not exactly easy to type&amp;hellip; So, with the help of PowerShell, my new favorite command line tool on Windows, i added an alias:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-Alias subl &#39;c:\program files\sublime text 2\sublime_text.exe&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added this to my Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1 file in Documents\WindowsPowerShell folder. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have one of these files, check out this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computerperformance.co.uk/powershell/powershell_profile_ps1.htm&#34;&gt;Computer Performance.Co.UK post on Creating PowerShell profile files&lt;/a&gt; and then edit the file and add the line above&amp;hellip; Now, I can edit files in PowerShell with Sublime Text 2 by typing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;subl filename
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy days!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoScaling with Amazon</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/autoscalling-with-amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/autoscalling-with-amazon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a few &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/ec2/&#34;&gt;Amazon EC2&lt;/a&gt; instances running on a project, and one of these instances was known as the Zombie Instance! Every time i killed it, it came back to life a few min later&amp;hellip; I found out that i, at some point, set that instance to be in an &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/autoscaling/&#34;&gt;AutoScaling&lt;/a&gt; group. Any time the instance died, Amazon would check and restart the instance. So, how did I kill this undead instance? Check out &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kkpradeeban.blogspot.ie/2011/02/auto-scaling-with-amazon-ec2-ii.html&#34;&gt;Auto Scaling with Amazon EC2 II&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; on LLOVIZNA&amp;rsquo;s blog. They had the same issue i had (trying to kill the Auto Scaling group gives an error) and figured out how to do it. Handy stuff. Now the instance is dead, and hopefully it wont come back any time soon&amp;hellip; Mind you, When AutoScaling works correctly, it can be very cool indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new Git Powered Site</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/newsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 12:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/newsite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, this site is brought to you by &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;GIT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and Magic&amp;hellip; here is how i did it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a Linux VM running the site. Its an &lt;a href=&#34;http://ubuntu.com&#34;&gt;Ubuntu 12.04&lt;/a&gt; server. On that i installed Jekyll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also have &lt;a href=&#34;http://sitaramc.github.com/gitolite/master-toc.html&#34;&gt;gitolite&lt;/a&gt; installed for personal git repos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Git Repo for this site, under the hooks directory, I added a post-receive file which I got from &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.zerosum.org/2010/11/01/pure-git-deploy-workflow.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; originally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache is set to serve the directory that Jekyll produces&amp;hellip; That&amp;rsquo;s what you are reading here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are interested, you can find the code and config for this site on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie&#34;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
