<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubiquiti on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/ubiquiti.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubiquiti on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2018 Tiernan OToole</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/ubiquiti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge Router, Sophos UTM, DMZ and LAN Networks</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/2015/09/30/edgerouter-sophosutm-dmz-lan-firwwalls.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/2015/09/30/edgerouter-sophosutm-dmz-lan-firwwalls.html</guid>
      <description>I have been using an EdgeRouer POE as my main router for most of the network (some of the network still uses PFSense as a router, but thats being removed soon) for the last few weeks, and i am quite happy with it. I also have a second router, a Sophos UTM VM between my first LAN (essentially a DMZ) and my client LAN (there will be more &amp;ldquo;LANs&amp;rdquo; over there soon).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 4)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/2015/09/16/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/2015/09/16/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-4.html</guid>
      <description>So, after some messing, tweaking, and thinking, I have made some progress with the home lab&amp;hellip; or at least broken some stuff&amp;hellip; I mentioned previously that i had a Ubiqititi networks EdgeRouter POE in the home lab. Originally, the plan was to use a Virtual PFSense box for my core router&amp;hellip; Given the power usage of the current PfSense Box (I have 2 MPower Pro&amp;rsquo;s watching power in the lab) I am now thinking of moving to just the EdgeRouter for, well, edge routing&amp;hellip; below is the usage of the ProLiant for the last 12 hours or so:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquiti EdgeRouter PoE in the lab</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/2015/08/05/ubiquiti-edgerouter-poe-in-the-lab.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/2015/08/05/ubiquiti-edgerouter-poe-in-the-lab.html</guid>
      <description>Today, my Ubiquiti EdgeRouter POE arrived in the house. I got it hooked up to both UPC connections (as secondary connections) and all seems to be working grand. Some notes i wanted to put up here:
 out of the box, the install was quite simple. set my Ethernet connection to a static ip in the 192.168.1.x/24 range, using 192.168.1.1 as gateway and dns, and then point at http://192.168.1.1 for admin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>