<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Web and Desktop Apps 2016 edition</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/useful-web-and-desktop-apps-2016-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/useful-web-and-desktop-apps-2016-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided to do a post on some of my favourite tools to use for development, administration, etc. It’s kind of like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/ScottHanselmans2014UltimateDeveloperAndPowerUsersToolListForWindows.aspx&#34;&gt;Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s Ultimate Tools list&lt;/a&gt;, but not as popular and about 2 years newer&amp;hellip; Anyway, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/ToolsList/&#34;&gt;list is available here&lt;/a&gt;, and will be updated over time, much like my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/DailyCarry/&#34;&gt;Daily Carry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/&#34;&gt;Computers&lt;/a&gt; pages. If you are interested, you add links though &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; by editing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie/blob/master/_data/toolslist.yml&#34;&gt;toolslist.yml data file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash on Ubuntu on Windows</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buildwindows.com/&#34;&gt;Build 2016&lt;/a&gt; is on this week, and there were a lot of interesting developments yesterday, but the one that interested me the most is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/DevelopersCanRunBashShellAndUsermodeUbuntuLinuxBinariesOnWindows10.aspx&#34;&gt;Bash on Ubuntu on Windows&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.dustinkirkland.com/2016/03/ubuntu-on-windows.html&#34;&gt;Dustin from Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; has a more details, and Scott Hanselman has posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/Build/2016/C906&#34;&gt;a technical video&lt;/a&gt; about this. This is very interesting, and I CANT WAIT TO GET MY HANDS ON IT! But, I do have some questions, which I thought I would put down in blog format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the post by Dustin, it seems that low level Linux calls are being handled and translated to Windows system calls. Which makes me think, could &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; Linux Distro work? Could &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archlinux.org&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redhat.com&#34;&gt;RedHat&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centos.org&#34;&gt;Centos&lt;/a&gt; work in the same way?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will this Work on Windows Server 2016 when it launches?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given that it calling down to a low level, could GUI applications work too?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shut up and take my money! I WANT IT NOW!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there are my questions&amp;hellip; This is very cool, and I cannot wait to get my hands on this. Just wondering if this will be available to &lt;a href=&#34;https://insider.windows.com/&#34;&gt;Windows Insiders&lt;/a&gt; sooner, rather than later?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulk compressing images for the Web</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/bulk-compressing-images-for-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/bulk-compressing-images-for-the-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that all my sites are running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; I am trying to get them optimized for &lt;strong&gt;SPEED&lt;/strong&gt; which meant
looking at all the stuff that takes time to download&amp;hellip; There are more tweaks (and possibly posts) coming down
the road, but to start, I needed to look at images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first. I&amp;rsquo;m running this on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sabayon.org&#34;&gt;Sabayon Linux&lt;/a&gt; box, so some of the install commands will be different&amp;hellip; (Also, i do need to explain why I moved from Windows to Linux on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/GodBoxV2.html&#34;&gt;GodboxV2&lt;/a&gt;, but that&amp;rsquo;s a different post&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, install &lt;a href=&#34;http://optipng.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;OptiPNG&lt;/a&gt; (they have a Windows build too&amp;hellip;) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kokkonen.net/tjko/projects.html&#34;&gt;JPEGOptim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo equo install optipng
sudo equo install jpegoptim
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[UPDATE] I tried this on an Ubutnu Box, and to install both of these, the package names are the same. so, to install both:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install optipng jpegoptim
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, using the Linux find command (this should work also on OSX&amp;hellip;) run OptiPNG and JPEGOptim on all pngs and
jpgs in your given directory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;find . -iname &amp;quot;*.png&amp;quot; -exec optipng {} \;
find . -iname &amp;quot;*.jpe?g&amp;quot; -exec jpegoptim {} \;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;depending on how many images (and how fast your machine is) it should take a min or two&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! I did a git status, which showed me all the changed images, and then deployed the Jekyll sites&amp;hellip; All
good! That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 &#43; MikroTik &#43; Linux &#43; Windows</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_%2b_mikrotik_%2b_linux_%2b_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 16:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_%2b_mikrotik_%2b_linux_%2b_windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to setup an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ipv6&#34;&gt;IPv6&lt;/a&gt; network for a while now, but never had the hardware or network to support it. My broadband Modem, a Cisco EPC3925, was pretty useless&amp;hellip; But with the advent of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/02/Enabling-true-briding-mode-on-Cisco-EPC3925.html&#34;&gt;Bridging on the Cisco EPC3925&lt;/a&gt; it now works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing i needed to do was setup a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tunnelbroker.net/&#34;&gt;Tunnel Broker Account&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.he.net&#34;&gt;Hurricane Electric&lt;/a&gt;. I got a /64 block of IPv6 addresses, which should do me for a while&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I followed the config example from the MikroTik Wiki Page: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:My_First_IPv6_Network&#34;&gt;My First IPv6 Network&lt;/a&gt;. In my case, i only ran though most of router 1&amp;rsquo;s config, and did not create the &amp;ldquo;routing between segments&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ospv-v3&amp;rdquo; backbone&amp;hellip; I did give my internal LAN port an IPv6 address, as well as an IPv4 address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, on my Windows Server machine, i gave it a static IPv6 address (since i dont have an IPv6 DHCP setup&amp;hellip; yet&amp;hellip;) and told it to use the IPv6 address i gave the RouteBoard as its gateway. Then i told it to use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendns.com&#34;&gt;OpenDNS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendns.com/ipv6&#34;&gt;public IPv6&lt;/a&gt; address. I then visited &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipv6-test.com&#34;&gt;IPv6 Test&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ipv6.google.com&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s IPv6 page&lt;/a&gt; to confirm connectivity&amp;hellip; SUCCESS!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my Linux box, I followed &lt;a href=&#34;http://knowledgelayer.softlayer.com/questions/468/Adding+IPv6+to+Ubuntu+systems&#34;&gt;Soflayer&amp;rsquo;s Adding an IPv6 IP&lt;/a&gt; tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WANProxy and Squid with Upstream Servers</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/wanproxy_and_squid_with_upstream_servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 13:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/wanproxy_and_squid_with_upstream_servers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/24/building_wanproxy_on_ubuntu_12.04.html&#34;&gt;previous post on WANProxy&lt;/a&gt;, i did not really go into detail about what it actually was. The direct quote from their site is &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wanproxy.org&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt; is a free, portable TCP proxy which makes TCP connections send less data, which improves TCP performance and throughput over lossy links, slow links and long links. This is just what you need to improve performance over satellite, wireless and WAN links.&lt;/em&gt; This is something that has interested me for a while, so i have been looking into it, and so far so good&amp;hellip; In my last post i mentioned i was proxying &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; traffic, in todays post, i still am, but with some tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i have a Squid box running in the house. It is connected to 2 Cable Modems, giving me 250Mbits/s down and 20Mbits/s upload connection. It is caching data locally also.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on my laptop i have Squid running also. It connects to a WANProxy server at home and proxies the Squid server. The local squid box is using the home Squid box as an upstream connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for upstream connections i used the following lines in the squid.conf:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 3958472 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have set it to never use a direct connection, which is probably silly, since if i loose the WANProxy connection, i loose connectivity&amp;hellip; Also, port 3300 is the WANProxy port its listening on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good&amp;hellip; I am also thinking this could be an interesting thing to get working on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;. Just a though&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building WANProxy on Ubuntu 12.04</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/building_wanproxy_on_ubuntu_12.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 14:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/building_wanproxy_on_ubuntu_12.04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Updated 2016/04/09] I had to use this today to build on Debian 8.3 for 2 different boxes. So, making minor changes (url to git proxy, and where you build from) to make sure this works now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been looking into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wanproxy.org&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, but never successfully got it to build&amp;hellip; I have been more successfull reciently, so here is what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** NOTE **: I built this on Ubuntu 12.04, so these are the tips for that&amp;hellip; Not sure about other Distros&amp;hellip;
** Second NOTE ** : I am using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/diegows/wanproxy&#34;&gt;Digows GitHub Repo&lt;/a&gt; for downloads&amp;hellip; There is also the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/svn/trunk&#34;&gt;WANProxy SVN Server&lt;/a&gt; and their official &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/get.shtml&#34;&gt;downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install build-essential git-core libssl-dev uuid-dev

git clone https://github.com/wanproxy/wanproxy.git

cd wanproxy/programs/wanproxy

make
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note -: git-core is needed to checkout code, build-essentails gives you your essential build utils, and the -dev files are needed for the build
*- NOTE -: I have tried it on a couple VMs and they take about  5 min to build&amp;hellip; If you are building on Physical hardware, it may be faster. Also, as a general note, if you are building with multiple processors, try add the -jX option, where x is your CPU count +1. for example, make -j5 if you have CPUs or Cores. or make -j17 if you have 16 cores&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cp wanproxy ~/local/bin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~Now, this is, so far, as far as i have gotten&amp;hellip; but given its building, and its further than I was a few weeks back, i though i would post incase i can help someone else&amp;hellip; ~~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** UPDATE ** I have successfully managed to get a WANProxy working. The way i have it setup is as follows:
** UPDATE 2016 ** as part of my series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Projects/&#34;&gt;getting double internet speed&lt;/a&gt;, I am back looking at WANProxy&amp;hellip; more on that later..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux box in house, and VM on laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;both have WANProxy installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use the ** Proxying over SSH ** example &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/examples.shtml&#34;&gt;from the WANProxy examples site&lt;/a&gt; which shows you how to proxy a single web server over SSH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in my case, i pointed the port at my proxy server inhouse. I also changed the if0.host address from 127.0.0.1 (only accessable from that machine) to its internal IP address (can be seen by anyone on that network)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally, I told my browser to use the WANProxy ip and port 3300 (see the if0 config section) as its proxy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Works grand so far. no idea yet if its &amp;ldquo;faster&amp;rdquo; but its working, which is a start&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boot Raspberry Pi with SSH Enabled, Enable Wifi on Boot, and more</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/boot_raspberry_pi_with_ssh_enabled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 16:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/boot_raspberry_pi_with_ssh_enabled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some interesting links for the Raspberry Pi today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, you just bought a new Raspberry Pi and need to enable SSH, but dont have a screen? &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/38/prepare-for-ssh-without-a-screen&#34;&gt;Prepare for SSH without a Screen&lt;/a&gt; shows you what to do!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/3200/wifi-bring-wlan0-up-on-boot&#34;&gt;How to Bring up WLAN0 on boot&lt;/a&gt; shows you how to start your Wifi adapter when you boot your Pi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Tunneling made simple</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ssh-tunneling-made-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ssh-tunneling-made-simple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something I do on a regular basis is use the internet while &amp;ldquo;out and about&amp;rdquo;. This could be college, which has a semi open network, or it could be a coffee shop, which also usually has a semi open connection. There is also the possibility of using the a mobile internet connection on my iPhone, which can be slow, but at least its only shared with me&amp;hellip; Anyway, over on RevSys.com, there is a post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.revsys.com/writings/quicktips/ssh-tunnel.html&#34;&gt;SSH Tunneling made simple&lt;/a&gt; which shows you how to open an SSH tunnel to your machine somewhere else (could be at home, as is my case, or a VPS/Dedicated server somewhere, or even on Amazon&amp;hellip;) and use that for different things&amp;hellip; In the case he shows, its for SMTP access. For my case, i am forwarding my local port 3128 to my Microsoft TMG 2010 Server in house on port 8080. Then my system proxy on my laptop is set to use localhost:3128 for all web and HTTPS requests. Very handy. One other tip: Using the -C flag, so your command may look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh yourname@remotemachine -L 3128:remoteMachine:8080 -C
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will compress data between you and the SSH server, which for basic web browsing (HTML, CSS, JS) will make things faster, but for stuff like images, etc, may not work so well&amp;hellip; Your Mileage may Vary&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, while on the subject of SSH, Linux Journal has an article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/6602&#34;&gt;Eleven SSH tricks&lt;/a&gt; which mentions compression, Encryption Cyphers, X11 Forwarding, Config files and other interesting bits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build your own Private GIT server</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/build-your-own-private-git-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 10:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/build-your-own-private-git-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This site is built with GIT, GitoLite and Jekyll&amp;hellip; I posted about this &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/29/NewSite.html&#34;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;. but how do you setup your own Git Server? checkout &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mmncs.com/2011/07/how-to-install-and-setup-a-git-repository-server-using-gitolite-on-linux-ubuntu-11-04-server-and-client/&#34;&gt;How to install and Setup a Git Repository Server using Gitolite on Linux Ubuntu 10.04 and 11.04&lt;/a&gt; on mmncs.com. I am using Ubuntu 12.04, but its mostly the same&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
