<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet </title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with AMD&#39;s Epyc</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/playing-with-amd-epyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/playing-with-amd-epyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, a few days back I got an email from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packet.net&#34;&gt;Packet.net&lt;/a&gt; about a promotion they and AMD where running. Essentially, they gave me some credit for their service (i am an existing customer) to play with one of their c2.medium machines. A c2.medium comes with an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amd.com/en/products/cpu/amd-epyc-7401p&#34;&gt;AMD EPYC 7401P&lt;/a&gt; which consists of 24 physical cores clocked at 2Gz with an all core boost at 2.8Gb and a max clock of 3Gz, 48 threads, 64GB ECC Memory, 2x120GB SSDs for boot and 2x480GB SSDs for main stoage. It also has a 20Gb network link (2x10gb bonded) and can run pretty much any OS you can think of (Windows is not on the list officially, but you can boot off your own ISO, so you could probably get it on there&amp;hellip; might not be supported, but it might be possible). all this for $1 per hour! And did i mention they are bare metal machines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the perfect opertunity to play with the new AMD processors. My current and previoius generation workstations (GodBoxv1 and Godboxv2) are both running Intel Xeon processors. the machine previous to this, the mac pro, is also running a Xeon processor. But previous to both of them, my first 2 major workstations ran AMD&amp;hellip; the first ran 2 AMD Athlon MP processors. These were old school processors that were single core, and i cant even remember their speeds, but i do know there were 32bit only and the machine maxed out at about 1.25GB RAM (well, i had it maxed out at that). the second AMD workstation ran 2 AMD Opterons&amp;hellip; again, single core machines, but this time, they ran 64 bit and IIRC maxed out at 8GB ram. This was a limitation of the board, not the processor&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about GodboxV.next, and the AMD processors, specicially the &lt;a href=&#34;https://products.amd.com/en-us/search/cpu/amd-ryzen%E2%84%A2/amd-ryzen%E2%84%A2-threadripper&#34;&gt;Threadrippers&lt;/a&gt; and Epycs, are contenders for the next machine&amp;hellip; so, this test allows me to check them out before i buy!Why would i say no?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, i spun a box up in New Jersey running Ubuntu 17.10 to play with it, and here are my findings&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, i ran lscpu on the box to see what i was playing with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/4877abe19c89f1e45e617da1b4d46447.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then ran fdisk -l to see what disks i had to play with. on my machine sda and sdb where the 480gb SSDs, sdc was a 120gb that was empty and sdd was the boot drive&amp;hellip; i installed the btrfs-progs and then formatted sda and sdb as a RAID0 array, which i then mounted to /mnt. this gave me just under 900gb to play with&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my first test is the usual test: building the Linux Kernel. I know that this is something that the lads at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servethehome.com&#34;&gt;ServeTheHome&lt;/a&gt; do a lot but its something i wanted to try my self&amp;hellip; So, first i installed git and build essential, then bison, flex and ncurses-dev, then i cloned Linus&amp;rsquo; git repo at git://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git. First things first: this machine has a twin 10gb link, a shead load of cores and some very fast storage. How long did it take to clone? it download 1.02 GiB at 35.32MiB/s (about 30 seconds and aboiut 280Mbit/s) and all in, took 2 min 55 seconds to clone. I then ran &amp;lsquo;time make -j 49&amp;rsquo; to see how long it would take&amp;hellip; hmmm&amp;hellip; no config file&amp;hellip; make menuconfig and just hit save&amp;hellip; defaults are grand&amp;hellip; time make -j 49 again&amp;hellip; and more errors&amp;hellip; after a bit of googling, i find the page from Ubutnu &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/KernelTeam/GitKernelBuild&#34;&gt;showing what i need to do to build the kernel&lt;/a&gt;. i follow that&amp;hellip; download a LOT more stuff using their instrustions, and finally, we get to build&amp;hellip; Time: 6 min 12 seconds&amp;hellip; this is a FULL default build of the kernel&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530618253/top_kernel_build_epy_hdb0R.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same build on a VM on GodboxV2 (which was given 32GB RAM and 16 thread, so a full Xeon E5-4620) took 8min 27s to clone (8.18MiB/s. or about 64Mbit/s) and 36 min&amp;hellip; yea, that is 3x less cores, 2x less memory, slower storage (This is on Spinny Disk, not SSD), slower network and it is also a VM VS bare metal, still, to be essentially 6 times slower? interesting&amp;hellip; I might, at some stage, boot the machine off a live Linux USB and run some more tests, but not tonight&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530618253/top-kernel-build-godboxv2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, all this is becasue i was holding out for the main event&amp;hellip; Photo processing&amp;hellip; I wanted to do somethign &amp;ldquo;real life&amp;rdquo;, which for me would be development and photo processing&amp;hellip; the kernel build gives an idea of a large project build built, the image processsing gives an idea of multimedia work&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so, i devised a test: Export a bunch of photos (mix of photos taken on my 5Ds, 5D MKII, iPhone 6 Plus and iPhone 7Plus) that are stored in light room as full  and run them though a basic .NET Core app i wrote. the code for the app is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/imageresizer-testapp&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;. The app fully utilizes the machine by using multiple threads, and because its 64 bit, it will use as much memory as it can get its hands on. It just does some basic processing: open the file, resize to 1024X1024 and then save it&amp;hellip; the 1024X1024 part is just a test&amp;hellip; i was a bit under the gun on time, so couldnt spend as much time working on it as i wanted to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, there was 1546 photos exported, and the total file size was 15Gb. First obstical was to get them uploaded to the Packet machine, which took a while (my upload speed is currently 40Mbit/s)&amp;hellip; Once up, i downloaded a copy of dotnet core 2.0 SDK, cloned the repo with the project, built and ran&amp;hellip; and man, its fast! 4 min 43 seconds. And it used all the cores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530618252/image-resizer-epyc.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running the same code on GodBoxV2 on the bare metal (no VM this time), i got XX min of a run&amp;hellip; Now, GodBoxV2 has other things running in the back ground, but not that much&amp;hellip; I also noticed that, on average, photos were being processed in 3-5 seconds on Epyc, but nearly 13-15, and sometimes 20 and 25 seconds on GodBoxV2. I also noticed that on Epyc, the dotnet process took nearly 45GB of RAM&amp;hellip; to run&amp;hellip; On GodBoxV2, it took over 70!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530618252/image_resizer_godbox_f5de0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. Some starting tests with these processors. I am well impressed with these processors, and would have no issue getting one for the next GodBox&amp;hellip; And with names like Epyc and Threadripper, why not?!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging on an iPad Pro</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/blogging-on-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/blogging-on-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, a few months back I bought myself an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/ipad-pro&#34;&gt;iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. I got a 10.5&amp;rdquo; with 64GB Storage and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MPTL2LL/A/smart-keyboard-for-105‑inch-ipad-pro-us-english?fnode=37&#34;&gt;Smart Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, i have been mostly using it for playing around: watching YouTube, Netflix, surfing on the couch, etc. but i started to wonder how &amp;ldquo;Pro&amp;rdquo; this was&amp;hellip;so i went and did some testing, and in the end nearly all of this post is being written on it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;first, the good stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ai/app/microsoft-remote-desktop/id714464092?mt=8&#34;&gt;Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Remote Desktop Connection&lt;/a&gt; works perfect on the iPad Pro. I have RDPed into machines (with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zerotier.com&#34;&gt;ZeroTier&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/prompt-2/id917437289?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=11l4BV&#34;&gt;Panic&amp;rsquo;s Prompt&lt;/a&gt; works well too&amp;hellip; again, with ZeroTier, i can SSH into boxes and remote manage them. Handy for checking on docker instances&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panic also have &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/coda/id500906297?mt=8&amp;amp;at=11l4BV&#34;&gt;Coda for iOS&lt;/a&gt;. its a very nice (if somewhat expensive at $25) editor for the iPad. This post is being written on there now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for Git stuff, i am using an app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/working-copy/id896694807?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=6&amp;amp;at=1000lHq&amp;amp;ct=workingcopyapp&#34;&gt;Working Copy&lt;/a&gt;. Its free, to an extend, but if you need to do stuff like push changes, which is kind of important, then you need to pay a fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coda and Working Copy work together with some magic built into Working Copy. It can act as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://workingcopyapp.com/manual/webdav-server&#34;&gt;WebDav server&lt;/a&gt;, which Coda can the connect to. you open, edit, change and create docs, and Working Copy keeps note. then you swap to them and checkin. You need to have both apps on the screen at the same time (the docking feature works well for that) since iOS seems to kill some background tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unrelated to blogging, but i have also tried editing photos using &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ai/app/adobe-lightroom-cc-for-ipad/id804177739?mt=8&#34;&gt;Lightroom&lt;/a&gt;, and so far so good. I have used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/ie/shop/product/MJYT2ZM/A/lightning-to-sd-card-camera-reader&#34;&gt;Apple SD Card adapter&lt;/a&gt; to download 50MP photos (upwards of 60MB) from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usa.canon.com/internet/portal/us/home/products/details/cameras/dslr/eos-5ds&#34;&gt;Canon 5Ds&lt;/a&gt; quick enough, add them to Lightroom, make some changes and send them to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tiernano&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook (not Instagram just yet&amp;hellip;) and it works well. I have managed to hook it to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnarbox.com&#34;&gt;Gnarbox&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad Stuff?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keyboard takes a bit of getting used to. the Stupid &amp;ldquo;Global&amp;rdquo; button to swap keyboards (from
English to Emoji) is in the place you would expect to find CTRL. and CTRL, Option and Cmd (remember, this is a &amp;ldquo;Mac&amp;rdquo; style keyboard) and all shifted one place&amp;hellip; I would have preferred if they moved that somewhere else, or removed it altogether&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a mouse would be very handy! I have tried pairing a bluetooth mouse to it, and no luck&amp;hellip; it would be handy especially for editing documents and code, since touchscreen is &amp;ldquo;handy&amp;rdquo; some of the time, but not all the time&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. Blogging on an iPad. Would i give up my daily driver of my Surface Book and GodBoxV2 and just uses an iPad? Hell No&amp;hellip; for basic stuff, it works well. Basic photo editing, blogging, surfing, etc, yes. But there is a reason my workstation has 16 processor cores and 160GB RAM: I need it. I have multiple copies of Visual Studio running, SQL Server, multiple VMs running different tasks, multiple web browsers, multiple monitors, etc. the iPad can do a good chunk of stuff, but not the major stuff&amp;hellip; not yet. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook. all the major office tools work grand. But Visual Studio? SQL Management Studio? just not there yet&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what did i not do on the iPad, and ended up doing on the PC? Well, so far, nothing&amp;hellip; using Coda and Working Copy, i wrote the text, previewed it and checked it into GitHub. Then, Prompt is being used to build it on my docker box, check into the static site and push, which will then publish. unless you see an update below, all went as planned and all was done on an iPad&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Desktop becoming a reality</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/cloud-desktop-becoming-reality./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/cloud-desktop-becoming-reality./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have talked about the theory of the &amp;ldquo;Cloud desktop&amp;rdquo; twice on my older blog (&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.lotas-smartman.net/rackspaces-hosted-virtual-desktop/&#34;&gt;Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s Hosted Virtual Desktop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.lotas-smartman.net/more-on-desktop-in-the-cloud/&#34;&gt;More on the desktop in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;) way back since 2011. Since then, a few things have changed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon have released &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/workspaces/&#34;&gt;AWS Workspaces&lt;/a&gt;, which is a cloud based desktop using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teradici.com/pcoip-technology&#34;&gt;Teradici&amp;rsquo;s PCoIP technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/&#34;&gt;EC2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/services/virtual-machines/&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; now have GPU enabled VMs to spin up and use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NVidia have released &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nvidia.co.uk/grid/&#34;&gt;NVidia Grid cards&lt;/a&gt;, specifically for the &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;remote&amp;rdquo; desktop services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-ie/windows/continuum&#34;&gt;Windows Continuum&lt;/a&gt; now allows you to use your Windows Phone with a keyboard, monitor and mouse, allowing you to replace your desktop. basically, plug your continuum enabled phone into a docking station, and use it as a Windows Desktop. Email, Browsing, Office Apps, etc. anything that supports UWP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and now &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neowin.net/news/vmware-releases-horizon-beta-client-for-windows-10-mobile-continuum-compatible&#34;&gt;VMWare has just released a Windows UWP app that works with Continuum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the increased bandwidth for mobile devices (4 and 5G, expanding wifi, etc) the idea of having your desktop live in the cloud is getting nearer&amp;hellip;  interesting times, my friend&amp;hellip; interesting times&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Update] Thinking a bit more about this, and if this was to work correctly, your phone could be everything required. Get up in the morning, check your emails on your phone, calander items, and news. head off, head to the coffee shop and plug your phone into a &amp;ldquo;laptop&amp;rdquo; style device like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://nexdock.com/&#34;&gt;NexDock&lt;/a&gt; and catch up on some emails, checking more news sites, etc. When you get into the office, plug your phone into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-ie/mobile/accessory/hd-500/&#34;&gt;docking station&lt;/a&gt; and Remote Desktop in to your cloud desktop to do your development work, or whatever needs to be done. basic Office apps and Email can be run direct from the phone. When you get home, you can use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/accessories/en-us/products/adapters/wireless-display-adapter-2/p3q-00001&#34;&gt;Microsoft Wireless Display adapter&lt;/a&gt; to watch videos on the big TV, or show web pages. And if your cloud desktop is available outside of your work network, you could work anywhere also&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge Router, Sophos UTM, DMZ and LAN Networks</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/edgerouter-sophosutm-dmz-lan-firwwalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/edgerouter-sophosutm-dmz-lan-firwwalls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;EdgeRouer POE&lt;/a&gt; as my main router for most of the network (some of the network still uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; as a router, but thats being removed soon) for the last few weeks, and i am quite happy with it. I also have a second router, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/unified-threat-management.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM&lt;/a&gt; VM between my first LAN (essentially a DMZ) and my client LAN (there will be more &amp;ldquo;LANs&amp;rdquo; over there soon). The Client LAN is NATed between the DMZ and the LAN, which means anything on the LAN i want to access from the DMZ has to be port forwarded&amp;hellip; Ideally, not much from the LAN should be accessible though the DMZ, but in my initial setup, stuff like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plex.tv&#34;&gt;Plex&lt;/a&gt;, etc, is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What i wanted to do was setup a proper firewall between both networks, without the use of NAT&amp;hellip; Do do this, i first had to disable th masquerading rules in Sophos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530620916/20150930-masquerading-off.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next, on the EdgeRouter, i added a static route to point at the new network:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530620916/20150930-static-route.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, under firewall rules, i allowed what i wanted to allow (in this case, SSH from any DMZ client (not advised) to my Mac Mini).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530620916/20150930-firewall-rules.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, as they say, is that! So far, so good!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 4)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, after some messing, tweaking, and thinking, I have made some progress with the home lab&amp;hellip; or at least broken some stuff&amp;hellip; I mentioned previously that i had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2015/08/05/Ubiquiti-EdgeRouter-POE-In-the-lab.html&#34;&gt;Ubiqititi networks EdgeRouter POE&lt;/a&gt; in the home lab. Originally, the plan was to use a Virtual &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; box for my core router&amp;hellip; Given the power usage of the current PfSense Box (I have 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/mfi/mpower/&#34;&gt;MPower Pro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s watching power in the lab) I am now thinking of moving to just the EdgeRouter for, well, edge routing&amp;hellip;  below is the usage of the ProLiant for the last 12 hours or so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-proliant-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Proliant Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for the same period, here is the usage for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Edge Router&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-edgerouter-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;EdgeRouter POE Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also setting up a DMZ for front facing services, and then a LAN for inside facing machines. There will be a firewall (currently thinking &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/unified-threat-management.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM&lt;/a&gt; or similar) between the DMZ and the network. Some machines will be able to access the DMZ, and there may be machines allowed into the LAN, but only some things&amp;hellip; not even sure if that would be done&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also need to work out the VLAN side of things. I have currently though of the following VLAN setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WAN 1 (connected directly to the Cable modem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WAN 2 (again, direct to cable modem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LAN Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DMZ Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VoIP Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IOT (stuff for running the house, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/ie/thermostat/meet-nest-thermostat/&#34;&gt;Nest&lt;/a&gt;, the MPower devices or the like)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Media Network (Plex, Roku, Apple TV, Chrome Cast, etc. Not sure if i need to separate this, but it might be done&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/switches/catalyst-3560-series-switches/index.html&#34;&gt;Cisco 3560G switch&lt;/a&gt; should do all that, without problems, so no new switch needed&amp;hellip; lets see what i can break over the next while&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Server 2012 R2 returning to The GodBoxV2</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/windwsserver2012r2-returing-to-the-godboxv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/windwsserver2012r2-returing-to-the-godboxv2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few months of running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sabayon.org&#34;&gt;Sabayon&lt;/a&gt; Linux on the GodboxV2, i am going back to Windows Server. Back around October of last year, i installed Windows 10 Preview on the GodBoxV2, and, well, there where issues with graphics drivers, etc. Then, some time after, i cant remember off hand when, i moved to Sabayon Linux. Its based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gentoo.org&#34;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt; but has a lot of the components pre-built. Gentoo is a &amp;ldquo;Build from scratch&amp;rdquo; sort of OS. You get a basic kernel and a basic set of components, but you build everything else from scratch&amp;hellip; including rebuilding the kernel if you want. Sabayon, on the other hand has all that mostly prebuilt, though you can still use Gentoo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/Portage&#34;&gt;Portage&lt;/a&gt; to build stuff yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for the last few months, all was going mostly well&amp;hellip; but I miss Windows. And, given i have pretty much always ran a server OS on my main workstations, I am heading back to Server 2012R2. I was tempted by 2016, but its still very early days&amp;hellip; Maybe i will run it as a VM for a while, but we will see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFS Home storage pool</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zfs-home-dir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zfs-home-dir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://btrfs.wiki.kernel.org/index.php/Main_Page&#34;&gt;BTRFS&lt;/a&gt; pool for my /home directory on Linux failed&amp;hellip; Not sure what happened, but it made me
do something i wanted to do for a while: Build a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ZFS&#34;&gt;ZFS&lt;/a&gt; pool for my home dir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, the pool consists of 4 2Tb hard drives and 1 128Gb SSD. Its setup in RAIDZ1 (equivilent of RAID 5)
and then the SSD is set for caching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create the pool i ran&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;zpool create home raidz sda sde sdf sdg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then, to add the cache drive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;zpool add home cache sdd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the pool (in my case) got mounted to /home, and then i restored my backup to it. to do some tests, i can the
following&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 638891a7d9acac8e396f %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;614MB/s write and 5.3GB a second read is nothing to be sniffed at! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquiti EdgeRouter PoE in the lab</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ubiquiti-edgerouter-poe-in-the-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ubiquiti-edgerouter-poe-in-the-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti EdgeRouter POE&lt;/a&gt; arrived in the house. I got it hooked up to both UPC connections (as secondary connections) and all seems to be working grand. Some notes i wanted to put up here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;out of the box, the install was quite simple. set my Ethernet connection to a static ip in the 192.168.1.x/24 range,
using 192.168.1.1 as gateway and dns, and then point at &lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.1&#34;&gt;http://192.168.1.1&lt;/a&gt; for admin. login (ubit for both username and
password) and heay presto. I was asked did i agree to the license, and then im in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by default, NAT is off&amp;hellip; i turned it on, and enabled DNS and was able to surf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also noticed the software was out of date&amp;hellip; Oddly, there did not seem to be an option to update automatically, but
you can manually download the tar and upload it, which i did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;so far, so good&amp;hellip; not sure yet if i will be using it as my main router, but it may end up being a VoIP router.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, speed test result below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/tiernanotoole/image/upload/v1530620885/20150805.ubiquiti.speedtest.compressed-resized.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Speed Test Result&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti&lt;/a&gt; stuff arriving tomorrow&amp;hellip; will post more stuff then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, this part of my article set will be talking specifically about the router and wireless network. At the moment, my router is way overkill:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old HP Proliant ML110 G5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/29765/Intel-Core2-Quad-Processor-Q6600-8M-Cache-2_40-GHz-1066-MHz-FSB?q=Q6600&#34;&gt;Intel Core2Quad Q6600&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 Gb RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;total of 12 Gigabit network cards (of which 4 are currently used&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;500Gb HDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been playing with some networking in the house and have managed to build some VLANs. The modems are connected both directly to the Router
and to a dedicated switch port for a given VLAN. The plan for the upgrade, which i hope to complete sooner than the rest of the network is as
follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get the ML110 running &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/products/vsphere-hypervisor&#34;&gt;ESXi&lt;/a&gt; and visualize &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt;. Give it 2gb of RAM and some processor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take some of the network cards out of the box. It does not need 12 ports, but maybe leave the 2 quad ports in there. They should be connected
to the main switch trunked. 8 may be overkill, but i never do things by half.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the PFSEnse VM should be connected to all 3 WAN VlANs (900, 901 and 902) and should also have at least one port to the LAN. There may also be
other ports for other internal VLANs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with the spare processor, i can then add other (small) VMs to this machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, in my last post i talked about the requirements for the home lab, and in this post, im going to talk about a few more updates i have made in the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the processors: in the first post, i talked about Xeon D or Xeon E3&amp;hellip; Well, i missed one&amp;hellip; The Xeon E5. I have 2 of these in GodBox 2, and you can get them into a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servethehome.com/asrock-rack-epc612d4i-review-mitx-xeon-e5-platform/&#34;&gt;microATX board&lt;/a&gt;. There does seem to be some limits with the microatx boards, but hopefully enough searching will find me what i am looking for. Ideally, i want it to take &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; DDR3/4 memory (not SODIMMs like the ASRock one above) and also take enough of them to run 64 or 128Gb of ram (thinking 8 would do the job!). Also, i would like to have 4 GigE ports onboard and 1 management port. 4 onboard is not a hard requirement: If i can get one with 2 ports, i can always get a 4 port card for the PCI-Express slot&amp;hellip; Finally, i would like it to have at least 6 SATA ports and possibly an MSATA port. Thinking Boot off MSATA (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Server_2016&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2016 Nano Server&lt;/a&gt; would be used), 2 SSDs and 4 HDDs. Using Storage Spaces, use the 2 SSDs as &amp;ldquo;Fast&amp;rdquo; storage for the pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think i moved off the idea of 10Gb. I like the idea of it, but given a small 10Gb switch costs upwards of a grand, and the plan is to build a machine for that price, i would prefer a fifth machine and using my existing Cisco 48 port switch and leave 10Gb as a future upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, changed from last time round is machine count. Originally i was saying 3-4 machines&amp;hellip; now i am thinking 6-7&amp;hellip; 5-6 of them should be Hyper-V boxes and the last one would be a Media Box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think the Synology or SAN requirement is out&amp;hellip; Hyper-V can be setup to do replication between hosts, and with a 4Gb link to the LAN, i think i should be OK. Also, if i have the media box separate, i should be ok there too. I will detail the media center in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, any suggestions or thoughts on what should and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be looked at?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and Homelab V.Next (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, its that time again&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/Computers&#34;&gt;HomeLab&lt;/a&gt; upgrade time&amp;hellip; Or at least the planning for it. I am in the process of rebuilding my home lab, which involves pull all old servers out of the rack and replacing them with new ones&amp;hellip; It also means rewriting the network, possibly upgrading some existing gear and hopefully getting the whole lot done on a budget of some sort&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why? Well, biggest reason for all this is currently heat and power usage. We use about 4-6x more electricity than the average house here in Ireland, which means our electricity bill is fairly high. It also means that the lab, which is also my office/bedroom, gets quite warm and uncomfortable during the summer month. There is an Air-Con unit in the room, and, well, that&amp;rsquo;s costing the most on electricity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what I got is a basic overview of what I want from the homelab and hopefully in the next post, I will have an idea of what it will look like..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-4 machines running a Hyper Visor (HyperV, VMWare ESXi or other). Leaning more towards Hyper-V purely because its what I got currently and its what we use in our main office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each machine should be connected to at least 2 networks: one for storage and migration, one for &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; to the LAN. There may be more VLANs for other networks, but 2 is a start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ideally, 10Gb connections would be nice, but multiple 1Gb connections would also work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shared storage (iSCSI, SMB3, etc) would also be a nice to have, but may bump up the server count (not actually a problem) but would increase power and cooling costs. An off the shelf box, like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.synology.com&#34;&gt;Synology&lt;/a&gt; could do the job&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower power usage and less heat produced is also a major requirement. Most of the boxes I am decommissioning are older Xeon hardware (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/family/28144/Intel-Xeon-Processor-5000-Sequence#@All&#34;&gt;5000&lt;/a&gt; series upto a &lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/series/33092/Intel-Xeon-Processor-5200-Series#@All&#34;&gt;5200&lt;/a&gt; series process and even an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xeon#Netburst-based_Xeon&#34;&gt;older Xeon P4&lt;/a&gt;!). The newer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.ie/content/www/ie/en/processors/xeon/xeon-processor-e3-family.html&#34;&gt;Xeon E3&lt;/a&gt; and the even newer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.ie/content/www/ie/en/processors/xeon/xeon-processor-d-family.html&#34;&gt;Xeon D&lt;/a&gt; are a lot more efficient, use less power, produce less heat and are way faster than what I currently have. The E3 can use up to 32Gb of RAM and the Xeon D top out at 128Gb&amp;hellip; Me being me would like more than 32Gb RAM&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smaller machines would also be nice. I have been looking at both Xeon D and Xeon E3 Mini-ITX boards and cases for them. I do have a half height Dell Rack, which I host these machines, and ideally, these machines should be rack mountable, but micro ATX cases could work. 2 per shelf would work grand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboard IPMI and KVM support is something I want too&amp;hellip; I do have a KVMoIP switch in the house, and it works, most of the time, but getting a box that has this embedded into the board would be ideal&amp;hellip; A lot of the server boards had it as standard or allowed it to be speced, so that&amp;rsquo;s all good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am also thinking of upgrading the router to a similar spec board&amp;hellip; Possibly a Xeon E3, or even an i5&amp;hellip;. Ideally it should have IPMI and KVMoIP on board and should produce less heat. Biggest issues is getting enough network cards into the box&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are my requirements at a  high level overview. Over time things may change, but lets see how we get on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RouterOS Dynamic IP Updates</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_dynamic_ip_updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 10:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_dynamic_ip_updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mikrotik.com&#34;&gt;MikroTik&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB750G&#34;&gt;RouterBoard RB750&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, and i love it! Over the weekend, i upgraded it to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB1100&#34;&gt;RB1100&lt;/a&gt;. Its the same software running the device, but the device is faster (800Mhz PowerPC chip VS MIPS-BE at 680Mhz), has more memory (512Mb upgradable to 1.5Gb vs 32Mb) and more storage (think its 512Mb on board, plus 4Gb MicroSD card vs 32mb&amp;hellip;). It also has more ports (13 GigE VS 5) and 2 Switch Groups, which i have no idea what they do just yet&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, part of getting the RB1100 online and taking over from my existing router was getting Dynamic DNS updating. I use both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dyndns.org&#34;&gt;Dyndns&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://no-ip.com&#34;&gt;NoIP&lt;/a&gt; for DNS, but I also like the look of &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;Amazon Route 53&lt;/a&gt;. For updating NoIP, I am using the Alternitive script from &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Dynamic_DNS_Update_Script_for_No-IP_DNS&#34;&gt;The Mikrotik Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. To get this to work with DynDNS, it would just be a matter of chaning the URL you point to&amp;hellip; I am going to write a web script which will sit internally on the network, use that instead of the No-IP url. When that script gets called, i can log the info, update DynDNS, NoIP and Router53 all in one go. I will be posting more about that soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we are on the topic of Scripting RouterOS, checkout the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Scripts&#34;&gt;Mikrotik Script Example Page&lt;/a&gt;. Lots of good stuff up there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPS and Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/gps_and_raspberry_pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 16:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/gps_and_raspberry_pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Need to add GPS to your Raspberry Pi? &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/547/how-do-i-attach-a-gps-receiver&#34;&gt;How do i attach a GPS to a Raspberry&lt;/a&gt; answers your question!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi now with 512MB RAM, other random links...</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_now_with_512mb_ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 12:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_now_with_512mb_ram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier on today, the Raspberry Pi Foundation announced that the Model B will now be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/archives/2180&#34;&gt;shipping with 512Mb RAM as standard&lt;/a&gt;, with no price change. I posted the link up on &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4654251&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and its caused quite a lot of happy people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with the news of extra RAM, its started making me think of more things the Pi could be used for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Austrian hosting company &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edis.at/en/server/colocation/austria/raspberrypi/&#34;&gt;are offering free Co-Location for Raspberry Pis&lt;/a&gt; with a 100Mb/s uplink and 100Gb bandwidth! FREE! with 512Mb RAM (or even 256Mb RAM) thats enough for a small site. or even a medium site (like this one) running statically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2012/07/3g-internet-on-raspberry-pi-success/&#34;&gt;Pi can connect to the internet using 3G&lt;/a&gt;, you could install a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org/&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; and use an SSH tunnel back to your main office or home, have have multiple levels of caching going on&amp;hellip; It would also secure your browsing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2012/06/raspberry-pi-python-and-3g-dongles-oh-my/&#34;&gt;Sending SMS messages though the Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; could be useful for sending diagnostic info if the device is remote&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[XBMC on the Raspberry Pi] would make your media center a lot smaller, use less power, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;just a note on the idea of using 3G and Squid for the Pi&amp;hellip; This is something i am interested in, so its something i want to start playing with. The idea would be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have a linux box in house with Squid and SSH enabled, and port forward SSH to the linux box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tell the pi, on boot, to try and connect to a 3G connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once connection is live, connect to SSH tunnel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squid should already be configued to load and use the upstream Squid box as an upstream cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;local squid should use some storage on either USB or SD for local cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, using something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt; on both ends should make things faster also&amp;hellip; Having the Pi, a 3G modem, USB key (optional) and a battery pack, all in a small box, with a Wifi Adapter, should give you a faster mobile internet connection&amp;hellip; And if you could get 2 or more 3G modems (using a Powered USB Hub of some sort), you could do load balancing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more raspberry pi and camera antics</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more_raspberry_pi_and_camera_antics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 15:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more_raspberry_pi_and_camera_antics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/09/06/Rasberry-Stuff.html&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, and in the post was a link to a Photographer who was &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidhunt.ie/?p=2641&#34;&gt;embeding a Raspberry Pi into a Canon 5D MKII battery grip&lt;/a&gt;. Well, its been a while, and i have been thinking about the Pi and Cameras, so I went looking around&amp;hellip; Here is what i found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://islandinthenet.com/2012/08/23/hdr-photography-with-raspberry-pi-and-gphoto2/&#34;&gt;HDR Photography with a Raspberry Pi and GPhoto2&lt;/a&gt;: It was linked at the end of David&amp;rsquo;s post, and i missed it completely. David mentions he was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gphoto.org/proj/gphoto2/&#34;&gt;GPhoto2&lt;/a&gt; to take photos from the Pi, so its a good place to start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://skowron.biz/artikel/gphoto-raspberry/&#34;&gt;GPhoto2 and the Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;: starters guide on getting the Pi to talk to your Camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not specifically Pi+Camera released, but the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/&#34;&gt;Stackoverflow Raspberry Pi Page&lt;/a&gt; is a handy resource for asking questions&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing i have not been able to figure out is how to tell the Pi to take the photos out of the camera &lt;strong&gt;wihtout having a monitor plugged in&lt;/strong&gt;. I was thinking either tell it, on boot, to start monitoring the camera and download everything. This way, if you have it plugged into a external power source, it will be monitoring and downloading to somewhere&amp;hellip; USB HDD, USB Key, etc. If there is a Wifi spot around, try uploading them to a location, posibily manageable via web interface of some sort&amp;hellip; Lots of interesting ideas can be done&amp;hellip; its just a matter of doing them&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Stuff</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/rasberry-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/rasberry-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple months back, I got my hands on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, a tiny development board that can run a full copy of Linux, has a HDMI port, a couple USB ports, Ethernet and a few other little bits and pieces. The full specs, from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raspberry_Pi&#34;&gt;Wikipedia Article&lt;/a&gt; are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating system: Linux (Debian GNU/Linux, Fedora, and Arch Linux ARM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power: 2.5 W (model A), 3.5 W (model B)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU: ARM1176JZF-S (armv6k) 700 MHz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage capacity: SD card slot (SD or SDHC card)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory: 256 MByte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphics: Broadcom VideoCore IV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a few things i have wanted to play with it for, but have not implemented all them yet&amp;hellip; still learning&amp;hellip; but some interesting projects have come to my attention&amp;hellip; here they are, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://davidhunt.ie/?p=2641&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi embedded into a Canon 5D MKII Battery Grip&lt;/a&gt;: The idea of this is epic! the possibilities are endless&amp;hellip; GPS, Wifi, FTP, Processing RAW images (ok, maybe not with a 700Mhz processor&amp;hellip;), auto upload to the internet, auto add watermark, resize images before upload, send to iPad&amp;hellip; I could go on and on&amp;hellip;. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://liliputing.com/2012/08/raspberry-pi-mini-pc-crammed-into-a-keyboard.html&#34;&gt;Embedding a Raspberry Pi into a Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;: this is pretty cool too&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/phpBB3/viewtopic.php?f=26&amp;amp;t=12017&amp;amp;p=129471#p129471&#34;&gt;Quick setup of a Web Server on the Raspberry PI&lt;/a&gt;: Install Apache, SSH, PHP, MySQL and an FTP server, all on your Pi!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all fairness, the Pi makes a lot of ideas possible. with such a small size, and such a cheap price ($25-35), you are only limited by your imagination&amp;hellip; Wonder could i get Windows 8 installed on one of these&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there are also a few interesting things that may make the Pi work more portable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seeedstudio.com/depot/lipo-rider-pro-p-992.html?cPath=155&#34;&gt;LiPo Rider Pro&lt;/a&gt;: takes input from Batteries and Solar Panels and outputs as USB 5V. should run the Pi off solar and batteries for a while&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
