<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tags/tutorial.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2019 Tiernan OToole</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 16:40:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto deploying to multiple servers with GitHub and Webhooks</title>
      <link>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2018/07/05/auto-deploying-to-multiple-servers-with-github-and-webhooks.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 16:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2018/07/05/auto-deploying-to-multiple-servers-with-github-and-webhooks.html</guid>
      <description>In yesterdays post, i mentioned that i wanted to try get an auto deploy working for this site. It already builds automagically using Forestry and puts the static HTML into a Github repo, but i needed to manually update the servers hosting the site&amp;hellip; Well, not any more!
using the magic of Github&amp;rsquo;s Web hooks, the Webhook project and a small piece of bash shell script, i have managed to get this auto deploying&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed S3 data storage using Minio (and Zerotier)</title>
      <link>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2017/01/19/distributed-s3-storage-minio-zerotier.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2017/01/19/distributed-s3-storage-minio-zerotier.html</guid>
      <description>So, something i have been looking into in recient times has been Distributed Storage, and, more specifically, how to use the storage in my many, many machines to protect data, and also increese my usable space&amp;hellip; There are a few projects on the market that do this (Ceph, NooBaa and Gluster all spring to mind) but some are more painful to setup than others&amp;hellip; which brings me nicely to Minio. Minio is a 20ish MB executable you download from their site, mark it as executable (on Linux or Mac Boxes) and run&amp;hellip; and you have yourself a S3 compatable storage server&amp;hellip; Simples!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>