<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 22:55:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>AS204994, Own IP Space and Anycast</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/as204994-own-ip-space-and-anycast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 22:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/as204994-own-ip-space-and-anycast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, if you are reading this page, it is being delivered with the magic of Anycast&amp;hellip; Well, technically, it was before, since i used &lt;a href=&#34;http://cloudflare.com&#34;&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;, and it still is because of Cloudflare, but also because of my own ASN (&lt;a href=&#34;http://as204994.net&#34;&gt;As204994&lt;/a&gt;), some servers in different locations, and some magic, which i will explain a bit of in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all started late last year when i got my hands on an ASN and a /48 block of IPv6 addresses. I had been reading stuff about BGP, routing, etc, and decided to go all in. it was quite cheap with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.hostus.us/aff.php?aff=2152&#34;&gt;HostUS&lt;/a&gt;. All in, it was about $50 for the year. As part of the process, i needed 2 upstream providers to say they would accept my announcement. They were &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.he.net&#34;&gt;Hurricane Electric&lt;/a&gt; though their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tunnelbroker.com&#34;&gt;Tunnel Broker&lt;/a&gt; service, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vultr.com/?ref=6925432&#34;&gt;Vultr &lt;/a&gt;using a few of their VPSs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After i got my space and ASN, i started to announce the V6 addresses over Vultr and Hurricane Electric, and all was good. I had 2 Vultr servers: 1 in London, UK, and one in New Jersey, USA. I had my home machine announce to HE, and then also link to both Vultr servers using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zerotier.com&#34;&gt;Zerotier&lt;/a&gt;. All worked well, but due to some family issues, i never got around to putting it into production&amp;hellip; till now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those 3 servers now share an IPv6 address on the loopback port. When you (well, Cloudflare) asks for that IP, the closet (network) with that IP responds, and the NGinx server on that box sends back the contents of the site. This site is hosted on each box, since its fully static, but both &lt;a href=&#34;https://as204994.net&#34;&gt;AS204994 &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&#34;https://tiernanotoole.net&#34;&gt;TiernanOToole.net&lt;/a&gt; are hosted in Ghost, so Dublin (my machine in the house) serves them, and both Lon1 and Nyc1 do proxying. so, most requests from the US are hitting the box in NYC and the ones in Europe share either Dub1 or Lon1. I have some tweaks to do with which servers will be running where, and may add more, but currently its working well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you figure out what server responded? Simple. Open your Dev tools on your browser, go to network tab, refresh, and see the response headers for anything on this domain. You should see something like below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/uploads/2018/04/01/responding-server.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next while, i will be updating tiernanotoole.net with more details on how this works, and more stuff will end up on AS204994.net too. If anyone notices any weird and wonderful issues, shout. If you have more questions, shout.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zerotier and Minio Followup</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zerotier-minio-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zerotier-minio-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2017/01/19/distributed-s3-storage-minio-zerotier.html&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about setting up a distributed S3 like data storage system using &lt;a href=&#34;https://minio.io/&#34;&gt;Minio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zerotier.com/&#34;&gt;ZeroTier&lt;/a&gt;. Well, this week, the ZeroTier guys tweeted about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Distributed S3 data storage using &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Minio&#34;&gt;@minio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ZeroTier?src=hash&#34;&gt;#ZeroTier&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MAXTjo3muh&#34;&gt;https://t.co/MAXTjo3muh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; ZeroTier, Inc. (@ZeroTier) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ZeroTier/status/859557214997970944&#34;&gt;May 2, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few people then started asking questions, and looking for a follow up, so here it is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, a quick recap. I had 4 machines, all running Linux. Three of them were in 1 time zone (GMT+1) and one was in another (GMT). Looking at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.minio.io/docs/distributed-minio-quickstart-guide&#34;&gt;Distributed Minio Quickstart Guide&lt;/a&gt; again, there is a mention of times being in sync&amp;hellip; which is probably why this did not work as planned&amp;hellip; and by &amp;ldquo;not work as planed&amp;rdquo;, I mean that Minio would crash, or not be responsive, or not write data in the place it should have&amp;hellip; which was a pain. But looking at the documentation again, they do mention that Windows support is &amp;ldquo;experimental&amp;rdquo; which means, hopefully, some day it will be not so experimental, and might work&amp;hellip; Given that most of my machines in house are Windows boxes, this would be a nice feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what about ZeroTier? Given they posted it to their twitter? Well, it worked. it did the inter connect stuff well, and, given bandwidth limitations on a home broadband connection, it was still quite fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the question is, how fast? Well, on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/surfacebook.html&#34;&gt;Surface Book&lt;/a&gt; on a WiFi connection in the house, behind a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meraki.com&#34;&gt;Meraki&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;MX64&lt;/a&gt; firewall, connecting to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/GodBoxV2.html&#34;&gt;the GodBoxV2&lt;/a&gt; over FTP though ZeroTier, i get the following result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/ftpdownload-zerotier.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/ftpdownload-zerotier-rs.png&#34; alt=&#34;FTP over ZeroTier&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the same download over FTP direct (no ZeroTier) does the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/ftpdownload-direct.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/ftpdownload-direct-rs.png&#34; alt=&#34;FTP direct&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, direct over FTP is faster&amp;hellip; in this instance by about 70%, but, over the download, it did get slower (seen it hit 12 at one stage) and because its over WiFi, those are a bit wonky&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did get one last screen shot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/networkspeed.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2017/05/05/networkseed-rs.png&#34; alt=&#34;network speed&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as you can see, the Zerotier network adapter is showing 77.3Mbps, but the main network adapter is showing 80.8Mbps. There would be other traffic there, but if we assume there is nothing but ZeroTier traffic being sent, there is about 5% of an overhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to wrap up: Minio and its distributed storage system over ZeroTier needs more testing. Ideally, all hosts need to be in the same time zone, or at least have the same time&amp;hellip; Will try work on that soon. As for ZeroTier? I am extremely happy with them. Its fast, easy to setup, and easy to configure. What more could you ask for? Oh, and free, unless you need a pro account!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Class Broadband... finally here....</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/business-class-broadband/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/business-class-broadband/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, after many (MANY) years messing with dual cable modems, struggling to get them working together, to get websites to even allow me in, having to use hacks and kluges to get it to work at all&amp;hellip; I have given up. It has been a struggle getting two modems working properly. Load blanching &lt;em&gt;kind&lt;/em&gt; of works&amp;hellip; but it&amp;rsquo;s messy at best. Some sites kick you out every now and again because your IP changes. Some sites wont let you login at all&amp;hellip; Mind you, some sites work grand and don&amp;rsquo;t ask questions&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the whole idea of multiple modems, to allow you to download things faster, doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for everything&amp;hellip; Anything you download in the browser is single threaded, so its limited to one modem&amp;hellip; you can use use download accelerators, and they do work, but its an extra step, and some sites don&amp;rsquo;t work for that either (MSDN for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, i have given up, bit the bullet, and moved to business class broadband from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virginmedia.ie/business/&#34;&gt;Virgin Media&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s actually cheaper than the two residential lines i had, but it is also slower than the two combined: previously, it was two x 360/36mb/s. Now i am am on a single 400/40mb/s modem. That being said, there are definite advantages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static IPs pretty much as standard, and option of either one or five (no unbeaten!) Guess which one i went with? Its &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; a /29 range, but the first usable IP is given to the modem, which acts as a gateway, so i end up with five usable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proper business class SLA. Any issues, someone who knows what they are talking about can help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone lines on a separate modem. So, i got phone lines with them, and they give a separate modem for those lines, so as not to interfere with the internet. that modem has no internet connection and is just for calls. They are also working on a VoIP/SIP offering, which is something i am interested in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guaranteed speed! They guarantee a minimum speed to the modem at all time. Business customers have a priority on the network, which is nice. And, during testing, so far, i am getting the advertised speed most of the time. I needed to download a Windows 10 ISO yesterday from the MSDN, and it came in at between 45 and 48MBytes/s!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, only had it installed a week, and so far, so good. I have one IP given to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSesne&lt;/a&gt; box, and the rest given to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vyos.io&#34;&gt;VyOS&lt;/a&gt; VM. The plan is to use the VyOS box for all network traffic, but first i need to do some testing and learning&amp;hellip; Expect some posts on this soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 9 - Going Back</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-9-going-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-9-going-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 9 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the double internet experiment is about ready to be finished&amp;hellip; After 9 posts, 4 months, lots of sweating, many painful nights trying to figure out why something stopped using, shouting when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netflix.com&#34;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; did not work, wondering why my internet connection was so slow, and many, many other problems, i have decided to wind down the project. in the last 9 posts, i have learned a lot, and i hope i have helped someone figure out some stuff on their end. Even though this is a wind up of the project, there are still new things i have to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found another project that has potential for speeding up the internet: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vrayo.com/how-to-set-up-a-bonding-vpn-connection-in-linux/&#34;&gt;VTrunkd&lt;/a&gt;. after some testing, i does seem to manage to speed up the connection, but either limits on hardware i have in house, or limits of hardware in the cloud, or even the software, stopped me in my tracks&amp;hellip; i did see 400mb/s out of it at one stage, using 200mb/s from each modem&amp;hellip; its close, but its not the full 720&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;messing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga/Zebra&lt;/a&gt; as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/06/08/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around.html&#34;&gt;the previous post&lt;/a&gt; has been, well, interesting&amp;hellip; I did manage to get all &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.ie&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt; traffic sent though their server, &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; traffic sent over that box, and everything else over &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;. I added an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azure.com&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; box to the mix for a while, aswell as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vultr.com/?ref=6925433&#34;&gt;Vultr&lt;/a&gt; box, but it got very messey, very quickly. if i had something automated, it would be better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the idea of having a /29 IP range in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; and forwarding it though the tunnels back to the house did work. My &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;Meraki MX64&lt;/a&gt; had one IP address, i had a mail server on a second, everything else on a third, and was planning on using more&amp;hellip; but its just, well, again, messy. So, i will be going back to the idea of 2 IP addresses, and hoping whatever i put infront of the network can figure stuff out&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what am i moving to? well, thats a question&amp;hellip; Currently, i have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;Meraki MX64&lt;/a&gt; plugged directly into the modems, and protecting my LAN. So far, so good, but due to hardware limits, it maxes out at around 260mb/s. So, thats out of the question for the main network! I did at one stage have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en/products/free-tools/sophos-utm-home-edition.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM Home edition&lt;/a&gt; running. Sophos also have their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/free-tools/sophos-xg-firewall-home-edition.aspx&#34;&gt;XG firewall&lt;/a&gt; available for home use, so i might try that&amp;hellip; There is also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pfsense.org/&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; which i used before also&amp;hellip; And there may be more&amp;hellip; Maybe there will be a new series reviewing these home firewalls? we will see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meraki and Ubiquiti networks gear Update</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/meraki-gear-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/meraki-gear-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/05/17/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition.html&#34;&gt;part 6&lt;/a&gt; of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;Double Internet Series&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned i was running a &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/&#34;&gt;Meraki&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;MX64&lt;/a&gt; in the network, and said i would write up about it. I am taking this oppertunity to also write up about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubnt.com&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti networks&lt;/a&gt; gear in the house also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First on the list is my older &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti Edgerouter POE&lt;/a&gt;. It currently in the process of being decommissioned, or used for something else. It was the main edge router for the network: it had both internet connections connected, and did routing, firewalls, etc, but with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/proliantml110.html&#34;&gt;Proliant&lt;/a&gt; taking over as a router, it is not requried as much any more&amp;hellip; Its still on, mainly because its still a DHCP server, but not much else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/switches/ms220-8&#34;&gt;Meraki MS220-8&lt;/a&gt; switches next. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/godbox.html&#34;&gt;GodBox1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/GodBoxV2.html&#34;&gt;Godbox2&lt;/a&gt; both connect in here, and are bonded, as is everything else on the network. The MS220-8 has 8 GigE ports, but also has 2 SFP ports. I bought 4 SFP Ethernet adapters and have a short calbe running between the switches. That uplink is also bonded. All going well so far!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All meraki hardware can be managed though the meraki dashboard. check out their site for more details and examples of how to use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bought one of the MS220&amp;rsquo;s from ebay a few months back, and loved it. Then i realized that you can get your hands on free gear, the MX64, an MS220 and a Wifi Access point if you attend their &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/webinars&#34;&gt;webinars&lt;/a&gt;. Terms and conditions apply, but check them out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/unifi/unifi-ap/&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti UniFi APs&lt;/a&gt;, one in the front of the house, one in the back. They are connected to one of the MS220&amp;rsquo;s, but dont work with its POE (maybe the EdgeRouter could do that, since its POE&amp;hellip;) so there are injectors for them. Anyway, the network ports on there are VLANed to the MX64 (more on that later) and the detault traffic is going to a management VLAN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;MX64&lt;/a&gt; has a static internal IP on my DMZ network, and uses the Proliant as an upstream connection. Upstream on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; server, all traffic coming from the MX64 ip uses one of my /29 ip block. all traffic to that ip is also forwarded directly to the MX64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I has 2 small, unmanaged switches (a cheap 8 port Linksys and a 8 port TP Link) which are used for seperate things: the Linksys has 4 Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s, which run a [GlusterFS] cluster, plugged into it and the TP Link connects to my printers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/CRS226-24G-2SplusIN&#34;&gt;Mikrotik CRS226-24G-2S+IN&lt;/a&gt; which has 2 10Gbit SFP+ Ports, and plan on using this for higher speed networking soon, aswell as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/switches/catalyst-3560-series-switches/index.html&#34;&gt;Cisco 48 port 3560&lt;/a&gt; which also has 4 SFP ports (GigE) and may come in handy for something soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thats the network currently. any questions, please leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 8 - Routing Around</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 8 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/05/31/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of.html&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I asked the question about routing traffic to different servers based on thier distances, etc&amp;hellip; Well, after a bit of messing, i can say it kind of works! here is a quick over view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;server in the house has now got multiple OpenVPN connections (2 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;, 1 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.ie&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt; (with a plan to double), 1 to &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; (again, to be doubled) and i am planning 2 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azure.com&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; as well).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga/Zebra&lt;/a&gt; has static routes (currently static, planing on dynamic soon&amp;hellip; more eventually) to different servers depending on where they are. for example, all traffic to the hetzner network (including their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hetzner.de/en/hosting/produktmatrix/storagebox-produktmatrix&#34;&gt;Storage Boxes&lt;/a&gt;) go though the hetzner link. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hubic.com&#34;&gt;Hubic&lt;/a&gt; traffic goes though OVH, Azure (currently) and AWS traffic, aswell as some CDNs go direct over either WAN1 or WAN2 in the house, and some other stuff (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crashplan.com&#34;&gt;CrashPlan&lt;/a&gt; currently) goes though Digital Ocean. Everything that has no static route goes though Hetzner&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally, the static side of things should be removed, and a more dynamic setup done. How that works, i have no idea&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spotify.com&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; have 2 posts about their SDN Internet Router (&lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.spotify.com/2016/01/26/sdn-internet-router-part-1/&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.spotify.com/2016/01/27/sdn-internet-router-part-2/&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;) which is an interesting idea&amp;hellip; More digging and research is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. Everything currently seems to be working, mostly, and tweaks can be made easily&amp;hellip; I have a couple posts i have in my head, including something to do with automating bringing up new machines (probably with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ansible.com/&#34;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; or something like it), more monitoring, and some other stuff too&amp;hellip; Any questions, leave a comment, and i will get back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[UPDATE] I wrote a quick and dirty app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/whoistozebraconfig&#34;&gt;WhoIsToZebraConfig&lt;/a&gt; which takes an AS Number, looks up the info in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radb.net/&#34;&gt;Merit RADb&lt;/a&gt; (with the help of some code from &lt;a href=&#34;https://coderbuddy.wordpress.com/2010/10/12/a-simple-c-class-to-get-whois-information/&#34;&gt;Coder Buddy&lt;/a&gt;) and outputs what you need to put into your Zebra Config&amp;hellip; should save me some time, and it might save you time too&amp;hellip;  shout if you have questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 7 - ECMP (kind of)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 7 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/05/17/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition.html&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned I am now using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; for hosting a dedicated box. Thats still live, and going well. I have a /29 IP range (6 usable) and also 2 other IPs. So far, so good&amp;hellip; But because i was using a Socks Server, I was not fully able to use the /29 ips&amp;hellip; I use something like as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/68894593dd44acb4820617aef2889fd6.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;essentially, for each public IP i have that i want to map to an internal IP, i have a POST and PRE ROUTING rule, plus the required forward rules&amp;hellip; But, if socks are used, then that goes out the Window, since TCP traffic will look like its coming from the socks server&amp;hellip; So, i killed the socks server, removed the IPTables rule, and then realized that while outgoing traffic was being balanced somewhat (2 default rules on the internal box pointing at the OpenVPN IPs from the Hetzner box) incoming was a problem. Hetzner knew how to get to my internal network, but only though one ip&amp;hellip; enter Quagga and Zebra&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga&lt;/a&gt; is a routing software suite, which can do protocols like OSPF, BGP and RIP, and Zebra is the component that does static routing. using their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/docs/docs-info.html#Static-Route-Commands&#34;&gt;documentation on static routes&lt;/a&gt;, I created a static route to my internal network with 2 next hops, the OVPN IPs from the internal box&amp;hellip; and, after restarting Quagga, all works! happy days! now i can forward ips from outside the network to inside the network correctly, and they look like they are the public ip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, whats next then? well, I now have a server in Germany (Hetzner) and one in France (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.com&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt;), and can spin one up in the UK or the US (&lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;). Given that i have Quagga running on the box, i am now thinking of trying to see if its possible to route traffic depending on distance or something similar&amp;hellip; If i am trying to hit a server in Hetzner&amp;rsquo;s DC, i should go though Germany. If its in Digital Ocean, go though either US or UK servers, same with OVH. Then figure out who has the fastest links to, say, Amazon, Azure, Netflix, BBC, Dropbox, etc, and add either static or dynamic links to the router&amp;hellip; essentially, thats the theory&amp;hellip; lets see how that works&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 6 - Hetzner Edition</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 6 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its been a while, since I posted, and there are some, well, pretty major changes since the last time&amp;hellip; Lets start are the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; for my hosting provider. I was using their $20 a month server (2 cores, 2GB RAM, 40GB SSD, 3TB transfer), and it was all good&amp;hellip; But I noticed that every now and again I would need to reboot the box. I also noticed that when transferring large files or using higher bandwidth (400mb/s+) the 100% of both cores were being used. So, I wanted to move to something with more power&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also was limited to IP addresses. Yes, Digital Ocean do offer IPv6, but I could only get 1 IPv4 address&amp;hellip; and I wanted more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I went back to some old friends of mine, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;, and bought a dedicated server with a Quad Core Xeon E3, 32GB RAM, 4*3 TB HDDs, 1Gbit/s network connection with 30TB transfer per month and a KVMoIP plugged in. I also got 2 extra standard IPs and a /29 (8 IPs, 6 usable). I will explain that next. I installed Debian 8.4 on the first disk, and I am planning on using the other 3 for storage of some sort. I then installed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multipath-tcp.org&#34;&gt;MPTCP kernel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt;, Squid and a Socks server (same as the Digital Ocean box) and reconfigured the home machine&amp;hellip; All good! Now when browsing the web, everywhere thinks I am in Germany, but so far, so good&amp;hellip; Speed tests are about the same, but I have my theory about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equal-cost_multi-path_routing&#34;&gt;ECMP&lt;/a&gt; to try this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the extra IPs, I am working on doing full IP forwarding, not just port forwarding. One of my IPs in pointing directly at my &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;Meraki MX64&lt;/a&gt; in house (a post on the Meraki stuff is coming, eventually&amp;hellip;) and another at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/proliantml110.html&#34;&gt;Proliant box&lt;/a&gt;, and I plan on pointing other IPs at machines in the DMZ or a firewall of some sort. the /29 is routed though the IP pointing at the Proliant, so that makes life easier. The original IP is only used for SSH and OVPN from the house. it should not do much else. All network traffic in house is coming from other of the other IPs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, so far, so good. Hopefully the ECMP stuff works correctly, so I will do an updated post soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Mad) Max Speed - The Road Warrior (Internet connection) (double speed internet Part 5)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 5 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is going to be an update and theoretical post. probably very little &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; stuff going on here, mostly updates, and what I am planning on doing later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.technet.com/b/exchange/archive/2004/07/12/180899.aspx&#34;&gt;OOF&lt;/a&gt; sick, so I have not done much work, but I have been surfing the web, watching videos, downloading stuff, etc., so I have an idea of how things are going. First, as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/04/14/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4.html&#34;&gt;the previous post&lt;/a&gt; I have MPTCP, Squid, Socks Servers, OpenVPN and IPTables doing their magic. 2 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt; tunnels between the house and &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;. All TCP Traffic (bar port 80) is sent over socks to the box in the cloud using RedSocks. All UDP traffic is sent direct over OpenVPN. Since MPTCP is in the mix, all socks traffic is actually split over the 2 connections. All port 80 traffic, and 443 (if the client is using local Squid as their proxy) is sent round-robin between the 2 upstream IPs to Squid (2 OpenVPN end points).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I have noticed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every now and again, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/darkk/redsocks&#34;&gt;RedSocks&lt;/a&gt; crashes&amp;hellip; just full on dies. It’s just a matter of starting again, but it’s a pain&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have had to restart squid a couple of times&amp;hellip; not too often though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was a power outage in the house a few days back&amp;hellip; so, when everything came back online, it was a bit of a pain bringing all connections back to life. I do have to figure out a better plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have to read more on this ECMP stuff. Hopefully it will do what I am hoping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the theoretical stuff. I started thinking, could this work outside the house? Could you build this into something smaller, like a Raspberry Pi, and stick 2 or more USB Modems in, connect it back to a server in the cloud, setup P2P OpenVPN connections and then get more than a single modem speed download? The problems I can see are around MPTCP. I am not sure if it has been ported to ARM to run on a Raspberry Pi. Second, the max you could ever get out of it is 100Mbit/s, given the 10/100mb network port on board&amp;hellip; and you may need extra power for the USB dongles. Also, getting P2P connections may be complicated, given the non-static IPs on the modems, though, in theory, non-P2P OpenVPN could work&amp;hellip; Again, it’s a theory. I had the though and that’s where the title came from&amp;hellip; anyway, throwing it out there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable Modems = Double Speed? Part 4</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 4 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double%Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this week I went in a completely different direction that I have been thinking recently&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the basic theory is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am still using MPTCP kernels on both upstream and local machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;now have 2 P2P UDP &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt; tunnels between house and cloud. Example config is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/09c6928d1d8f6752ea84fd895451bbe5&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all TCP traffic (bar port 80) that hits the router in house is redirected to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/darkk/redsocks&#34;&gt;RedSocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RedSocks uses a socks server, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inet.no/dante/&#34;&gt;Dante&lt;/a&gt;, as an upstream server on the cloud box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;since the socks traffic is over TCP (inside the UDP OpenVPN tunnel) it uses MPTCP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;having socks running, gives me quite the download speed, turning it off does not, hence the following tweet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Hmmmm&amp;hellip; If I have socks on, the Internet is fast 400mb/s+). But without socks, it&amp;#39;s down to 60&amp;hellip; Feck&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tiernan (@tiernano) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tiernano/status/720186883905626112&#34;&gt;April 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am also noticing that I am starting to hit the limits of my upstream VM. If downloading or uploading at speed, the processor cores (2 in the case of the box I am currently running) are pegged at pretty much 100% full&amp;hellip; Well, 80ish, but that because the other 20% is being used by Dante. I am noticing I can hit a full 72Mbit/s up, but the max currently downloading is about 400, maybe 450&amp;hellip; Need a faster box now&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I mentioned port 80 not being set over socks. That&amp;rsquo;s because its redirected to Squid. Squid (in house) then uses Squid (in cloud) as a parent. There are 2 round-robin parents for squid, one on each OpenVPN connection IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all other traffic (UDP, ICMP, etc.) are sent over the OpenVPN connection&amp;hellip; currently only one is picked, but I have a cunning plan&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube AsXKS8Nyu8Q %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cunning plan? Well, if I am reading the internet correctly, and I would like to think I am, I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equal-cost_multi-path_routing&#34;&gt;ECMP&lt;/a&gt;, or Equal Cost Multi-Path Routing, could help&amp;hellip; Again, it’s a fledgling idea currently, and I am still reading the documentation, but if it works&amp;hellip; Well&amp;hellip; I not sure&amp;hellip; let’s see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable modems = Double speed? Part 3</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 3 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/22/2-Cable-Modems-Double-Internet-Speed-part1.html&#34;&gt;Part 1 of this series&lt;/a&gt; I explained the why and what I wanted to do for this &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo;. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/30/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2.html&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; I did some basic testing of both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multipath-tcp.org&#34;&gt;MPTCP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://zehome.github.io/MLVPN&#34;&gt;MLVPN&lt;/a&gt;. I also mentioned trying &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Point-to-Point_Protocol#PPP_Configuration_Options&#34;&gt;MMPPP&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;http://vtun.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;vtund&lt;/a&gt; but it has been a while since I did that testing, and it had not been on bare metal. So, this post is a follow up, where I am using bare metal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first, the setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ProLiant box is running Debian 8.3 x64, and has both vtund and ppp installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digtial Ocean&lt;/a&gt; box also has Debian 8.3, vtund and ppp installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walked though the guide from &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnlewis.ie/bonding-teaming-internet-connections/&#34;&gt;John Lewis&lt;/a&gt; and made some changes to the configs. the main ones are mentioned below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once done, i installed both iperf and iftop on both boxes, and ran&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iperf -s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the Digital Ocean box and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iperf -c 192.168.10.1 -d
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the local box. And, well, the results where not as expected. Pretty poor actually:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, using Squid installed on the DO box, i tried using WGET to download a file using it. If I did this on the DO box itself, i was getting 100MBytes/s&amp;hellip; When I ran it over the MLPPP box, well, under 7 was achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-downloading-over-mlppp-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-downloading-over-mlppp.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;WGET over Squid over MLPPP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then i though it might have been Squid. So, since the file had been downloaded to DO, i SFTPed into the box over the MLPPP link, and tried again&amp;hellip; Again, pretty poor result. I think i seen it hit about 7MB a sec at one stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp2-over-mlppp-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp2-over-mlppp.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;SFTP over MLPPP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what is showing on the DO box when running the SFTP download. You can see 2 connections from the 2 WAN links at home hitting the box, and they are balanced. Its just nowhere near the speed they are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp-over-mlppp-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp-over-mlppp.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;iftop running on server&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not get a screen shot of this, but when I tried with iperf, thinking it might have been overhead of SFTP or Squid, I was getting results matching what I was seeing with SFTP. Downloads in the 55-60mbit/s range for download and 40ish for upload. 40 is still faster than 1 link, mind you&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned that I had made some minor tweaks to the configs from what John had written. Well, mostly it was config changes to how routing was done. In Johns case, he is bonding a DSL and a HSDPA connection, so he had setup to do for logging into his PPP modem and connecting. Also, when he setup the interfaces, he routing tables in there. I have mine setup in a single config file, like as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/a9a642c4d029c0dcf8beb926b3588991.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have changed the names from adsl1 and 2 to WAN1 and 2, and the IPs are changed from internal IPs to my public IPs. I manually run this when setting up my connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing else on his config files have changed. I did not do any of the masquerading stuff, mainly cause this was testing. I just want a tunnel to start with. When reading the vtund.conf file, you can see that encryption and compression are both turned off, and and the same in the ppp configuration. I also don&amp;rsquo;t think the issue is to do with the CPU performance, since these are the screenshots of top running on both boxes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-server-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-server.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Top on Server&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-client-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-client.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Top on Client&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in both cases, CPU usage is sub 6% for VTUN and SSH seems to be using less than 10%. So, now, I&amp;rsquo;m baffled as to why this is not performing as expected&amp;hellip; More testing required!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[update 4/4/2016] - fixing images so they are clickable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPTCP, SSH, Squid, OpenVPN (and 2 Cable modems) = Double Speed? Not quite... Part 2</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 2 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/22/2-Cable-Modems-Double-Internet-Speed-part1.html&#34;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt; I explained what i was trying to do&amp;hellip; This post explains what i have been working on recently, and performance results&amp;hellip;
So, first, what have i tried&amp;hellip; There are 3 different things i have tried, and here are some of their details. Some will need to be updated (other parts of this series), and others i will try get back to eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware-and-servers-used&#34;&gt;Hardware and servers used&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test this, i am using my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/proliantml110.html&#34;&gt;HP Proliant ML110 G5&lt;/a&gt; running either Ubuntu or Debian Linux, with 2 GigE connections directly to the cable modems, and 1 connection to the LAN (for SSH and testing). The LAN has no gateway set, and the 2 WAN connections have DHCP enabled. They get fully public IP addresses. Upstream, I am using either &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scaleway.com&#34;&gt;ScaleWay&lt;/a&gt; VPS boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Ocean has the advantage of allowing different Kernels, so i have been using them for testing MPTCP. As for ScaleWay, well, their BareMetal C2S/M/L boxes have between 4 and 8 cores (4 for the S, 8 for the M and L) and between 8 and 32Gb RAM (S=8, M=16, L=32GB). The L model also comes with 256GB SSD (plus the boot disk, which seems to be a network disk of some sort) and they all come with lots of bandwidth (i use the L because its got about 800MBit/s to the internet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ping wise, Digital Ocean is about 20-30ms away from the house (I picked London to host the servers) and Scaleway is a little further at about 50ms (They are based in France).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mptcp-multipath-tcp-http-www-multipath-tcp-org&#34;&gt;MPTCP (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multipath-tcp.org&#34;&gt;MultiPath TCP&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MPTCP (their site is a bit wonky as of writing, so bare with me&amp;hellip;) is a Linux Kernel patch that allows TCP connections to use multiple paths&amp;hellip; Essentially, if you have Wifi and 4G in a phone, and MPTCP is enabled, it should allow you to use both connections for TCP traffic, as long as the server upstream supports it. It also allows for easy fail over if, say, you lose your wifi connection. There is an example &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/VWN0ctPi5cw&#34;&gt;video of it on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; which should show the fail over parts and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VMdPI9Cfi9k&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; shows how they managed to get 50Gbit/s out of a 6 10Gb Ethernet connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When i was using MPTCP, I had a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; on both boxes, and told Squid locally to use Squid on the upstream box (over a SSH tunnel, which was over the MPTCP link) as a parent cache. Using this method, i could see (using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ex-parrot.com/pdw/iftop/&#34;&gt;iftop&lt;/a&gt;) that both connections were being used. When trying proper performace testing, I setup a RAM disk on both machines and copied a Linux ISO to the Digtial Ocean Box. Then, using wget and &lt;a href=&#34;http://axel.alioth.debian.org/&#34;&gt;Axel&lt;/a&gt; I downloaded the files using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nginx.com/&#34;&gt;Nginx&lt;/a&gt; on the server, and checked the results. I can max out 1 single connection, plus use about 60-80mbit/s from the second. about 420-440mbit/s total. Disk was not the bottleneck, since I was writing to RAM, so more tests are required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mlvpn&#34;&gt;MLVPN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zehome.github.io/MLVPN&#34;&gt;MLVPN&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty interesting project that caught my eye. The idea is quite simple: you configure the local box and server, as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;http://mlvpn.readthedocs.org/en/latest/linux_example.html&#34;&gt;their example guide&lt;/a&gt; and run the MLVPN program on the server, then the client. It creates 2 VPN tunnels between the 2 boxes, and bonds them&amp;hellip; In my case, i was given an IP of 10.42.42.1 on my box in house and 10.42.42.2 on the server. Any traffic over that tunnel is bonded&amp;hellip; Problem is, it seems to be quite processor intensive: my Digital Ocean box was showing one cpu core (out of 2) maxing out at around 80% and my Proliant in house maxing around the 70% mark&amp;hellip; all while transferring data at around 100mbit/s. I tried iperf and got the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20160330-mlvpn-speed-test.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;mlvpn speed test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;getting 50mbit/s upload is good, in reality, since in theory my max speed would be 72, without overhead. but 116mb/s down is less than a third the max speed of a single connection. So, I tried just uploads and downloads&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upload Only (from local machine to server)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20160330-mlvpn-speed-test-upload-only.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;mlvpn upload only test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download Only (from server to local machine)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20160330-mlvpn-speed-test-download-only.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;mlvpn download only test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the download speed has increased a little, to 176Mbit/s, but the upload speed is now at over 60MBit/s!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still.. download is as important as upload, and given I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to get it to max out one connection, never mind 2, even more testing is required&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mlppp-using-vtun&#34;&gt;MLPPP (using VTUN)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one i need to come back to&amp;hellip; Used the guide from &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnlewis.ie/bonding-teaming-internet-connections/&#34;&gt;John Lewis&lt;/a&gt; but was only managing to get about 100Mbit/s&amp;hellip; I was originally using a VM (so disk may have been the issue) and also had the connection behind my EdgeRouter, so it might have been firewall rules causing a slow down. But I do need to come back to this soon&amp;hellip; Watch this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, at the moment, all I can conclude is that there is more testing required. Upload wise, i can somewhat use most of my bandwidth with MLVPN, and I did see promising results with MPTCP. I gave up a bit too early with MLPPP, so more testing is required with that. Also, all tests are using just iperf between boxes. I did use squid with the MPTCP box for a while, but not for proper performance testing. So, even once this is all sorted out, i will need to turn this into a proper &amp;ldquo;router&amp;rdquo; too&amp;hellip; So, conclusion? this was originally meant to be a 2 parter&amp;hellip; now it looks like I will require a lot more parts&amp;hellip; Watch this space&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable modems = Double Internet Speed? Well... not really... Part 1</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-internet-speed-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-internet-speed-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 1 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, a bit of background, and then I will explain what I am currently running in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/30/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2.html&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 15 or so years, I have had at least 2 internet connections in to the house&amp;hellip; 2 of them have always been Cable Modems from NTL, which became UPC, and now is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virginmedia.ie&#34;&gt;Virgin Media&lt;/a&gt;. When I started, i think the modems where 150/50kbit/s and 600/150kb/s, and have steadily increased in speed, currently at 360/36Mbit/s each&amp;hellip; But they have always been somewhat separate, and single thread downloads have always been limited to 1 of the connections&amp;hellip; I have been looking for ways around this for years&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/routers/rv042-dual-wan-vpn-router/index.html&#34;&gt;Linksys RV042 router&lt;/a&gt; which allowed me to load balance my connections&amp;hellip; At the time, and i cant even remember when this was, my total bandwidth would not exceed the router. The RV042 has 2 10/100mbit WAN links and 4 100mb/s LAN links&amp;hellip;So, when the connection bandwidth increased, I moved to a new router&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next router vendor i tried was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mikrotik.com&#34;&gt;Mikrotik&lt;/a&gt;. I tried a few different options, including an &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB1100&#34;&gt;RB1100&lt;/a&gt; and running their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mikrotik.com/software&#34;&gt;RouterOS&lt;/a&gt; on x86 hardware&amp;hellip; Both worked, well, ok, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Load_Balancing#Nth&#34;&gt;Load balancing with nth&lt;/a&gt; stuff did do what i needed, along with other stuff, like routing traffic destined for some sites (like BBC iPlayer) to go over a VPN. But in the end, hardware issues and performance problems with the x86 machine (Mikrotik at the time was limited to 2GB of RAM on x86 hardware) I ended up at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PfSense&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PfSense was installed on the same hardware, a HP ProLiant ML110 G5 with 8GB RAM, a Core2Quad processor and 12 GigE Network cards&amp;hellip; And, on PfSense, things were good&amp;hellip; Performance was stable, load balancing worked as expected, I could set some traffic to go over certain links, etc. all was good&amp;hellip; But I lacked IPv6&amp;hellip; Plus, the HP used a LOT of power&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current instalment of my network uses a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubnt.com&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti Networks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Edge Router POE&lt;/a&gt;. To show the difference in power, check out the graphs from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/mfi/mpower/&#34;&gt;Ubnt MPower&lt;/a&gt; device. ProLiant first, EdgeRouter second:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-proliant-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Proliant Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-edgerouter-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;EdgeRouter POE Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, the EdgeRouter does not produce as much heat, and its a LOT smaller that the PowerEdge! It does all the same things I could get PfSense to do, in a lot smaller package (I could, in theory, get a smaller box for PfSense).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, where does that leave us? Well, I now have 720Mbit/s down and 72Mbit/s up, if I can do multiple threads for uploading&amp;hellip; But what if I don&amp;rsquo;t? What&amp;rsquo;s next? Well, in the second post, I will explain what I have been trying to do in resent weeks, and what I can do now&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge Router, Sophos UTM, DMZ and LAN Networks</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/edgerouter-sophosutm-dmz-lan-firwwalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/edgerouter-sophosutm-dmz-lan-firwwalls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;EdgeRouer POE&lt;/a&gt; as my main router for most of the network (some of the network still uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; as a router, but thats being removed soon) for the last few weeks, and i am quite happy with it. I also have a second router, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/unified-threat-management.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM&lt;/a&gt; VM between my first LAN (essentially a DMZ) and my client LAN (there will be more &amp;ldquo;LANs&amp;rdquo; over there soon). The Client LAN is NATed between the DMZ and the LAN, which means anything on the LAN i want to access from the DMZ has to be port forwarded&amp;hellip; Ideally, not much from the LAN should be accessible though the DMZ, but in my initial setup, stuff like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plex.tv&#34;&gt;Plex&lt;/a&gt;, etc, is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What i wanted to do was setup a proper firewall between both networks, without the use of NAT&amp;hellip; Do do this, i first had to disable th masquerading rules in Sophos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530620916/20150930-masquerading-off.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next, on the EdgeRouter, i added a static route to point at the new network:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530620916/20150930-static-route.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, under firewall rules, i allowed what i wanted to allow (in this case, SSH from any DMZ client (not advised) to my Mac Mini).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/v1530620916/20150930-firewall-rules.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, as they say, is that! So far, so good!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 4)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, after some messing, tweaking, and thinking, I have made some progress with the home lab&amp;hellip; or at least broken some stuff&amp;hellip; I mentioned previously that i had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2015/08/05/Ubiquiti-EdgeRouter-POE-In-the-lab.html&#34;&gt;Ubiqititi networks EdgeRouter POE&lt;/a&gt; in the home lab. Originally, the plan was to use a Virtual &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; box for my core router&amp;hellip; Given the power usage of the current PfSense Box (I have 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/mfi/mpower/&#34;&gt;MPower Pro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s watching power in the lab) I am now thinking of moving to just the EdgeRouter for, well, edge routing&amp;hellip;  below is the usage of the ProLiant for the last 12 hours or so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-proliant-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Proliant Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for the same period, here is the usage for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Edge Router&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2015/09/16/20150916-edgerouter-power-usage.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;EdgeRouter POE Power Usage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also setting up a DMZ for front facing services, and then a LAN for inside facing machines. There will be a firewall (currently thinking &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/unified-threat-management.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM&lt;/a&gt; or similar) between the DMZ and the network. Some machines will be able to access the DMZ, and there may be machines allowed into the LAN, but only some things&amp;hellip; not even sure if that would be done&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also need to work out the VLAN side of things. I have currently though of the following VLAN setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WAN 1 (connected directly to the Cable modem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WAN 2 (again, direct to cable modem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LAN Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DMZ Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VoIP Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IOT (stuff for running the house, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/ie/thermostat/meet-nest-thermostat/&#34;&gt;Nest&lt;/a&gt;, the MPower devices or the like)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Media Network (Plex, Roku, Apple TV, Chrome Cast, etc. Not sure if i need to separate this, but it might be done&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/switches/catalyst-3560-series-switches/index.html&#34;&gt;Cisco 3560G switch&lt;/a&gt; should do all that, without problems, so no new switch needed&amp;hellip; lets see what i can break over the next while&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquiti EdgeRouter PoE in the lab</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ubiquiti-edgerouter-poe-in-the-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ubiquiti-edgerouter-poe-in-the-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com/edgemax/edgerouter-poe/&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti EdgeRouter POE&lt;/a&gt; arrived in the house. I got it hooked up to both UPC connections (as secondary connections) and all seems to be working grand. Some notes i wanted to put up here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;out of the box, the install was quite simple. set my Ethernet connection to a static ip in the 192.168.1.x/24 range,
using 192.168.1.1 as gateway and dns, and then point at &lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.1&#34;&gt;http://192.168.1.1&lt;/a&gt; for admin. login (ubit for both username and
password) and heay presto. I was asked did i agree to the license, and then im in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by default, NAT is off&amp;hellip; i turned it on, and enabled DNS and was able to surf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also noticed the software was out of date&amp;hellip; Oddly, there did not seem to be an option to update automatically, but
you can manually download the tar and upload it, which i did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;so far, so good&amp;hellip; not sure yet if i will be using it as my main router, but it may end up being a VoIP router.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, speed test result below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/tiernanotoole/image/upload/v1530620885/20150805.ubiquiti.speedtest.compressed-resized.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Speed Test Result&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubnt.com&#34;&gt;Ubiquiti&lt;/a&gt; stuff arriving tomorrow&amp;hellip; will post more stuff then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, this part of my article set will be talking specifically about the router and wireless network. At the moment, my router is way overkill:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old HP Proliant ML110 G5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/29765/Intel-Core2-Quad-Processor-Q6600-8M-Cache-2_40-GHz-1066-MHz-FSB?q=Q6600&#34;&gt;Intel Core2Quad Q6600&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 Gb RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;total of 12 Gigabit network cards (of which 4 are currently used&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;500Gb HDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been playing with some networking in the house and have managed to build some VLANs. The modems are connected both directly to the Router
and to a dedicated switch port for a given VLAN. The plan for the upgrade, which i hope to complete sooner than the rest of the network is as
follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get the ML110 running &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/products/vsphere-hypervisor&#34;&gt;ESXi&lt;/a&gt; and visualize &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt;. Give it 2gb of RAM and some processor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take some of the network cards out of the box. It does not need 12 ports, but maybe leave the 2 quad ports in there. They should be connected
to the main switch trunked. 8 may be overkill, but i never do things by half.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the PFSEnse VM should be connected to all 3 WAN VlANs (900, 901 and 902) and should also have at least one port to the LAN. There may also be
other ports for other internal VLANs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with the spare processor, i can then add other (small) VMs to this machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and HomeLab V.Next (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, in my last post i talked about the requirements for the home lab, and in this post, im going to talk about a few more updates i have made in the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the processors: in the first post, i talked about Xeon D or Xeon E3&amp;hellip; Well, i missed one&amp;hellip; The Xeon E5. I have 2 of these in GodBox 2, and you can get them into a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servethehome.com/asrock-rack-epc612d4i-review-mitx-xeon-e5-platform/&#34;&gt;microATX board&lt;/a&gt;. There does seem to be some limits with the microatx boards, but hopefully enough searching will find me what i am looking for. Ideally, i want it to take &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; DDR3/4 memory (not SODIMMs like the ASRock one above) and also take enough of them to run 64 or 128Gb of ram (thinking 8 would do the job!). Also, i would like to have 4 GigE ports onboard and 1 management port. 4 onboard is not a hard requirement: If i can get one with 2 ports, i can always get a 4 port card for the PCI-Express slot&amp;hellip; Finally, i would like it to have at least 6 SATA ports and possibly an MSATA port. Thinking Boot off MSATA (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Server_2016&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2016 Nano Server&lt;/a&gt; would be used), 2 SSDs and 4 HDDs. Using Storage Spaces, use the 2 SSDs as &amp;ldquo;Fast&amp;rdquo; storage for the pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think i moved off the idea of 10Gb. I like the idea of it, but given a small 10Gb switch costs upwards of a grand, and the plan is to build a machine for that price, i would prefer a fifth machine and using my existing Cisco 48 port switch and leave 10Gb as a future upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, changed from last time round is machine count. Originally i was saying 3-4 machines&amp;hellip; now i am thinking 6-7&amp;hellip; 5-6 of them should be Hyper-V boxes and the last one would be a Media Box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think the Synology or SAN requirement is out&amp;hellip; Hyper-V can be setup to do replication between hosts, and with a 4Gb link to the LAN, i think i should be OK. Also, if i have the media box separate, i should be ok there too. I will detail the media center in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, any suggestions or thoughts on what should and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be looked at?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network and Homelab V.Next (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/network-and-homelab-vnext-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, its that time again&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/Computers&#34;&gt;HomeLab&lt;/a&gt; upgrade time&amp;hellip; Or at least the planning for it. I am in the process of rebuilding my home lab, which involves pull all old servers out of the rack and replacing them with new ones&amp;hellip; It also means rewriting the network, possibly upgrading some existing gear and hopefully getting the whole lot done on a budget of some sort&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why? Well, biggest reason for all this is currently heat and power usage. We use about 4-6x more electricity than the average house here in Ireland, which means our electricity bill is fairly high. It also means that the lab, which is also my office/bedroom, gets quite warm and uncomfortable during the summer month. There is an Air-Con unit in the room, and, well, that&amp;rsquo;s costing the most on electricity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what I got is a basic overview of what I want from the homelab and hopefully in the next post, I will have an idea of what it will look like..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-4 machines running a Hyper Visor (HyperV, VMWare ESXi or other). Leaning more towards Hyper-V purely because its what I got currently and its what we use in our main office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each machine should be connected to at least 2 networks: one for storage and migration, one for &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; to the LAN. There may be more VLANs for other networks, but 2 is a start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ideally, 10Gb connections would be nice, but multiple 1Gb connections would also work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shared storage (iSCSI, SMB3, etc) would also be a nice to have, but may bump up the server count (not actually a problem) but would increase power and cooling costs. An off the shelf box, like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.synology.com&#34;&gt;Synology&lt;/a&gt; could do the job&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower power usage and less heat produced is also a major requirement. Most of the boxes I am decommissioning are older Xeon hardware (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/family/28144/Intel-Xeon-Processor-5000-Sequence#@All&#34;&gt;5000&lt;/a&gt; series upto a &lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/series/33092/Intel-Xeon-Processor-5200-Series#@All&#34;&gt;5200&lt;/a&gt; series process and even an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xeon#Netburst-based_Xeon&#34;&gt;older Xeon P4&lt;/a&gt;!). The newer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.ie/content/www/ie/en/processors/xeon/xeon-processor-e3-family.html&#34;&gt;Xeon E3&lt;/a&gt; and the even newer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.ie/content/www/ie/en/processors/xeon/xeon-processor-d-family.html&#34;&gt;Xeon D&lt;/a&gt; are a lot more efficient, use less power, produce less heat and are way faster than what I currently have. The E3 can use up to 32Gb of RAM and the Xeon D top out at 128Gb&amp;hellip; Me being me would like more than 32Gb RAM&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smaller machines would also be nice. I have been looking at both Xeon D and Xeon E3 Mini-ITX boards and cases for them. I do have a half height Dell Rack, which I host these machines, and ideally, these machines should be rack mountable, but micro ATX cases could work. 2 per shelf would work grand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboard IPMI and KVM support is something I want too&amp;hellip; I do have a KVMoIP switch in the house, and it works, most of the time, but getting a box that has this embedded into the board would be ideal&amp;hellip; A lot of the server boards had it as standard or allowed it to be speced, so that&amp;rsquo;s all good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am also thinking of upgrading the router to a similar spec board&amp;hellip; Possibly a Xeon E3, or even an i5&amp;hellip;. Ideally it should have IPMI and KVMoIP on board and should produce less heat. Biggest issues is getting enough network cards into the box&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are my requirements at a  high level overview. Over time things may change, but lets see how we get on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PFSense with Multiple Public IPs</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/pfsense-with-multiple-public-ips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/pfsense-with-multiple-public-ips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, a few weeks back, i got my hands on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; Dedicated box. It has a quad core Xeon, 32Gb ram, 3x3Tb hdds, RAID controller and KVMoIP. one of the first thing i did was get myself a /29 IP pool (8 total, 6 usable IPs). There where already 3 IPs given to me: 1 for the KVM, one for the box itself, and 1 as the router for the IP block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, i need to setup my own router, so i picked &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; since its what i run in house. I gave it 2 network connections: 1 connected to the main network adapter on the VMWare ESXi box (public) and one to a virtual switch, which is only used by VMs. The public is the WAN link and it gets a static IP from Hetzner, and the virtual switch is then my &amp;ldquo;LAN&amp;rdquo; link. This allows me to have standard NATed network connections to any VM i have, but then, what do i do with those IPs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after a lot of digging, i found the answer. So, this should help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under firewall, click on Virtual IPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click the plus. I then selected IP alias, selected the WAN interface and set the IP to my first public IP i wanted to give. in my case, i was given a /29 block, and my first address was 176. This is the network address. I used 177. Likewise, my last address is 183, but that cannot be used either as its a broadcast address. give it a description and then hit OK. Repease for all IPs you want to use. TIP: Give each a meaningful description!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, click firewall, NAT and 1:1. Click the add button and select your interface as WAN. set the External Subnet IP as the one you want to use and your internal IP as the machine that will have it. Thats all i did on that screen&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then go to Firewall, NAT, outbound&amp;hellip; this is where things got complicated. Set the mode to &amp;ldquo;Manual outbound NAT rule generation (AON - Advanced Outbound NAT)&amp;rdquo; and click save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then create a new rule: Interface: WAN, Source, Network, IP of the internal machine and then under translation, under address select the IP you want to give it. If you followed my tip in step 2, you should see the descriptions in here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After saving everything and reloading the firewall, visiting a page like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whatsmyip.org&#34;&gt;WhatsMyIP&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://icanhazip.com&#34;&gt;ICanHazIP&lt;/a&gt; should show you your public IP. You can then create firewall rules to allow access. Quick idea would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firewall/Rules, Add, Interface WAN, Destination: Local IP you want to use, and give whatever &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; rules you would (HTTP, lock down to source address, etc). Click apply and hitting that address using what ever method (SSH, HTTP, etc) should work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YMMV, but hopefully this helps! Any questions, leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick tip for internet facing ESXi servers</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/quick-tip-for-internet-facing-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 08:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/quick-tip-for-internet-facing-esxi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick tip for all you with internet facing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/vsphere-hypervisor&#34;&gt;VMWare ESXi&lt;/a&gt; Hosts. I
have just got my hands on a box on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; network (more on
that later) and using their LARA system i installed ESXi on it. All was good, then I tried login in a couple hours later and i kept getting errors about my password being wrong&amp;hellip; So, i tried a few more times,  got pissed off and rebooted the box (had to do a hard reboot, since i couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get in over KVM). I though this was a hardware issue, or a config issue, and left it&amp;hellip; yesterday, i had the console open most of the day, and when looking at something i noticed this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/tiernanotoole/image/upload/v1530620877/20150520-esxi-login-errors.png&#34; alt=&#34;ESXi Errors&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s why I couldn&amp;rsquo;t login! So, tip: create a second user account, name it something other than root, give it a secure password and use that to login to your ESXi box. Ideally, your ESXi box should be behind a firewall, but in the case of a dedicated server, that may not be financially feasible&amp;hellip; Hope this helps someone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLANs, Wifi and Mikrotik</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/vlans-wifi-and-mikrotik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/vlans-wifi-and-mikrotik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, while i was recovering from surgery, i attended a Webinar on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meraki.com&#34;&gt;Cisco Meraki&lt;/a&gt; devices. After the webinar, i was contacted by Maraki and given a &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/wireless/mr18&#34;&gt;MR18&lt;/a&gt; with a 3 year license, to play with and evaluate. So, i set it up in the house and all was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thing is, the wifi in the house was grand previously. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB951G-2HnD&#34;&gt;Routerboard RB951G&lt;/a&gt; which does the job and has no issues. And because i am mostly offsite in the office i work, and because i need to remotely manage the network, the MR18 is going into the office from tomorrow morning. I may talk about the MR18 and the rest of the Meraki gear later on, but this is not that post. This post is about something the MR18 did, and i wanted to do on the RB951.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the MR18 allows you to create multiple Wifi SSIDs, each with different encryption and security and can use different VLANs. Now, the Mikrotik does the same, but the VLANs stuff is not that easy to figure out. but essentially, what i needed to do was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;create your new wifi SSIDs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/interface wireless
add master-interface=wlan1 name=wlan1.10 ssid=vlan10
add master-interface=wlan1 name=wlan1.20 ssid=vlan20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next, create your vlans. these need to be connected back to your main
ethernet connection. In the case of my RB951, there are 5 ethernet
ports. 1 is the gateway back to my Cisco switch and on to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pfsense.org&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; router. 2-5 are all slaves of number 1, which is a master. So, 1 is essentially a trunk network. So, vlans are created on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/interface vlan
add name=vlan10 interface=ether1-gateway name=ether1.10 vlan-id=10
add name=vlan20 interface=ether1-gateway name=ether1.20 vlan-id=20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next, a bridge to connect them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/interface bridge
add name=vlan10
add name=vlan20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and connect them to the bridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/interface bridge port
add bridge=vlan10 interface ether1.10
add bridge=vlan10 interface wlan1.10
add bridge=vlan20 interface ether1.20
add bridge=vlan20 interface wlan1.20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thats all i needed to do. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/free-tools/sophos-utm-home-edition.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM Home edition&lt;/a&gt; running on a vm for testing, which vlan10 is connected to. It has an upstream connection back to the PFSense box, which has it firewalled off and allows it outside the network, not nothing else. I am planning on doing this with other firewalls, just to do some testing with. This allows me to connect my phone or laptop, or any other wifi device, to a given wifi connection and then be on my way. I also have an older Dell PowerConnect switch, which, if i ever get around to it, will have multiple connections back to the Cisco and then allow physical devices to connect to different vlans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any questions, comments, etc, leave a comment blow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using git and Route53 together</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/using-git-and-route53/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/using-git-and-route53/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;so, earlier on today, i was talking about using &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2015/05/07/git-push-dns.html&#34;&gt;Git with a DNS service called LuaDNS&lt;/a&gt; to update your DNS records. Well, thing is, i have 30+ domains registered, and of them about 25 are hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Route53&lt;/a&gt;. So, moving ALL of them seems, well at the moment, excessive&amp;hellip; So, i went digging&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there is a tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/barnybug/cli53&#34;&gt;cli53&lt;/a&gt; which will allow you to manage route53 objects from the command line. It can also export your zones to BIND format and then re-import them if you have made changes&amp;hellip; This all came out of a blog post by the guys and gals at &lt;a href=&#34;https://netguru.co/blog/ci-your-dns-setup&#34;&gt;netguru&lt;/a&gt; who showed how they integrate their DNS records with their Continuous Integration&amp;hellip; Now, i have not gotten to that stage, just yet, but its only 1 step more down the road&amp;hellip; but I don&amp;rsquo;t have my zones in bind format&amp;hellip; So, how do i do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tweaked their block of ruby code (first time playing with ruby, be gentle with me) and got the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist f11fbec2075b8bf19d57 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;essentially, it runs cli53 (you may need to change your path) and then creates .bind files for each zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then, using their code below, you can re-import them to Route53:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 7249547 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i have exported all mine, added them to git and done some testing&amp;hellip; All seems to be in order&amp;hellip; once i do some tweaks, i can get that CI piece working and it should be all magic&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Push DNS</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/git-push-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/git-push-dns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are now a lot of services that have &amp;ldquo;git push&amp;rdquo; options available&amp;hellip; you can build websites with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azure.com&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, books using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sharelatex.com/&#34;&gt;ShareLaTeX&lt;/a&gt; and now, DNS using &lt;a href=&#34;http://luadns.com&#34;&gt;LuaDNS&lt;/a&gt;. I have one zone
running at the moment (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tiernanotoole.net&#34;&gt;tiernanotoole.net&lt;/a&gt;) and you can see the DNS records on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/dns&#34;&gt;github here&lt;/a&gt;. I am
tempted at moving other records over soon&amp;hellip; but i am currently on &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;Amazon Route53&lt;/a&gt; and 1: its works, so
dont break it, and 2, not sure how to bulk export records from Route53 to Bind or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.luadns.com/help.html#lua-zone-file-format&#34;&gt;Lua&lt;/a&gt; format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[update] 2 quick updates: 1) their free account, which is what i am using, allows 3 domains and 30 host
records. they also charge less than &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;Route53&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;route 53 for 10 domains per year cost 50c per domain (first 25) per month, then query charges. total,
about $60 + queries (@40c per million).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;luadns cost $29 a year for 10 domains, 5 million (ish) querys a month and 500 host records&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think i have nearly 30 domain on AWS&amp;hellip; so, their $59 a year package, which include 30 domains, would
probably save me money&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and 2) i forgot about one of those git push services&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://developermail.io/&#34;&gt;DeveloperMail&lt;/a&gt; is a service, for developers,
for managing email servers. IMAP, SMTP, Git&amp;hellip; all supported! just signed up&amp;hellip; $2 a month per user. Lets
see how this works&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi as a Mobile WiFi HotSpot (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_as_a_mobile_wifi_hotspot_-_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 07:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_as_a_mobile_wifi_hotspot_-_part_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using an iPhone 4 as a wifi hotspot for a while now. It does not have a &amp;ldquo;phone&amp;rdquo; SIM in it, with calls and texts enabled, instead it has a 3G Data SIM from a dongle&amp;hellip; It works OK, but there are a few issues i have with it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No easy way to see how much data is being used, unless you Jail Break, and then battery life goes away&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not very hackable&amp;hellip; other than Jail Break, and thats not hackable enough&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not a lot of storage: 16Gb, and most of that is takin up by Music and Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no background network daemons&amp;hellip; more on that in a second&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Network Daemons i am thinking would be useful for a WiFi Hotspot would be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt;, SSH, PPTP or OpenVPN Client and possibly a downloader of some sort. What i am thinking is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a device, that is small enough to fit in a bag, possibly small enough to fit in a jacket pocket. It will probably not be as small as the iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should have storage on board. Boot storage and cache storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 1, possibly more, WiFi Adapters, with optional antennas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 1, possibly more, 3G or 4G Modems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 1 ethernet port, again possibility for more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battery that can run the whole system for at least 4-5 hours, and should be able to run while being charged. charging via USB would be ideal also&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optional Screen, but more likley, some sort of web interface to show whats going on (Bandwdith usage, clients connected, connection details)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this turns on, it should automatically start the 3/4G connections (if there are multiple connections, it should do some balancing of the connections). if there are more then 1 WiFi Connection, one should be a Client (connect to an external WiFi connection, like home, college, work) and one should be an Access Point (Your Phone, Tablet and Laptop connect to this one). Ethernet can also be used in a simular way (if one only, it could be client or server, if multiple, one can be client, one can be server). DHCP addresses will be given out on Access Point or Server connections, and on Client connections, DHCP will be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squid would be installed and listen on its usual port. Optionally, all port 80 and 8080 traffic could be routed though Squid. Ideally, HTTPS traffic should be automatically routed, but i think thats a bit harder to setup&amp;hellip; If VPN Clients are enabled, it could also allow All or Some traffic to be routed over the VPN connections. SSH could also be used to compress traffic between multiple Squid boxes (one in house, one on the device). WANProxy could be used in a simular manner to save bandwdith and make the connection faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with all that, i am looking at using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; for the job. I am still working on this, but here is what i have so far&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have put a Wifi adapter into my Raspberry Pi (A Linksys, but forget the exact model number). Using a tutorial on &lt;a href=&#34;http://exain.wordpress.com/2011/03/31/making-a-wifi-hotspot-access-point-using-linux-wifi-lan-cardusb-adapter/&#34;&gt;Vivek&amp;rsquo;s blog on making a wifi hotspot on linux&lt;/a&gt; i managed to get the AP showing up on my laptop, but could not connect. I am not sure if its the adapter causing the problem, or what, but i am going to change out the adapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the moment, i am sharing the ethernet connection, not the 3G connection&amp;hellip; I have posted here before the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2012/07/3g-internet-on-raspberry-pi-success/&#34;&gt;link to Terence Eden&amp;rsquo;s post on getting the Raspberry Pi to connect to 3G&lt;/a&gt;. All that i will need to do is connect to 3g and then NAT the connection from Wifi to 3G&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there are a few more bits and pieces to get done over the next while&amp;hellip; I will keep posting here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Firewall rules for MikroTik RouterOS</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_firewall_rules_for_mikrotik_routeros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 11:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_firewall_rules_for_mikrotik_routeros/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/12/19/ipv6_%2B_mikrotik_%2B_linux_%2B_windows.html&#34;&gt;yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post on IPv6 Networking in the house&lt;/a&gt;, I realized that all machines internally had publically facing IPv6 addresses! I started to panic, then went looking online, and found the following script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/4344701.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This script, when run on your RouterOS board, will allow Established and Related connections, allow outgoing connections, and drop anything incoming that has not been requested&amp;hellip; so, now everything inside the network should be more secured&amp;hellip; I am new to this IPv6 stuff, so I am still learning&amp;hellip; but, i am getting there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 &#43; MikroTik &#43; Linux &#43; Windows</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_%2b_mikrotik_%2b_linux_%2b_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 16:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ipv6_%2b_mikrotik_%2b_linux_%2b_windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to setup an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ipv6&#34;&gt;IPv6&lt;/a&gt; network for a while now, but never had the hardware or network to support it. My broadband Modem, a Cisco EPC3925, was pretty useless&amp;hellip; But with the advent of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/02/Enabling-true-briding-mode-on-Cisco-EPC3925.html&#34;&gt;Bridging on the Cisco EPC3925&lt;/a&gt; it now works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing i needed to do was setup a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tunnelbroker.net/&#34;&gt;Tunnel Broker Account&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.he.net&#34;&gt;Hurricane Electric&lt;/a&gt;. I got a /64 block of IPv6 addresses, which should do me for a while&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I followed the config example from the MikroTik Wiki Page: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:My_First_IPv6_Network&#34;&gt;My First IPv6 Network&lt;/a&gt;. In my case, i only ran though most of router 1&amp;rsquo;s config, and did not create the &amp;ldquo;routing between segments&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ospv-v3&amp;rdquo; backbone&amp;hellip; I did give my internal LAN port an IPv6 address, as well as an IPv4 address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, on my Windows Server machine, i gave it a static IPv6 address (since i dont have an IPv6 DHCP setup&amp;hellip; yet&amp;hellip;) and told it to use the IPv6 address i gave the RouteBoard as its gateway. Then i told it to use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendns.com&#34;&gt;OpenDNS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendns.com/ipv6&#34;&gt;public IPv6&lt;/a&gt; address. I then visited &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipv6-test.com&#34;&gt;IPv6 Test&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ipv6.google.com&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s IPv6 page&lt;/a&gt; to confirm connectivity&amp;hellip; SUCCESS!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my Linux box, I followed &lt;a href=&#34;http://knowledgelayer.softlayer.com/questions/468/Adding+IPv6+to+Ubuntu+systems&#34;&gt;Soflayer&amp;rsquo;s Adding an IPv6 IP&lt;/a&gt; tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symform - P2P Backup</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/symform_-_p2p_backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 09:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/symform_-_p2p_backup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have previously &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/30/CrashPlan-Backups.html&#34;&gt;posted about CrashPlan&lt;/a&gt; as my Backup System. I also, a long time ago, talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lotas-smartman.net/new-backup-plan-out-with-jungle-disk-and-zmanda-cloud-backup-in-with-crashplan-mysqlbf-and-sqlbf/&#34;&gt;Backing up SQL, MySQL and other stuff&lt;/a&gt; on my other blog. Well, CrashPlan is all good, but there are 2 &amp;ldquo;niggly&amp;rdquo; bits with it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its not FREE (well, this year i got it Free on Black Friday&amp;hellip;) but it is cheap ($120 a year to backup 10 machines to the cloud aint bad.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its NOT FAST! The CrashPlan Datacenters all live in the US, and my servers live in Europe (either Dublin or Germany). So, bandwidth is limited&amp;hellip; Getting less than 1Mbit/s most times, but have seen it reach 3&amp;hellip; I have 20Mbits/s upload&amp;hellip; even half that would be nice&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thats where &lt;a href=&#34;https://control.symform.com/Organization/Referral?referralId=96E53D9DC4501633F2294EF202734DB08C00F044&#34;&gt;Symform&lt;/a&gt; comes in. Symform is a P2P Backup Service, which runs on Windows, Linux and MacOSX. In theory, it should run anywhere that has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page&#34;&gt;Mono&lt;/a&gt; runtime since its written in .NET. Anyway, you start with 10Gb of free storage, and you can increese that by one of 2 ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay money: for $0.15 per month, you get 1Gb of storage in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay Bytes: For every 2Gb &amp;ldquo;Contributed&amp;rdquo; (which is actually more like a pledge than a contribution&amp;hellip; more on that later) you get 1Gb storage in the cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works very well, and is nice a fast too. I have a few machines in house which are contribting stoage, a total of about 2Tb, and I have been given 1Tb storage in &amp;ldquo;The Cloud&amp;rdquo;. There is a lot more on how this works on their &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symform.com/join-the-revolution/how-symform-works/&#34;&gt;How Symform Works&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; section of their site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned the &amp;ldquo;Contribution&amp;rdquo; VS &amp;ldquo;Pledge&amp;rdquo; up above&amp;hellip; I have a machine in the house where i have Pledged 1Tb of storage. In reality, Symform can use the full 1Tb of storage, if it needs to, but is currently only using 168Gb. Now, that could just be that the machine is still getting files, and it will end up using the full 1Tb eventually, but either way, its all good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as a couple of notes on Contribution and Backups:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The machine needs to be online and accessable on the internet at least 80% of the time, but &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; is ideal. If you drop below the 80%, your account can be suspended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your machine needs to be publically accessable, meaning port forwarded. I have a couple contribution machines in house, so they each have seperate ports forwarded to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given the P2P nature of the software, lots of connections to different machines are made&amp;hellip; if you are behind a firewall, you may need to allow all or most outgoing connections. If you are on a really restrictive firewall, you may want to stick a contribution box in your &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DMZ_(computing)&#34;&gt;DMZ&lt;/a&gt; and probably use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symform.com/our-solutions/key-features/turbo-seeding/&#34;&gt;Turbo Seeding&lt;/a&gt; feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turbo Seeding is a handy feature, especially for Laptops&amp;hellip; only problem is its Windows Only&amp;hellip; So, importing and exporting does not work on Linux or OSX.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The software can managed Work and Non Work hours, and will limit the upload and download speed during this time. Also a nice feature&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good. Very happy with the software, but would like a nicer interface to see whats going on. At the moment, you are either limited to using the web interface, which aint bad, but not great, or watching the log files&amp;hellip; I would also like the ability to prioritize certain files or folders, so, for example, upload my documents folder before anything else, and if anything changes in there, even if its uploading from somewhere else, pause and upload the documents folder&amp;hellip; Just a thought&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>enabling VNC from SSH on OSX</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/enabling_vnc_from_ssh_on_osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 16:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/enabling_vnc_from_ssh_on_osx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/Computers/MacBookPro.html&#34;&gt;Late 2008 MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; in the house, and SSH is enabled on it. I usually leave it on when in work. Anyway, SSH is enabled, but VNC access is not&amp;hellip; I found the following command on &lt;a href=&#34;http://technotes.twosmallcoins.com/?p=279&#34;&gt;Ryan&amp;rsquo;s Tech Notes&lt;/a&gt; allowing you to enable it though SSH:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 4170122 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** NOTE ** Change &lt;em&gt;mypasswd&lt;/em&gt; to your own password!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to disable it, use the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 4170129 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, of note, I am using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.realvnc.com/&#34;&gt;RealVNC client for Windows&lt;/a&gt; to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moving your TMG SQL server Logs DB and other TMG tips</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/moving_your_tmg_sql_server_and_other_tmg_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 08:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/moving_your_tmg_sql_server_and_other_tmg_tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In house, I have been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/tmg&#34;&gt;Microsoft TMG 2010 Server&lt;/a&gt; for a while now. I use it as a firewall for some of the machines on the network, and also as a proxy for most, if not all, machines. When acting as a Firewall, all traffic flows though the machine, be it HTTP/HTTPS, SMTP/POP3/IMAP, or anything for that matter. You can also lock down ports on the box, which is a feature of most firewalls, but i like TMG due to its relitive ease of use&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, one problem with routing all traffic from different machines though TMG is after a while, the logging starts getting big. Single TMG by default is set to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/sql&#34;&gt;SQL Server&lt;/a&gt;, it can start using lots of memory, hard drive space, etc. So, there are a couple of articles which should make moving your TMG&amp;rsquo;s SQL DB to a different machine easier&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb794937.aspx&#34;&gt;Configuring Forefront TMG Logs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dd441079.aspx&#34;&gt;Configuring (TMG) logging to a remote server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.isaserver.org/tutorials/How-configure-Forefront-TMG-logging-into-central-Microsoft-SQL-Server-database.html&#34;&gt;How to configure Forefront TMG logging into a central Microsoft SQL Server database&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other tips you may find useful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have Malware Inspection turned on, but you know there are certain sites that wont serve Malware (for example, Ubutnu Archives or YouTube.com) you can add these to the &amp;ldquo;Destination Exceptions&amp;rdquo; list. Under &amp;ldquo;Web Access Policy&amp;rdquo;, click &amp;ldquo;Malware Inspection&amp;rdquo; and click &amp;ldquo;Destination Exceptions&amp;rdquo;. Double click on the &amp;ldquo;Sites Exempt from Malware Inspection&amp;rdquo; and add your URL. I put *.ubuntu.com and *.youtube.com in here (Microsoft Updates are already on the list). Now, when downloading files from these locations, they do not run though inspection and save CPU cycles. &lt;strong&gt;WANRING&lt;/strong&gt; You need to trust these sites!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a nice little app to add into TMG called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bsplitter.com/&#34;&gt;Bandwidth Splitter&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to not only monitor what traffic is going though your network, but also put limits on different machine sets, users, etc. There is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bsplitter.com/download.aspx#trial_restrictions&#34;&gt;Free editon&lt;/a&gt; which works with only 10 clients, but does what i need it to do to start with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RouterOS Dynamic IP Updates</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_dynamic_ip_updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 10:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_dynamic_ip_updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mikrotik.com&#34;&gt;MikroTik&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB750G&#34;&gt;RouterBoard RB750&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, and i love it! Over the weekend, i upgraded it to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://routerboard.com/RB1100&#34;&gt;RB1100&lt;/a&gt;. Its the same software running the device, but the device is faster (800Mhz PowerPC chip VS MIPS-BE at 680Mhz), has more memory (512Mb upgradable to 1.5Gb vs 32Mb) and more storage (think its 512Mb on board, plus 4Gb MicroSD card vs 32mb&amp;hellip;). It also has more ports (13 GigE VS 5) and 2 Switch Groups, which i have no idea what they do just yet&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, part of getting the RB1100 online and taking over from my existing router was getting Dynamic DNS updating. I use both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dyndns.org&#34;&gt;Dyndns&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://no-ip.com&#34;&gt;NoIP&lt;/a&gt; for DNS, but I also like the look of &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;Amazon Route 53&lt;/a&gt;. For updating NoIP, I am using the Alternitive script from &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Dynamic_DNS_Update_Script_for_No-IP_DNS&#34;&gt;The Mikrotik Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. To get this to work with DynDNS, it would just be a matter of chaning the URL you point to&amp;hellip; I am going to write a web script which will sit internally on the network, use that instead of the No-IP url. When that script gets called, i can log the info, update DynDNS, NoIP and Router53 all in one go. I will be posting more about that soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we are on the topic of Scripting RouterOS, checkout the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Scripts&#34;&gt;Mikrotik Script Example Page&lt;/a&gt;. Lots of good stuff up there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WANProxy and Squid with Upstream Servers</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/wanproxy_and_squid_with_upstream_servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 13:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/wanproxy_and_squid_with_upstream_servers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/24/building_wanproxy_on_ubuntu_12.04.html&#34;&gt;previous post on WANProxy&lt;/a&gt;, i did not really go into detail about what it actually was. The direct quote from their site is &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wanproxy.org&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt; is a free, portable TCP proxy which makes TCP connections send less data, which improves TCP performance and throughput over lossy links, slow links and long links. This is just what you need to improve performance over satellite, wireless and WAN links.&lt;/em&gt; This is something that has interested me for a while, so i have been looking into it, and so far so good&amp;hellip; In my last post i mentioned i was proxying &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; traffic, in todays post, i still am, but with some tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i have a Squid box running in the house. It is connected to 2 Cable Modems, giving me 250Mbits/s down and 20Mbits/s upload connection. It is caching data locally also.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on my laptop i have Squid running also. It connects to a WANProxy server at home and proxies the Squid server. The local squid box is using the home Squid box as an upstream connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for upstream connections i used the following lines in the squid.conf:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 3958472 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have set it to never use a direct connection, which is probably silly, since if i loose the WANProxy connection, i loose connectivity&amp;hellip; Also, port 3300 is the WANProxy port its listening on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good&amp;hellip; I am also thinking this could be an interesting thing to get working on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;. Just a though&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building WANProxy on Ubuntu 12.04</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/building_wanproxy_on_ubuntu_12.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 14:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/building_wanproxy_on_ubuntu_12.04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Updated 2016/04/09] I had to use this today to build on Debian 8.3 for 2 different boxes. So, making minor changes (url to git proxy, and where you build from) to make sure this works now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been looking into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wanproxy.org&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, but never successfully got it to build&amp;hellip; I have been more successfull reciently, so here is what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** NOTE **: I built this on Ubuntu 12.04, so these are the tips for that&amp;hellip; Not sure about other Distros&amp;hellip;
** Second NOTE ** : I am using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/diegows/wanproxy&#34;&gt;Digows GitHub Repo&lt;/a&gt; for downloads&amp;hellip; There is also the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/svn/trunk&#34;&gt;WANProxy SVN Server&lt;/a&gt; and their official &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/get.shtml&#34;&gt;downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install build-essential git-core libssl-dev uuid-dev

git clone https://github.com/wanproxy/wanproxy.git

cd wanproxy/programs/wanproxy

make
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note -: git-core is needed to checkout code, build-essentails gives you your essential build utils, and the -dev files are needed for the build
*- NOTE -: I have tried it on a couple VMs and they take about  5 min to build&amp;hellip; If you are building on Physical hardware, it may be faster. Also, as a general note, if you are building with multiple processors, try add the -jX option, where x is your CPU count +1. for example, make -j5 if you have CPUs or Cores. or make -j17 if you have 16 cores&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cp wanproxy ~/local/bin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~Now, this is, so far, as far as i have gotten&amp;hellip; but given its building, and its further than I was a few weeks back, i though i would post incase i can help someone else&amp;hellip; ~~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** UPDATE ** I have successfully managed to get a WANProxy working. The way i have it setup is as follows:
** UPDATE 2016 ** as part of my series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Projects/&#34;&gt;getting double internet speed&lt;/a&gt;, I am back looking at WANProxy&amp;hellip; more on that later..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux box in house, and VM on laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;both have WANProxy installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use the ** Proxying over SSH ** example &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/examples.shtml&#34;&gt;from the WANProxy examples site&lt;/a&gt; which shows you how to proxy a single web server over SSH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in my case, i pointed the port at my proxy server inhouse. I also changed the if0.host address from 127.0.0.1 (only accessable from that machine) to its internal IP address (can be seen by anyone on that network)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally, I told my browser to use the WANProxy ip and port 3300 (see the if0 config section) as its proxy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Works grand so far. no idea yet if its &amp;ldquo;faster&amp;rdquo; but its working, which is a start&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RouterOS Using Host names in Firewall Rules</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_using_host_names_in_firewall_rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 07:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_using_host_names_in_firewall_rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow up to yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/11/routeros_blocking_machine_access.html&#34;&gt;RouterOS Blocking Machine access to all but one IP&lt;/a&gt; I tought i would show how to add extra IPs to that list, without having a shedload of firewall filters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First things first, get your list of IPs you allow access to. In my case, i just did an NSLOOKUP on the name and got the IPs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an &amp;ldquo;Address List&amp;rdquo; in RouterOS. This can be done on the Web Interface by going to IP / Firewall / Address List and clicking Add. I had none previously, so i created a new rule, naming it &lt;a href=&#34;www.expressvpn.com/?referrer_email=tiernan@tiernanotoole.ie/&#34;&gt;ExpressVPN&lt;/a&gt; (the lads i use for VPN access) and added the first address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this is where things get interesting. for extra IP (for ExpressVPN, i have 4) you create a new address with the SAME name, but different IP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in your firewall rule, you should have either a src address or dst address. in my case, i had both, but this was a change for the dst address. I removed the address from the rule, i added it as a dst address list entry. If you have multiple address lists, you will see them here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to do this at the command prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 3877692 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this will block any traffic, other than the IPs in the expressVPN address list, for the machine 192.168.0.123.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RouterOS Blocking Machine access to all but one IP</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_blocking_machine_access/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 13:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/routeros_blocking_machine_access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, i have a machine on my network, which should be only connecting to the internet though a VPN. I needed to tell my RouterOS box to block all access, except to this said IP address&amp;hellip; The following &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do the trick&amp;hellip; YMMV&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 3871919 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this will drop any packets from the srcaddress (IP address) that are not for destination dstaddress (IP address). in my case, dstaddress is the VPN server i want to connect to. So, in theory, all packets should just go though the VPN and not leak out in to the rest of the network&amp;hellip; again, still testing this so be careful!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling True Bridging modem on a Cisco ECP3925 Cable Modem (UPC Ireland)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/enabling-true-briding-mode-on-cisco-epc3925/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/enabling-true-briding-mode-on-cisco-epc3925/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.upc.ie/&#34;&gt;UPC Ireland&lt;/a&gt; customer, and have 2 cable modems into the house, both Cisco EPC3925s. These are not exactly great modems for power users, but are grand for normal use&amp;hellip; Me, however, being a poweruser wanted something a little more, how should I put it, powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months back, a tutorial was posted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boards.ie&#34;&gt;Boards.ie&lt;/a&gt; which showed you &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boards.ie/vbulletin/showthread.php?p=79448674&#34;&gt;How to enable &amp;ldquo;bridging&amp;rdquo; on your UPC modem&lt;/a&gt;. When i say &amp;ldquo;Bridging&amp;rdquo;, they used DMZ, turned off firewalls, static IPs internally, turned off Wifi and DHCP, etc. It worked, quite well actually, but was &amp;ldquo;odd&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; Today, however, there is a new tutorial &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boards.ie/vbulletin/showthread.php?t=2056758726&#34;&gt;Enabling REAL bridging on a Cisco EPC3925&lt;/a&gt;. I have tried this, and so far, it works! now just to set my router to work correctly, and update my IPs if they change&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MicroTik RouterOS VPN Setup</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/microtik-routeros-vpn-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/microtik-routeros-vpn-setup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have been running a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.routerboard.com&#34;&gt;MikroTik RouterBoard&lt;/a&gt; in the house for a couple of months now (the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.routerboard.com/RB750G&#34;&gt;RB750G&lt;/a&gt;) and I am very much loving the thing. But one thing you may need to do is setup VPN connections&amp;hellip; Here are some tips on how to create a VPN Server and Client on your RouterBoard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;client-setup&#34;&gt;Client Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to setup a client, you need to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 8581643 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does that all do? the first line creates an l2tp-client interface, pointing at &amp;ldquo;servername&amp;rdquo; with the username and password set. encryption, etc is enabled&amp;hellip; Line 2 then enables the client. Line 3 sets all traffic comming from networkaddress/24 (for example, 192.168.0.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;24&lt;/sub&gt;) to be sent though the VPN. any traffic going into networkaddress (same example) is not sent though the VPN. Line 4 creates a gateway, for all addresses (0.0.0.0/0) to use the VPN address. finally, NAT Masquerading is enabled on the VPN interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there are more advanced things you can set above&amp;hellip; some examples I can think of are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be no good reason to limit the amount of VPN connections you have&amp;hellip; in theory, you could have multiple&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for the mangle rule, set the src-address to a single machine in your network. that way, it gets VPN only connections. Also, you could set the dst-address to a single address or network to send only traffic going to a given server though the VPN&amp;hellip; Example would be Netflix US traffic to a US VPN server, BBC iPlayer traffic to a UK VPN, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the example above uses L2TP, but PPTP, SSTP and OpenVPN are also available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;server-setup&#34;&gt;Server Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, L2TP, PPTP, SSTP and OpenVPN servers are available on RouterOs. Details on setting them up are available on MicroTik&amp;rsquo;s Wiki at the following locations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Interface/OVPN&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Interface/PPTP&#34;&gt;PPTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Interface/L2TP&#34;&gt;L2TP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.mikrotik.com/wiki/Manual:Interface/SSTP&#34;&gt;SSTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Tunneling made simple</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ssh-tunneling-made-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/ssh-tunneling-made-simple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something I do on a regular basis is use the internet while &amp;ldquo;out and about&amp;rdquo;. This could be college, which has a semi open network, or it could be a coffee shop, which also usually has a semi open connection. There is also the possibility of using the a mobile internet connection on my iPhone, which can be slow, but at least its only shared with me&amp;hellip; Anyway, over on RevSys.com, there is a post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.revsys.com/writings/quicktips/ssh-tunnel.html&#34;&gt;SSH Tunneling made simple&lt;/a&gt; which shows you how to open an SSH tunnel to your machine somewhere else (could be at home, as is my case, or a VPS/Dedicated server somewhere, or even on Amazon&amp;hellip;) and use that for different things&amp;hellip; In the case he shows, its for SMTP access. For my case, i am forwarding my local port 3128 to my Microsoft TMG 2010 Server in house on port 8080. Then my system proxy on my laptop is set to use localhost:3128 for all web and HTTPS requests. Very handy. One other tip: Using the -C flag, so your command may look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh yourname@remotemachine -L 3128:remoteMachine:8080 -C
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will compress data between you and the SSH server, which for basic web browsing (HTML, CSS, JS) will make things faster, but for stuff like images, etc, may not work so well&amp;hellip; Your Mileage may Vary&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, while on the subject of SSH, Linux Journal has an article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/6602&#34;&gt;Eleven SSH tricks&lt;/a&gt; which mentions compression, Encryption Cyphers, X11 Forwarding, Config files and other interesting bits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
