<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tags/programming.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2019 Tiernan OToole</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with AMD&#39;s Epyc</title>
      <link>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2018/07/02/playing-with-amd-epyc.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2018/07/02/playing-with-amd-epyc.html</guid>
      <description>So, a few days back I got an email from Packet.net about a promotion they and AMD where running. Essentially, they gave me some credit for their service (i am an existing customer) to play with one of their c2.medium machines. A c2.medium comes with an AMD EPYC 7401P which consists of 24 physical cores clocked at 2Gz with an all core boost at 2.8Gb and a max clock of 3Gz, 48 threads, 64GB ECC Memory, 2x120GB SSDs for boot and 2x480GB SSDs for main storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compressing and UnCompressing Protobuf items in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/12/12/compressing_and_uncompressing_protobuf_items_in_c.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 11:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/12/12/compressing_and_uncompressing_protobuf_items_in_c.html</guid>
      <description>Part of a project i am working on required sending large amounts of data between different instances. To get this to work efficially, we started using the ProtoBuf using ProtoBuf-net in .NET. but the files where still quite large (17mb, give or take). So, we looked into compression&amp;hellip;
here is some examples of how we managed to compress the protobuf files. We got some decient compression: 3mb files, down from 17mb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom MSDeploy OverWrite Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/31/custom_msdeploy_overwrite_rules.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 09:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/31/custom_msdeploy_overwrite_rules.html</guid>
      <description>I have a project which we are trying to automate the deployment system. The plan is to automatically deploy the project to a staging server anytime the build succeeds from SVN.
I have had a few problems with this, but here are some of the links which may come in handy for you.
 MSDeploy skip rules when using MSBuild PublishProfile with Visual Studio 2012 Web Deploy : Customizing a deployment package How to set MSDeploy settings in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handbrake Cluster</title>
      <link>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/03/handbrake-cluster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/10/03/handbrake-cluster.html</guid>
      <description>[UPDATED] someone asked in the comments if there was an binary build for this file. there is now! http://handbrakecluster.codeplex.com now hosts the code and binaries, and will soon have help files and documentation.
A few days back, i wrote a post titled Powershell + Handbrake + AppleTV + iTunes = Automatic TV&amp;hellip; ish. In it i included a block of Powershell code to bulk convert TV shows from whatever format you had them in to a M4V format for the AppleTV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cross Compiler for your Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/09/25/raspberry-pi-cross-compiling.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/09/25/raspberry-pi-cross-compiling.html</guid>
      <description>My main machine at home, known as &amp;ldquo;The GodBox&amp;rdquo; is a Dual Processor, Quad Core Xeon 5520 with 60Gb RAM, 2 300Gb 10,000 RPM Western Digital Velociraptor in RAID 0 for boot, 4X1Tb 7200RPM drives for storage, 2 more 300Gb 10,000 RPM drives for &amp;ldquo;scratch disk&amp;rdquo; and a couple high(ish) end graphics cards with 3 monitors plugged in&amp;hellip; Hence the name, GodBox!
Anyway, The Raspberry Pi, on the other hand, has a 700Mhz processor, 256Mb RAM and not much else&amp;hellip; So, if you need to write code for your Pi, and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait a long time to compile, check out this tutorial on how to build a cross compiler for your raspberry pi which will allow you to build your apps on a different machine&amp;hellip; I have a college project which the Raspberry Pi will be used for, and i am thinking this will be how i build code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>