<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Howto on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Howto on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 9 - Going Back</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-9-going-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-9-going-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 9 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the double internet experiment is about ready to be finished&amp;hellip; After 9 posts, 4 months, lots of sweating, many painful nights trying to figure out why something stopped using, shouting when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netflix.com&#34;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; did not work, wondering why my internet connection was so slow, and many, many other problems, i have decided to wind down the project. in the last 9 posts, i have learned a lot, and i hope i have helped someone figure out some stuff on their end. Even though this is a wind up of the project, there are still new things i have to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found another project that has potential for speeding up the internet: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vrayo.com/how-to-set-up-a-bonding-vpn-connection-in-linux/&#34;&gt;VTrunkd&lt;/a&gt;. after some testing, i does seem to manage to speed up the connection, but either limits on hardware i have in house, or limits of hardware in the cloud, or even the software, stopped me in my tracks&amp;hellip; i did see 400mb/s out of it at one stage, using 200mb/s from each modem&amp;hellip; its close, but its not the full 720&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;messing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga/Zebra&lt;/a&gt; as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/06/08/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around.html&#34;&gt;the previous post&lt;/a&gt; has been, well, interesting&amp;hellip; I did manage to get all &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.ie&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt; traffic sent though their server, &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; traffic sent over that box, and everything else over &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;. I added an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azure.com&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; box to the mix for a while, aswell as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vultr.com/?ref=6925433&#34;&gt;Vultr&lt;/a&gt; box, but it got very messey, very quickly. if i had something automated, it would be better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the idea of having a /29 IP range in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; and forwarding it though the tunnels back to the house did work. My &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;Meraki MX64&lt;/a&gt; had one IP address, i had a mail server on a second, everything else on a third, and was planning on using more&amp;hellip; but its just, well, again, messy. So, i will be going back to the idea of 2 IP addresses, and hoping whatever i put infront of the network can figure stuff out&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what am i moving to? well, thats a question&amp;hellip; Currently, i have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;Meraki MX64&lt;/a&gt; plugged directly into the modems, and protecting my LAN. So far, so good, but due to hardware limits, it maxes out at around 260mb/s. So, thats out of the question for the main network! I did at one stage have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en/products/free-tools/sophos-utm-home-edition.aspx&#34;&gt;Sophos UTM Home edition&lt;/a&gt; running. Sophos also have their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sophos.com/en-us/products/free-tools/sophos-xg-firewall-home-edition.aspx&#34;&gt;XG firewall&lt;/a&gt; available for home use, so i might try that&amp;hellip; There is also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pfsense.org/&#34;&gt;PFSense&lt;/a&gt; which i used before also&amp;hellip; And there may be more&amp;hellip; Maybe there will be a new series reviewing these home firewalls? we will see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 8 - Routing Around</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 8 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/05/31/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of.html&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I asked the question about routing traffic to different servers based on thier distances, etc&amp;hellip; Well, after a bit of messing, i can say it kind of works! here is a quick over view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;server in the house has now got multiple OpenVPN connections (2 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;, 1 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.ie&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt; (with a plan to double), 1 to &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; (again, to be doubled) and i am planning 2 to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azure.com&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; as well).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga/Zebra&lt;/a&gt; has static routes (currently static, planing on dynamic soon&amp;hellip; more eventually) to different servers depending on where they are. for example, all traffic to the hetzner network (including their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hetzner.de/en/hosting/produktmatrix/storagebox-produktmatrix&#34;&gt;Storage Boxes&lt;/a&gt;) go though the hetzner link. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hubic.com&#34;&gt;Hubic&lt;/a&gt; traffic goes though OVH, Azure (currently) and AWS traffic, aswell as some CDNs go direct over either WAN1 or WAN2 in the house, and some other stuff (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crashplan.com&#34;&gt;CrashPlan&lt;/a&gt; currently) goes though Digital Ocean. Everything that has no static route goes though Hetzner&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally, the static side of things should be removed, and a more dynamic setup done. How that works, i have no idea&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spotify.com&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; have 2 posts about their SDN Internet Router (&lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.spotify.com/2016/01/26/sdn-internet-router-part-1/&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.spotify.com/2016/01/27/sdn-internet-router-part-2/&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;) which is an interesting idea&amp;hellip; More digging and research is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. Everything currently seems to be working, mostly, and tweaks can be made easily&amp;hellip; I have a couple posts i have in my head, including something to do with automating bringing up new machines (probably with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ansible.com/&#34;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; or something like it), more monitoring, and some other stuff too&amp;hellip; Any questions, leave a comment, and i will get back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[UPDATE] I wrote a quick and dirty app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/whoistozebraconfig&#34;&gt;WhoIsToZebraConfig&lt;/a&gt; which takes an AS Number, looks up the info in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radb.net/&#34;&gt;Merit RADb&lt;/a&gt; (with the help of some code from &lt;a href=&#34;https://coderbuddy.wordpress.com/2010/10/12/a-simple-c-class-to-get-whois-information/&#34;&gt;Coder Buddy&lt;/a&gt;) and outputs what you need to put into your Zebra Config&amp;hellip; should save me some time, and it might save you time too&amp;hellip;  shout if you have questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 7 - ECMP (kind of)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 7 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/05/17/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition.html&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned I am now using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt; for hosting a dedicated box. Thats still live, and going well. I have a /29 IP range (6 usable) and also 2 other IPs. So far, so good&amp;hellip; But because i was using a Socks Server, I was not fully able to use the /29 ips&amp;hellip; I use something like as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/68894593dd44acb4820617aef2889fd6.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;essentially, for each public IP i have that i want to map to an internal IP, i have a POST and PRE ROUTING rule, plus the required forward rules&amp;hellip; But, if socks are used, then that goes out the Window, since TCP traffic will look like its coming from the socks server&amp;hellip; So, i killed the socks server, removed the IPTables rule, and then realized that while outgoing traffic was being balanced somewhat (2 default rules on the internal box pointing at the OpenVPN IPs from the Hetzner box) incoming was a problem. Hetzner knew how to get to my internal network, but only though one ip&amp;hellip; enter Quagga and Zebra&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga&lt;/a&gt; is a routing software suite, which can do protocols like OSPF, BGP and RIP, and Zebra is the component that does static routing. using their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/docs/docs-info.html#Static-Route-Commands&#34;&gt;documentation on static routes&lt;/a&gt;, I created a static route to my internal network with 2 next hops, the OVPN IPs from the internal box&amp;hellip; and, after restarting Quagga, all works! happy days! now i can forward ips from outside the network to inside the network correctly, and they look like they are the public ip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, whats next then? well, I now have a server in Germany (Hetzner) and one in France (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ovh.com&#34;&gt;OVH&lt;/a&gt;), and can spin one up in the UK or the US (&lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;). Given that i have Quagga running on the box, i am now thinking of trying to see if its possible to route traffic depending on distance or something similar&amp;hellip; If i am trying to hit a server in Hetzner&amp;rsquo;s DC, i should go though Germany. If its in Digital Ocean, go though either US or UK servers, same with OVH. Then figure out who has the fastest links to, say, Amazon, Azure, Netflix, BBC, Dropbox, etc, and add either static or dynamic links to the router&amp;hellip; essentially, thats the theory&amp;hellip; lets see how that works&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 6 - Hetzner Edition</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 6 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its been a while, since I posted, and there are some, well, pretty major changes since the last time&amp;hellip; Lets start are the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; for my hosting provider. I was using their $20 a month server (2 cores, 2GB RAM, 40GB SSD, 3TB transfer), and it was all good&amp;hellip; But I noticed that every now and again I would need to reboot the box. I also noticed that when transferring large files or using higher bandwidth (400mb/s+) the 100% of both cores were being used. So, I wanted to move to something with more power&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also was limited to IP addresses. Yes, Digital Ocean do offer IPv6, but I could only get 1 IPv4 address&amp;hellip; and I wanted more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I went back to some old friends of mine, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hetzner.de/en&#34;&gt;Hetzner&lt;/a&gt;, and bought a dedicated server with a Quad Core Xeon E3, 32GB RAM, 4*3 TB HDDs, 1Gbit/s network connection with 30TB transfer per month and a KVMoIP plugged in. I also got 2 extra standard IPs and a /29 (8 IPs, 6 usable). I will explain that next. I installed Debian 8.4 on the first disk, and I am planning on using the other 3 for storage of some sort. I then installed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multipath-tcp.org&#34;&gt;MPTCP kernel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt;, Squid and a Socks server (same as the Digital Ocean box) and reconfigured the home machine&amp;hellip; All good! Now when browsing the web, everywhere thinks I am in Germany, but so far, so good&amp;hellip; Speed tests are about the same, but I have my theory about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equal-cost_multi-path_routing&#34;&gt;ECMP&lt;/a&gt; to try this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the extra IPs, I am working on doing full IP forwarding, not just port forwarding. One of my IPs in pointing directly at my &lt;a href=&#34;https://meraki.cisco.com/products/appliances/mx64&#34;&gt;Meraki MX64&lt;/a&gt; in house (a post on the Meraki stuff is coming, eventually&amp;hellip;) and another at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/proliantml110.html&#34;&gt;Proliant box&lt;/a&gt;, and I plan on pointing other IPs at machines in the DMZ or a firewall of some sort. the /29 is routed though the IP pointing at the Proliant, so that makes life easier. The original IP is only used for SSH and OVPN from the house. it should not do much else. All network traffic in house is coming from other of the other IPs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, so far, so good. Hopefully the ECMP stuff works correctly, so I will do an updated post soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Web and Desktop Apps 2016 edition</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/useful-web-and-desktop-apps-2016-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/useful-web-and-desktop-apps-2016-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided to do a post on some of my favourite tools to use for development, administration, etc. It’s kind of like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/ScottHanselmans2014UltimateDeveloperAndPowerUsersToolListForWindows.aspx&#34;&gt;Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s Ultimate Tools list&lt;/a&gt;, but not as popular and about 2 years newer&amp;hellip; Anyway, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/ToolsList/&#34;&gt;list is available here&lt;/a&gt;, and will be updated over time, much like my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/DailyCarry/&#34;&gt;Daily Carry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/&#34;&gt;Computers&lt;/a&gt; pages. If you are interested, you add links though &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; by editing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie/blob/master/_data/toolslist.yml&#34;&gt;toolslist.yml data file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Mad) Max Speed - The Road Warrior (Internet connection) (double speed internet Part 5)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 5 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is going to be an update and theoretical post. probably very little &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; stuff going on here, mostly updates, and what I am planning on doing later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.technet.com/b/exchange/archive/2004/07/12/180899.aspx&#34;&gt;OOF&lt;/a&gt; sick, so I have not done much work, but I have been surfing the web, watching videos, downloading stuff, etc., so I have an idea of how things are going. First, as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/04/14/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4.html&#34;&gt;the previous post&lt;/a&gt; I have MPTCP, Squid, Socks Servers, OpenVPN and IPTables doing their magic. 2 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt; tunnels between the house and &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;. All TCP Traffic (bar port 80) is sent over socks to the box in the cloud using RedSocks. All UDP traffic is sent direct over OpenVPN. Since MPTCP is in the mix, all socks traffic is actually split over the 2 connections. All port 80 traffic, and 443 (if the client is using local Squid as their proxy) is sent round-robin between the 2 upstream IPs to Squid (2 OpenVPN end points).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I have noticed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every now and again, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/darkk/redsocks&#34;&gt;RedSocks&lt;/a&gt; crashes&amp;hellip; just full on dies. It’s just a matter of starting again, but it’s a pain&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have had to restart squid a couple of times&amp;hellip; not too often though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was a power outage in the house a few days back&amp;hellip; so, when everything came back online, it was a bit of a pain bringing all connections back to life. I do have to figure out a better plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have to read more on this ECMP stuff. Hopefully it will do what I am hoping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the theoretical stuff. I started thinking, could this work outside the house? Could you build this into something smaller, like a Raspberry Pi, and stick 2 or more USB Modems in, connect it back to a server in the cloud, setup P2P OpenVPN connections and then get more than a single modem speed download? The problems I can see are around MPTCP. I am not sure if it has been ported to ARM to run on a Raspberry Pi. Second, the max you could ever get out of it is 100Mbit/s, given the 10/100mb network port on board&amp;hellip; and you may need extra power for the USB dongles. Also, getting P2P connections may be complicated, given the non-static IPs on the modems, though, in theory, non-P2P OpenVPN could work&amp;hellip; Again, it’s a theory. I had the though and that’s where the title came from&amp;hellip; anyway, throwing it out there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable Modems = Double Speed? Part 4</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 4 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double%Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this week I went in a completely different direction that I have been thinking recently&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the basic theory is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am still using MPTCP kernels on both upstream and local machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;now have 2 P2P UDP &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt; tunnels between house and cloud. Example config is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/09c6928d1d8f6752ea84fd895451bbe5&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all TCP traffic (bar port 80) that hits the router in house is redirected to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/darkk/redsocks&#34;&gt;RedSocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RedSocks uses a socks server, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inet.no/dante/&#34;&gt;Dante&lt;/a&gt;, as an upstream server on the cloud box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;since the socks traffic is over TCP (inside the UDP OpenVPN tunnel) it uses MPTCP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;having socks running, gives me quite the download speed, turning it off does not, hence the following tweet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Hmmmm&amp;hellip; If I have socks on, the Internet is fast 400mb/s+). But without socks, it&amp;#39;s down to 60&amp;hellip; Feck&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tiernan (@tiernano) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tiernano/status/720186883905626112&#34;&gt;April 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am also noticing that I am starting to hit the limits of my upstream VM. If downloading or uploading at speed, the processor cores (2 in the case of the box I am currently running) are pegged at pretty much 100% full&amp;hellip; Well, 80ish, but that because the other 20% is being used by Dante. I am noticing I can hit a full 72Mbit/s up, but the max currently downloading is about 400, maybe 450&amp;hellip; Need a faster box now&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I mentioned port 80 not being set over socks. That&amp;rsquo;s because its redirected to Squid. Squid (in house) then uses Squid (in cloud) as a parent. There are 2 round-robin parents for squid, one on each OpenVPN connection IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all other traffic (UDP, ICMP, etc.) are sent over the OpenVPN connection&amp;hellip; currently only one is picked, but I have a cunning plan&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube AsXKS8Nyu8Q %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cunning plan? Well, if I am reading the internet correctly, and I would like to think I am, I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equal-cost_multi-path_routing&#34;&gt;ECMP&lt;/a&gt;, or Equal Cost Multi-Path Routing, could help&amp;hellip; Again, it’s a fledgling idea currently, and I am still reading the documentation, but if it works&amp;hellip; Well&amp;hellip; I not sure&amp;hellip; let’s see&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Jekyll on Bash On Ubuntu on Windows</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/installing-jekyll-on-bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/installing-jekyll-on-bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the 2016 Build conference, Microsoft announced that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/31/bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows.html&#34;&gt;Bash on Ubuntu on Windows&lt;/a&gt; was coming. Well, it &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/commandline/2016/04/06/bash-on-ubuntu-on-windows-download-now-3/&#34;&gt;came out last week&lt;/a&gt;, and I installed it as soon as I could! My next challenge was to get &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to run and install on it, so I can build and preview this site on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/surface/en-us/devices/surface-book&#34;&gt;Surface Book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first, I needed to install version 2.0 of Ruby. There is a bit of messing involved for this, but first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get update
apt-get install ruby2.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when you run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby -v
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you will still see ruby 1.9.x installed&amp;hellip; and the github-pages gem, which includes Jekyll 3, requires ruby 2.0&amp;hellip; ugh. after reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/ruby2.0/+bug/1310292&#34;&gt;this very long bug report&lt;/a&gt; I got this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Rename original out of the way, so updates / reinstalls don&#39;t squash our hack fix
dpkg-divert --add --rename --divert /usr/bin/ruby.divert /usr/bin/ruby
dpkg-divert --add --rename --divert /usr/bin/gem.divert /usr/bin/gem
# Create an alternatives entry pointing ruby -&amp;gt; ruby2.0
update-alternatives --install /usr/bin/ruby ruby /usr/bin/ruby2.0 1
update-alternatives --install /usr/bin/gem gem /usr/bin/gem2.0 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when I run ruby -v, I am told I am on version 2.0! Happy days! Next, i installed bundler using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which uses a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tiernano/www.tiernanotoole.ie/blob/master/Gemfile&#34;&gt;Gemfile&lt;/a&gt; to install the required gems, so running&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; install all required gems but no luck&amp;hellip; I tried adding ruby2.0 dev to the mix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install ruby2.0-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but running jekyll from bash said it did not exist, and running&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle exec jekyll build
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;failed with a memory issue&amp;hellip; ugh&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, next, I tried&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install github-pages -V
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-v makes it verbose, so you can see what&amp;rsquo;s going on&amp;hellip; after a bit of time, and lots of output to the screen&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll build
bash: /usr/bin/jekyll: No such file or directory
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FECK! So, after a bit more digging, i find that jekyll is actually in /usr/local/bin/jekyll&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln /usr/local/bin/jekyll /usr/bin/jekyll
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;solves that problem!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now running&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll build
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;works perfectly, as does&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll serve
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAPPY DAYS! Mind you, I am only using this as a testing and writing system. I have not tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/laurilehmijoki/s3_website&#34;&gt;s3_website&lt;/a&gt; just yet, but that is being sorted elsewhere anyway. Maybe my next post will explain that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable modems = Double speed? Part 3</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 3 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/22/2-Cable-Modems-Double-Internet-Speed-part1.html&#34;&gt;Part 1 of this series&lt;/a&gt; I explained the why and what I wanted to do for this &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo;. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/30/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2.html&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; I did some basic testing of both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multipath-tcp.org&#34;&gt;MPTCP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://zehome.github.io/MLVPN&#34;&gt;MLVPN&lt;/a&gt;. I also mentioned trying &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Point-to-Point_Protocol#PPP_Configuration_Options&#34;&gt;MMPPP&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;http://vtun.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;vtund&lt;/a&gt; but it has been a while since I did that testing, and it had not been on bare metal. So, this post is a follow up, where I am using bare metal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first, the setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ProLiant box is running Debian 8.3 x64, and has both vtund and ppp installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digtial Ocean&lt;/a&gt; box also has Debian 8.3, vtund and ppp installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walked though the guide from &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnlewis.ie/bonding-teaming-internet-connections/&#34;&gt;John Lewis&lt;/a&gt; and made some changes to the configs. the main ones are mentioned below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once done, i installed both iperf and iftop on both boxes, and ran&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iperf -s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the Digital Ocean box and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iperf -c 192.168.10.1 -d
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the local box. And, well, the results where not as expected. Pretty poor actually:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, using Squid installed on the DO box, i tried using WGET to download a file using it. If I did this on the DO box itself, i was getting 100MBytes/s&amp;hellip; When I ran it over the MLPPP box, well, under 7 was achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-downloading-over-mlppp-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-downloading-over-mlppp.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;WGET over Squid over MLPPP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then i though it might have been Squid. So, since the file had been downloaded to DO, i SFTPed into the box over the MLPPP link, and tried again&amp;hellip; Again, pretty poor result. I think i seen it hit about 7MB a sec at one stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp2-over-mlppp-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp2-over-mlppp.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;SFTP over MLPPP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what is showing on the DO box when running the SFTP download. You can see 2 connections from the 2 WAN links at home hitting the box, and they are balanced. Its just nowhere near the speed they are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp-over-mlppp-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-sftp-over-mlppp.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;iftop running on server&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not get a screen shot of this, but when I tried with iperf, thinking it might have been overhead of SFTP or Squid, I was getting results matching what I was seeing with SFTP. Downloads in the 55-60mbit/s range for download and 40ish for upload. 40 is still faster than 1 link, mind you&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned that I had made some minor tweaks to the configs from what John had written. Well, mostly it was config changes to how routing was done. In Johns case, he is bonding a DSL and a HSDPA connection, so he had setup to do for logging into his PPP modem and connecting. Also, when he setup the interfaces, he routing tables in there. I have mine setup in a single config file, like as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tiernano/a9a642c4d029c0dcf8beb926b3588991.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have changed the names from adsl1 and 2 to WAN1 and 2, and the IPs are changed from internal IPs to my public IPs. I manually run this when setting up my connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing else on his config files have changed. I did not do any of the masquerading stuff, mainly cause this was testing. I just want a tunnel to start with. When reading the vtund.conf file, you can see that encryption and compression are both turned off, and and the same in the ppp configuration. I also don&amp;rsquo;t think the issue is to do with the CPU performance, since these are the screenshots of top running on both boxes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-server-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-server.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Top on Server&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-client-orig.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/post_images/2016/04/02/20160402-top-view-client.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Top on Client&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in both cases, CPU usage is sub 6% for VTUN and SSH seems to be using less than 10%. So, now, I&amp;rsquo;m baffled as to why this is not performing as expected&amp;hellip; More testing required!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[update 4/4/2016] - fixing images so they are clickable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPTCP, SSH, Squid, OpenVPN (and 2 Cable modems) = Double Speed? Not quite... Part 2</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;[NOTE] This part 2 in a series of posts. The rest can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/tag/Double_Internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2016/03/22/2-Cable-Modems-Double-Internet-Speed-part1.html&#34;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt; I explained what i was trying to do&amp;hellip; This post explains what i have been working on recently, and performance results&amp;hellip;
So, first, what have i tried&amp;hellip; There are 3 different things i have tried, and here are some of their details. Some will need to be updated (other parts of this series), and others i will try get back to eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware-and-servers-used&#34;&gt;Hardware and servers used&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test this, i am using my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/Computers/proliantml110.html&#34;&gt;HP Proliant ML110 G5&lt;/a&gt; running either Ubuntu or Debian Linux, with 2 GigE connections directly to the cable modems, and 1 connection to the LAN (for SSH and testing). The LAN has no gateway set, and the 2 WAN connections have DHCP enabled. They get fully public IP addresses. Upstream, I am using either &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/d4d345b83b55&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scaleway.com&#34;&gt;ScaleWay&lt;/a&gt; VPS boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Ocean has the advantage of allowing different Kernels, so i have been using them for testing MPTCP. As for ScaleWay, well, their BareMetal C2S/M/L boxes have between 4 and 8 cores (4 for the S, 8 for the M and L) and between 8 and 32Gb RAM (S=8, M=16, L=32GB). The L model also comes with 256GB SSD (plus the boot disk, which seems to be a network disk of some sort) and they all come with lots of bandwidth (i use the L because its got about 800MBit/s to the internet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ping wise, Digital Ocean is about 20-30ms away from the house (I picked London to host the servers) and Scaleway is a little further at about 50ms (They are based in France).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mptcp-multipath-tcp-http-www-multipath-tcp-org&#34;&gt;MPTCP (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multipath-tcp.org&#34;&gt;MultiPath TCP&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MPTCP (their site is a bit wonky as of writing, so bare with me&amp;hellip;) is a Linux Kernel patch that allows TCP connections to use multiple paths&amp;hellip; Essentially, if you have Wifi and 4G in a phone, and MPTCP is enabled, it should allow you to use both connections for TCP traffic, as long as the server upstream supports it. It also allows for easy fail over if, say, you lose your wifi connection. There is an example &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/VWN0ctPi5cw&#34;&gt;video of it on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; which should show the fail over parts and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VMdPI9Cfi9k&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; shows how they managed to get 50Gbit/s out of a 6 10Gb Ethernet connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When i was using MPTCP, I had a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; on both boxes, and told Squid locally to use Squid on the upstream box (over a SSH tunnel, which was over the MPTCP link) as a parent cache. Using this method, i could see (using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ex-parrot.com/pdw/iftop/&#34;&gt;iftop&lt;/a&gt;) that both connections were being used. When trying proper performace testing, I setup a RAM disk on both machines and copied a Linux ISO to the Digtial Ocean Box. Then, using wget and &lt;a href=&#34;http://axel.alioth.debian.org/&#34;&gt;Axel&lt;/a&gt; I downloaded the files using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nginx.com/&#34;&gt;Nginx&lt;/a&gt; on the server, and checked the results. I can max out 1 single connection, plus use about 60-80mbit/s from the second. about 420-440mbit/s total. Disk was not the bottleneck, since I was writing to RAM, so more tests are required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mlvpn&#34;&gt;MLVPN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zehome.github.io/MLVPN&#34;&gt;MLVPN&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty interesting project that caught my eye. The idea is quite simple: you configure the local box and server, as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;http://mlvpn.readthedocs.org/en/latest/linux_example.html&#34;&gt;their example guide&lt;/a&gt; and run the MLVPN program on the server, then the client. It creates 2 VPN tunnels between the 2 boxes, and bonds them&amp;hellip; In my case, i was given an IP of 10.42.42.1 on my box in house and 10.42.42.2 on the server. Any traffic over that tunnel is bonded&amp;hellip; Problem is, it seems to be quite processor intensive: my Digital Ocean box was showing one cpu core (out of 2) maxing out at around 80% and my Proliant in house maxing around the 70% mark&amp;hellip; all while transferring data at around 100mbit/s. I tried iperf and got the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20160330-mlvpn-speed-test.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;mlvpn speed test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;getting 50mbit/s upload is good, in reality, since in theory my max speed would be 72, without overhead. but 116mb/s down is less than a third the max speed of a single connection. So, I tried just uploads and downloads&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upload Only (from local machine to server)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20160330-mlvpn-speed-test-upload-only.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;mlvpn upload only test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download Only (from server to local machine)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;20160330-mlvpn-speed-test-download-only.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;mlvpn download only test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the download speed has increased a little, to 176Mbit/s, but the upload speed is now at over 60MBit/s!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still.. download is as important as upload, and given I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to get it to max out one connection, never mind 2, even more testing is required&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mlppp-using-vtun&#34;&gt;MLPPP (using VTUN)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one i need to come back to&amp;hellip; Used the guide from &lt;a href=&#34;https://johnlewis.ie/bonding-teaming-internet-connections/&#34;&gt;John Lewis&lt;/a&gt; but was only managing to get about 100Mbit/s&amp;hellip; I was originally using a VM (so disk may have been the issue) and also had the connection behind my EdgeRouter, so it might have been firewall rules causing a slow down. But I do need to come back to this soon&amp;hellip; Watch this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, at the moment, all I can conclude is that there is more testing required. Upload wise, i can somewhat use most of my bandwidth with MLVPN, and I did see promising results with MPTCP. I gave up a bit too early with MLPPP, so more testing is required with that. Also, all tests are using just iperf between boxes. I did use squid with the MPTCP box for a while, but not for proper performance testing. So, even once this is all sorted out, i will need to turn this into a proper &amp;ldquo;router&amp;rdquo; too&amp;hellip; So, conclusion? this was originally meant to be a 2 parter&amp;hellip; now it looks like I will require a lot more parts&amp;hellip; Watch this space&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compressing and UnCompressing Protobuf items in C#</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/compressing_and_uncompressing_protobuf_items_in_c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 11:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/compressing_and_uncompressing_protobuf_items_in_c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of a project i am working on required sending large amounts of data between different instances. To get this to work efficially, we started using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/protobuf/&#34;&gt;ProtoBuf&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/protobuf-net/&#34;&gt;ProtoBuf-net&lt;/a&gt; in .NET. but the files where still quite large (17mb, give or take). So, we looked into compression&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here is some examples of how we managed to compress the protobuf files. We got some decient compression: 3mb files, down from 17mb. very happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to compress an object (obj) and write to a temp file (tmpfile):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/4267147.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to decompress the object back to a known type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/4267157.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
