<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 9 - Going Back</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-9-going-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-9-going-back/</guid>
      <description>[NOTE] This part 9 in a series of posts. The rest can be found here
Well, the double internet experiment is about ready to be finished&amp;hellip; After 9 posts, 4 months, lots of sweating, many painful nights trying to figure out why something stopped using, shouting when Netflix did not work, wondering why my internet connection was so slow, and many, many other problems, i have decided to wind down the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 8 - Routing Around</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-8-routing-around/</guid>
      <description>[NOTE] This part 8 in a series of posts. The rest can be found here.
At the end of my last post I asked the question about routing traffic to different servers based on thier distances, etc&amp;hellip; Well, after a bit of messing, i can say it kind of works! here is a quick over view:
 server in the house has now got multiple OpenVPN connections (2 to Hetzner, 1 to OVH (with a plan to double), 1 to Digital Ocean (again, to be doubled) and i am planning 2 to Azure as well).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 7 - ECMP (kind of)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-7-ecmp-kind-of/</guid>
      <description>[NOTE] This part 7 in a series of posts. The rest can be found here.
In the last post I mentioned I am now using Hetzner for hosting a dedicated box. Thats still live, and going well. I have a /29 IP range (6 usable) and also 2 other IPs. So far, so good&amp;hellip; But because i was using a Socks Server, I was not fully able to use the /29 ips&amp;hellip; I use something like as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double speed Internet Part 6 - Hetzner Edition</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/double-speed-internet-part-6-hetzner-edition/</guid>
      <description>[NOTE] This part 6 in a series of posts. The rest can be found here.
Its been a while, since I posted, and there are some, well, pretty major changes since the last time&amp;hellip; Lets start are the beginning.
Last time I was using Digital Ocean for my hosting provider. I was using their $20 a month server (2 cores, 2GB RAM, 40GB SSD, 3TB transfer), and it was all good&amp;hellip; But I noticed that every now and again I would need to reboot the box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Mad) Max Speed - The Road Warrior (Internet connection) (double speed internet Part 5)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-5/</guid>
      <description>[NOTE] This part 5 in a series of posts. The rest can be found here.
This post is going to be an update and theoretical post. probably very little &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; stuff going on here, mostly updates, and what I am planning on doing later on.
This week, I have been OOF sick, so I have not done much work, but I have been surfing the web, watching videos, downloading stuff, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable Modems = Double Speed? Part 4</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-4/</guid>
      <description>[NOTE] This part 4 in a series of posts. The rest can be found here.
So, this week I went in a completely different direction that I have been thinking recently&amp;hellip;
So, the basic theory is as follows:
 I am still using MPTCP kernels on both upstream and local machine now have 2 P2P UDP OpenVPN tunnels between house and cloud. Example config is here all TCP traffic (bar port 80) that hits the router in house is redirected to RedSocks RedSocks uses a socks server, Dante, as an upstream server on the cloud box since the socks traffic is over TCP (inside the UDP OpenVPN tunnel) it uses MPTCP having socks running, gives me quite the download speed, turning it off does not, hence the following tweet  Hmmmm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable modems = Double speed? Part 3</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-speed-part-3/</guid>
      <description>[NOTE] This part 3 in a series of posts. The rest can be found here.
In Part 1 of this series I explained the why and what I wanted to do for this &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo;. In Part 2 I did some basic testing of both MPTCP and MLVPN. I also mentioned trying MMPPP using vtund but it has been a while since I did that testing, and it had not been on bare metal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPTCP, SSH, Squid, OpenVPN (and 2 Cable modems) = Double Speed? Not quite... Part 2</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mptcp-ssh-squid-openvpn-double-speed-part-2/</guid>
      <description>[NOTE] This part 2 in a series of posts. The rest can be found here.
In my previous post I explained what i was trying to do&amp;hellip; This post explains what i have been working on recently, and performance results&amp;hellip; So, first, what have i tried&amp;hellip; There are 3 different things i have tried, and here are some of their details. Some will need to be updated (other parts of this series), and others i will try get back to eventually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Cable modems = Double Internet Speed? Well... not really... Part 1</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-internet-speed-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/2-cable-modems-double-internet-speed-part1/</guid>
      <description>[NOTE] This part 1 in a series of posts. The rest can be found here.
First, a bit of background, and then I will explain what I am currently running in Part 2&amp;hellip;
For the last 15 or so years, I have had at least 2 internet connections in to the house&amp;hellip; 2 of them have always been Cable Modems from NTL, which became UPC, and now is Virgin Media. When I started, i think the modems where 150/50kbit/s and 600/150kb/s, and have steadily increased in speed, currently at 360/36Mbit/s each&amp;hellip; But they have always been somewhat separate, and single thread downloads have always been limited to 1 of the connections&amp;hellip; I have been looking for ways around this for years&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi as a Mobile WiFi HotSpot (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_as_a_mobile_wifi_hotspot_-_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 07:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_as_a_mobile_wifi_hotspot_-_part_1/</guid>
      <description>I have been using an iPhone 4 as a wifi hotspot for a while now. It does not have a &amp;ldquo;phone&amp;rdquo; SIM in it, with calls and texts enabled, instead it has a 3G Data SIM from a dongle&amp;hellip; It works OK, but there are a few issues i have with it&amp;hellip;
 No easy way to see how much data is being used, unless you Jail Break, and then battery life goes away&amp;hellip; not very hackable&amp;hellip; other than Jail Break, and thats not hackable enough&amp;hellip; not a lot of storage: 16Gb, and most of that is takin up by Music and Apps no background network daemons&amp;hellip; more on that in a second&amp;hellip;  The Network Daemons i am thinking would be useful for a WiFi Hotspot would be Squid, WANProxy, SSH, PPTP or OpenVPN Client and possibly a downloader of some sort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFS iSCSI NFS SFTP Hyper-V and more</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zfs_iscsi_nfs_sftp_hyper-v_and_more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 09:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/zfs_iscsi_nfs_sftp_hyper-v_and_more/</guid>
      <description>As part of my new task to make my files safer and backups faster, and, well, cheap, I am looking into ZFS for my storage needs. My needs are as follows:
 Allow me to store lots of different types of data (Photos, Videos, Music, VMs) in different formats (RAW and JPG photos, MP4, AVI and DivX Videos, with DVD and BluRay rips also a posibility, MP3 music and VHD files from HyperV, inclduing ISOs and Snapshots).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handbrake Cluster</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/handbrake-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/handbrake-cluster/</guid>
      <description>[UPDATED] someone asked in the comments if there was an binary build for this file. there is now! http://handbrakecluster.codeplex.com now hosts the code and binaries, and will soon have help files and documentation.
A few days back, i wrote a post titled Powershell + Handbrake + AppleTV + iTunes = Automatic TV&amp;hellip; ish. In it i included a block of Powershell code to bulk convert TV shows from whatever format you had them in to a M4V format for the AppleTV.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>