<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry_pi on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/raspberry_pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry_pi on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 21:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/raspberry_pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Phone as a Service</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mobile_phone_as_a_service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/mobile_phone_as_a_service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2013/05/29/RaspberryPi_Astrisk_Box.html&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about the Raspberry Pi acting as a VoIP server, and being able to add a 3G Dongle and allowing it to act as a Mobile Phone gateway, it got me thinking&amp;hellip; Why not have something that allows you to rent a mobile phone number in a country, send and recieve text messages, phone calls, etc, all from anywhere in the world? Thats where &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mpaas.co&#34;&gt;Mobile Phone as a Service&lt;/a&gt; comes in&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theory behing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mpaas.co&#34;&gt;MPaaS&lt;/a&gt; is quite simple: A SIM Card for a mobile phone is placed in a USB Dongle, plugged into a VoIP server (Asterisk box, probably a Raspberry Pi) and shared with the user who requests it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its only a theory at the moment&amp;hellip; Any interest?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi as an Asterisk Box</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberrypi_astrisk_box/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberrypi_astrisk_box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty amazing peice of kit for its price and size. And now, you can make it even more amazing by using it as a VoIP server for your house!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberry-asterisk.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Asterisk&lt;/a&gt; for downloads, documentation, etc, on how to setup a Raspberry Pi and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asterisk.org/&#34;&gt;Asterisk&lt;/a&gt;. I have a couple Pi&amp;rsquo;s in the house, and plan on setting this up in the next few days. Keep your eyes on the site&amp;hellip; more posts coming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as an added bonus: You can now use a 3G/HSDPA modem to make and recieve calls using Asterisk and your Pi! &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.carrier-connect.com/raspberry-gsm-gateway/&#34;&gt;Carrier Connect&lt;/a&gt; has details of how they setup a couple of Raspberry Pi devices in Germany and Cambodia and anyone ringing from Germany got redirected to Cambodia, with no noticable issue. Very cool stuff! Have to try this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Double Bonous: Chan-Dongle (the software that you use to make and recieve calls with GSM) also allows the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.e1550.mobi/doku.php?id=usage#receive_sms_and_ussd&#34;&gt;device to accept SMS messages&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi as a Mobile WiFi HotSpot (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_as_a_mobile_wifi_hotspot_-_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 07:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_as_a_mobile_wifi_hotspot_-_part_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using an iPhone 4 as a wifi hotspot for a while now. It does not have a &amp;ldquo;phone&amp;rdquo; SIM in it, with calls and texts enabled, instead it has a 3G Data SIM from a dongle&amp;hellip; It works OK, but there are a few issues i have with it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No easy way to see how much data is being used, unless you Jail Break, and then battery life goes away&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not very hackable&amp;hellip; other than Jail Break, and thats not hackable enough&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not a lot of storage: 16Gb, and most of that is takin up by Music and Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no background network daemons&amp;hellip; more on that in a second&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Network Daemons i am thinking would be useful for a WiFi Hotspot would be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt;, SSH, PPTP or OpenVPN Client and possibly a downloader of some sort. What i am thinking is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a device, that is small enough to fit in a bag, possibly small enough to fit in a jacket pocket. It will probably not be as small as the iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should have storage on board. Boot storage and cache storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 1, possibly more, WiFi Adapters, with optional antennas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 1, possibly more, 3G or 4G Modems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 1 ethernet port, again possibility for more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battery that can run the whole system for at least 4-5 hours, and should be able to run while being charged. charging via USB would be ideal also&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optional Screen, but more likley, some sort of web interface to show whats going on (Bandwdith usage, clients connected, connection details)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this turns on, it should automatically start the 3/4G connections (if there are multiple connections, it should do some balancing of the connections). if there are more then 1 WiFi Connection, one should be a Client (connect to an external WiFi connection, like home, college, work) and one should be an Access Point (Your Phone, Tablet and Laptop connect to this one). Ethernet can also be used in a simular way (if one only, it could be client or server, if multiple, one can be client, one can be server). DHCP addresses will be given out on Access Point or Server connections, and on Client connections, DHCP will be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squid would be installed and listen on its usual port. Optionally, all port 80 and 8080 traffic could be routed though Squid. Ideally, HTTPS traffic should be automatically routed, but i think thats a bit harder to setup&amp;hellip; If VPN Clients are enabled, it could also allow All or Some traffic to be routed over the VPN connections. SSH could also be used to compress traffic between multiple Squid boxes (one in house, one on the device). WANProxy could be used in a simular manner to save bandwdith and make the connection faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with all that, i am looking at using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; for the job. I am still working on this, but here is what i have so far&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have put a Wifi adapter into my Raspberry Pi (A Linksys, but forget the exact model number). Using a tutorial on &lt;a href=&#34;http://exain.wordpress.com/2011/03/31/making-a-wifi-hotspot-access-point-using-linux-wifi-lan-cardusb-adapter/&#34;&gt;Vivek&amp;rsquo;s blog on making a wifi hotspot on linux&lt;/a&gt; i managed to get the AP showing up on my laptop, but could not connect. I am not sure if its the adapter causing the problem, or what, but i am going to change out the adapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the moment, i am sharing the ethernet connection, not the 3G connection&amp;hellip; I have posted here before the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2012/07/3g-internet-on-raspberry-pi-success/&#34;&gt;link to Terence Eden&amp;rsquo;s post on getting the Raspberry Pi to connect to 3G&lt;/a&gt;. All that i will need to do is connect to 3g and then NAT the connection from Wifi to 3G&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there are a few more bits and pieces to get done over the next while&amp;hellip; I will keep posting here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boot Raspberry Pi with SSH Enabled, Enable Wifi on Boot, and more</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/boot_raspberry_pi_with_ssh_enabled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 16:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/boot_raspberry_pi_with_ssh_enabled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some interesting links for the Raspberry Pi today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, you just bought a new Raspberry Pi and need to enable SSH, but dont have a screen? &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/38/prepare-for-ssh-without-a-screen&#34;&gt;Prepare for SSH without a Screen&lt;/a&gt; shows you what to do!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/3200/wifi-bring-wlan0-up-on-boot&#34;&gt;How to Bring up WLAN0 on boot&lt;/a&gt; shows you how to start your Wifi adapter when you boot your Pi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPS and Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/gps_and_raspberry_pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 16:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/gps_and_raspberry_pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Need to add GPS to your Raspberry Pi? &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/questions/547/how-do-i-attach-a-gps-receiver&#34;&gt;How do i attach a GPS to a Raspberry&lt;/a&gt; answers your question!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi now with 512MB RAM, other random links...</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_now_with_512mb_ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 12:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry_pi_now_with_512mb_ram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier on today, the Raspberry Pi Foundation announced that the Model B will now be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/archives/2180&#34;&gt;shipping with 512Mb RAM as standard&lt;/a&gt;, with no price change. I posted the link up on &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4654251&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and its caused quite a lot of happy people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with the news of extra RAM, its started making me think of more things the Pi could be used for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Austrian hosting company &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edis.at/en/server/colocation/austria/raspberrypi/&#34;&gt;are offering free Co-Location for Raspberry Pis&lt;/a&gt; with a 100Mb/s uplink and 100Gb bandwidth! FREE! with 512Mb RAM (or even 256Mb RAM) thats enough for a small site. or even a medium site (like this one) running statically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2012/07/3g-internet-on-raspberry-pi-success/&#34;&gt;Pi can connect to the internet using 3G&lt;/a&gt;, you could install a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org/&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; and use an SSH tunnel back to your main office or home, have have multiple levels of caching going on&amp;hellip; It would also secure your browsing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2012/06/raspberry-pi-python-and-3g-dongles-oh-my/&#34;&gt;Sending SMS messages though the Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; could be useful for sending diagnostic info if the device is remote&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[XBMC on the Raspberry Pi] would make your media center a lot smaller, use less power, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;just a note on the idea of using 3G and Squid for the Pi&amp;hellip; This is something i am interested in, so its something i want to start playing with. The idea would be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have a linux box in house with Squid and SSH enabled, and port forward SSH to the linux box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tell the pi, on boot, to try and connect to a 3G connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once connection is live, connect to SSH tunnel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squid should already be configued to load and use the upstream Squid box as an upstream cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;local squid should use some storage on either USB or SD for local cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, using something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://wanproxy.org/&#34;&gt;WANProxy&lt;/a&gt; on both ends should make things faster also&amp;hellip; Having the Pi, a 3G modem, USB key (optional) and a battery pack, all in a small box, with a Wifi Adapter, should give you a faster mobile internet connection&amp;hellip; And if you could get 2 or more 3G modems (using a Powered USB Hub of some sort), you could do load balancing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more raspberry pi and camera antics</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more_raspberry_pi_and_camera_antics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 15:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/more_raspberry_pi_and_camera_antics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiernanotoole.ie/2012/09/06/Rasberry-Stuff.html&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, and in the post was a link to a Photographer who was &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidhunt.ie/?p=2641&#34;&gt;embeding a Raspberry Pi into a Canon 5D MKII battery grip&lt;/a&gt;. Well, its been a while, and i have been thinking about the Pi and Cameras, so I went looking around&amp;hellip; Here is what i found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://islandinthenet.com/2012/08/23/hdr-photography-with-raspberry-pi-and-gphoto2/&#34;&gt;HDR Photography with a Raspberry Pi and GPhoto2&lt;/a&gt;: It was linked at the end of David&amp;rsquo;s post, and i missed it completely. David mentions he was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gphoto.org/proj/gphoto2/&#34;&gt;GPhoto2&lt;/a&gt; to take photos from the Pi, so its a good place to start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://skowron.biz/artikel/gphoto-raspberry/&#34;&gt;GPhoto2 and the Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;: starters guide on getting the Pi to talk to your Camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not specifically Pi+Camera released, but the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.stackexchange.com/&#34;&gt;Stackoverflow Raspberry Pi Page&lt;/a&gt; is a handy resource for asking questions&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing i have not been able to figure out is how to tell the Pi to take the photos out of the camera &lt;strong&gt;wihtout having a monitor plugged in&lt;/strong&gt;. I was thinking either tell it, on boot, to start monitoring the camera and download everything. This way, if you have it plugged into a external power source, it will be monitoring and downloading to somewhere&amp;hellip; USB HDD, USB Key, etc. If there is a Wifi spot around, try uploading them to a location, posibily manageable via web interface of some sort&amp;hellip; Lots of interesting ideas can be done&amp;hellip; its just a matter of doing them&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cross Compiler for your Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry-pi-cross-compiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/raspberry-pi-cross-compiling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My main machine at home, known as &amp;ldquo;The GodBox&amp;rdquo; is a Dual Processor, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001QCEMFA/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B001QCEMFA&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;Quad Core Xeon 5520&lt;/a&gt; with 60Gb RAM, 2 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005CGDSDI/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B005CGDSDI&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lotassmartmann00&#34;&gt;300Gb 10,000 RPM Western Digital Velociraptor&lt;/a&gt; in RAID 0 for boot, 4X1Tb 7200RPM drives for storage, 2 more 300Gb 10,000 RPM drives for &amp;ldquo;scratch disk&amp;rdquo; and a couple high(ish) end graphics cards with 3 monitors plugged in&amp;hellip; Hence the name, GodBox!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, on the other hand, has a 700Mhz processor, 256Mb RAM and not much else&amp;hellip; So, if you need to write code for your Pi, and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait a long time to compile, check out this tutorial on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bootc.net/archives/2012/05/26/how-to-build-a-cross-compiler-for-your-raspberry-pi/&#34;&gt;how to build a cross compiler for your raspberry pi&lt;/a&gt; which will allow you to build your apps on a different machine&amp;hellip; I have a college project which the Raspberry Pi will be used for, and i am thinking this will be how i build code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Stuff</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/rasberry-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/rasberry-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple months back, I got my hands on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, a tiny development board that can run a full copy of Linux, has a HDMI port, a couple USB ports, Ethernet and a few other little bits and pieces. The full specs, from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raspberry_Pi&#34;&gt;Wikipedia Article&lt;/a&gt; are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating system: Linux (Debian GNU/Linux, Fedora, and Arch Linux ARM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power: 2.5 W (model A), 3.5 W (model B)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU: ARM1176JZF-S (armv6k) 700 MHz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage capacity: SD card slot (SD or SDHC card)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory: 256 MByte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphics: Broadcom VideoCore IV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a few things i have wanted to play with it for, but have not implemented all them yet&amp;hellip; still learning&amp;hellip; but some interesting projects have come to my attention&amp;hellip; here they are, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://davidhunt.ie/?p=2641&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi embedded into a Canon 5D MKII Battery Grip&lt;/a&gt;: The idea of this is epic! the possibilities are endless&amp;hellip; GPS, Wifi, FTP, Processing RAW images (ok, maybe not with a 700Mhz processor&amp;hellip;), auto upload to the internet, auto add watermark, resize images before upload, send to iPad&amp;hellip; I could go on and on&amp;hellip;. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://liliputing.com/2012/08/raspberry-pi-mini-pc-crammed-into-a-keyboard.html&#34;&gt;Embedding a Raspberry Pi into a Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;: this is pretty cool too&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/phpBB3/viewtopic.php?f=26&amp;amp;t=12017&amp;amp;p=129471#p129471&#34;&gt;Quick setup of a Web Server on the Raspberry PI&lt;/a&gt;: Install Apache, SSH, PHP, MySQL and an FTP server, all on your Pi!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all fairness, the Pi makes a lot of ideas possible. with such a small size, and such a cheap price ($25-35), you are only limited by your imagination&amp;hellip; Wonder could i get Windows 8 installed on one of these&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there are also a few interesting things that may make the Pi work more portable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seeedstudio.com/depot/lipo-rider-pro-p-992.html?cPath=155&#34;&gt;LiPo Rider Pro&lt;/a&gt;: takes input from Batteries and Solar Panels and outputs as USB 5V. should run the Pi off solar and batteries for a while&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
