<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Powershell on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</title>
    <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Powershell on Tiernan&#39;s Comms Closet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>VSCode and Markdown Monster with Powershell</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/vscode-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/vscode-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back, i created a post showing you how to add an Alias to PowerShell &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiernanotoole.ie/2012/08/30/SublimeText-With-Powershell.html&#34;&gt;to easily start Sublime Text from a PowerShell command line&lt;/a&gt; . This worked well, but this is 2017 (that post is from 2012!) and my daily text editor has changed. I have moved to &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; for most of my daily work. It works well 95% of the time. I still use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Pro&lt;/a&gt; for C# Development, but for quick fixes and work on, say &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; or smaller edits, Code is great. For blogging, on the other hand, I am trying out &lt;a href=&#34;https://markdownmonster.west-wind.com/&#34;&gt;MarkDown Monster&lt;/a&gt; but code still has some nice features. We will see how tests go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to upgrade the post, and to be able to use VS Code and MarkDown Monster from your PowerShell command line, I added the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-Alias code &amp;quot;C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft VS Code\Code.exe&amp;quot;
Set-Alias mm &amp;quot;C:\Program Files (x86)\Markdown Monster\MarkdownMonster.exe&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can either run this each time you open PowerShell (a bit of pain) or you can add it to your &lt;code&gt;Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1&lt;/code&gt; which lives in your &lt;code&gt;Document\WindowsPowerShell&lt;/code&gt; folder. If you dont have one, just create the file, add that piece of text, and next time you open PowerShell, you are good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, i am actually in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/insiders&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code Insiders&lt;/a&gt; group, so my alias is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-Alias code &amp;quot;C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft VS Code Insiders\Code - Insiders.exe&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When these are set (and you have restarted your PowerShell windows), you can now run the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;code filename.txt
code folder
mm filename.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VSCode will open either files or folders, but it seems Markdown Monster only opens files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell &#43; HandBrake &#43; AppleTV &#43; iTunes = Automatic TV... Ish...</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/powershell-handbrake-appletv-itunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/powershell-handbrake-appletv-itunes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/appletv&#34;&gt;AppleTV&lt;/a&gt; in the house (3, actually) and i am very happy with its ease of use, size and cost&amp;hellip; You cant really argue with the small price!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a lot of content that works great with the AppleTV in iTunes, but i have content which does not work so great with the AppleTV&amp;hellip; So, i needed to find a way to convert files quickly and easily&amp;hellip; thats where PowerShell and &lt;a href=&#34;http://handbrake.fr/&#34;&gt;Handbrake&lt;/a&gt; come in&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% gist 3798509 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the code above, you need to set the path of where your files live. in my case they live on a NAS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;next, set the location of HandBrake&amp;hellip; i have a 64 bit copy of Windows, and a 64 bit copy of HandBrake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set the new file name to where you want the file to go. in my case i have it set to my &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://support.apple.com/kb/HT3832&#34;&gt;Automatically Add to iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; folder, which is a magic folder for iTunes that copies any files dropped in there to your iTunes library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally, conversion is run&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may take a few min, depending on a few factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how many files you are converting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how fast your machine in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how fast your machine can read and write the files&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have set files to convert on 3 different machines (the GodBox and 2 other servers) and i am getting speeds of anywhere between 250FPS (on the GodBox running 2 instances of HandBrake CLI) and 40 - 60 FPS on the older servers&amp;hellip; on the remote machines, they are sending files to the GodBox folder also, so once everything completes, its just a matter of opening iTunes and we are good to go&amp;hellip; Now to figure out how to automate the Metadata import&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text 2 with Powershell</title>
      <link>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/sublimetext-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 09:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiernano.github.io/www.tiernanotoole.ie_hugo_static/post/sublimetext-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My new Favorite cross platform text editor is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com/2&#34;&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt;. It works on Windows, Mac OS and Linux, and i am very happy with it. My only problem is the path to start it is not exactly easy to type&amp;hellip; So, with the help of PowerShell, my new favorite command line tool on Windows, i added an alias:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-Alias subl &#39;c:\program files\sublime text 2\sublime_text.exe&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added this to my Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1 file in Documents\WindowsPowerShell folder. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have one of these files, check out this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computerperformance.co.uk/powershell/powershell_profile_ps1.htm&#34;&gt;Computer Performance.Co.UK post on Creating PowerShell profile files&lt;/a&gt; and then edit the file and add the line above&amp;hellip; Now, I can edit files in PowerShell with Sublime Text 2 by typing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;subl filename
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy days!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
